<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solar on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/solar/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solar on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/solar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 16: 22 AUGUST,Teplice nad Metuji – Ĉeský Krumlov</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2010/08/23/day-16-22-augustteplice-nad-metuji-cesky-krumlov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 16:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2010/08/23/day-16-22-augustteplice-nad-metuji-cesky-krumlov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We woke early today. Breaking camp and packing up was easier with our wonderful new tents. Today we are off to Ĉeský Krumlov, stopping along the way at the Church of Bones in Kostince near Kutná Hora. We were traffic lucky today and made it to Kostnice in good time. The church is the outcome of an estimated 40 000 to 70 000 peoples bones used to decorate the church. The church is said to be a reminder of our humanity, that without redemption we cannot enter heaven. It was an extremely interesting place. We bought some souvenirs and headed out looking for lunch. We set off after lunch for Ĉeský Krumlov. It turns out that Cassie has gained a wobbly tooth..oh the woes of being a child. We went through Ĉeský Budějove, home of Budweiser, on our way to Ĉeský Krumlov. Not much to write home about really. The outskirts of Ĉeský Krumlov looked a bit like a building site. We drove through and found a campsite on the outskirts of Ĉeský Krumlov. The camp we found was in a solar farm, very bizarre. We paid for only 1 night as we were unsure if we wanted to stay or not. What we ended up deciding on was having dinner in the camp restaurant, breaking cmp early and heady off into Ĉeský Krumlov for breakfast so that we could beat the tourists and still see the town. We sat outside and ate our dinner under candle light..romantic? Not really, we couldn’t see what it was we were eating! Another early night, this time with an alarm wake up for 7am so we could make town for breakfast and head off in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1080995.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1090024.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1090038.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1090044.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1090045.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>