<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Italy on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/italy/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Italy on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/italy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful maps for exploring the Maritime Alps</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; If your planning on exploring the tracks around the Maritime Alps on the French / Italian border, you&amp;#039;ll need a few maps of the area. The best single retailer for maps in the UK is Stanford maps in London. They have three floors of travel books and maps. This is where I got our maps months prior to departing. Of course you can try online also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#039;t have to buy the maps before you leave, they are sold locally in France. You will need something with some detail though, equivalent to the UK Ordnance Survey (OS) map, which is 1:25k or 1:50k depending on the series you go for. In France the equivalent is the Institut Geographique National (IGN) they do a 1:25k map series which covers the whole of France. Where ever you go in France you can normally by IGN maps of the local area. So you could buy on arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the IGN maps, we also used the Italian equivalent as we found the IGN maps loose detail on shortly after the border. These maps are Istituto Geografico Centrale (IGC). At Stanfords they had these in 1:50k. They have a slightly vintage feel in the style of printing, but they are very clear. Interestingly they also show prohibited routes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I should also mention is that Garmin maps have a lot of the tracks we used, well certainly in the European City Navigator 2012. Not all though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1320.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Here are some pictures of the maps we used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 8 Alpi Marittime E Liguri (ISBN 9788896455081)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 1 Valli Di Susi Chisone E Germanasca (ISBN 9788896455012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3841 OT Vallée De La Roya, Vallée Des Merveilles, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 3282113841030)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3741 ET Vallées De La Bévéra Et Des Paillons, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 9782758524083)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1319.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-2129.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And in case you are interested the back of the first one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-13191.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fort Pramand, Mount Pramand Overnight</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 08:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1825.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394770.2654&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Pramand&#34; width=&#34;388&#34; height=&#34;291&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since leaving the Plitvička national park, in Croatia where we visited the former top secret airbase of &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/&#34;&gt;Zeljava&lt;/a&gt; we made our way to Fort Pramand, which was the next area we planned to do some off-road exploring, near Oulx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394854.0425&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Drinking Prosecco&#34; width=&#34;306&#34; height=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt; On the way we stopped in Slovenia at the Bovec national park to chill out for a day or so, around the beautiful mountains and river Soča, we seem to like that area and always have a good time exploring. We also stopped in Revine, which is near Connegliano in Italy, the area famous for Prosecco sparkling wine. We obviously had to grab a box from a vineyard. The main reason for stopping here though was to use it as a gateway to Venice. There is an intercity train that will take you straight into Venice main station. That&amp;#039;s another story though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After this we travelled towards Oulx, barring another one night stop at Lago Maggiore. Oulx is one of the nearest towns to where we had planned to head up to the tracks I had researched. So the original plan was to stock up with and food, water and beer we needed then go. Oulx has a few official camp sites in the immediate vicinity, should you need a base to explore from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;But the Landy had other ideas. I had noticed that on occasion with increasing frequency, that the battery voltage was creeping up to the point of potentially over charging the batteries. This was concerning, as apart from potentially screwing up my expensive new batteries it was likely to mean we could not depend on them when we were off the beaten track. Luckily when we stopped in Oulx, we had a fiddle with the alternator which was fairly new as I uprated it a few months earlier and found that some of the terminals must have either worked loose or built up a resistance on the regulator sensing connection. This obviously led to the regulator over exciting the alternator giving a high output voltage. It was interesting because none of the connections were noticeably loose. It has been fine since. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1448.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394803.1416&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;On the up&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So now the beer could be kept cool we headed up to the mountain tracks, via the main road that runs parallel to the E70 motorway, I think it is the ss n 24 headed east we took the left that leads up past Fort Fenils. However the excitement was not over! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As we started to ascend we suddenly noticed a strong smell of smoke and soon came to some mountain fire trucks, police and lots of people. It was a forest fire approaching the road, we were lucky though they guided us past. The road is tarmac for a few kilometres on the way up before it turns to easy gravel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Next the Pajero which Carole and Daniel were driving started to overheat! So we had to stop shortly after hitting gravel for lunch. Luckily to get to Fort Pramand we did not have far to go so, time was on our side. You&amp;#039;d think that was the end of the drama though surely. Luckily the next incident started as we approached the fort. The Pajero decided that the automatic transmission oil indicator would light, suggesting it was overheating. We guessed it was because of the low range work and slow speed, not helped probably by the earlier overheat. Oh well it would get a chance to cool overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1629.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394765.179&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tracks up&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The tracks up to Fort Pramand are easy, until you get to the last bit leading up to the Fort, which is a turn off from the main track anyhow. The track narrows because of trees either side that lean towards the center of the track. The ground has a few large roots to climb. It is not to bad in a small or low 4x4, but with the root tent on the Landy it was a little tricky, we clipped a corner of the tent lightly. Just a scuff mark no damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The Fort itself is fairly big, but in a very poor state of repair it sits at 2162 meters, there are various warnings spray painted on the walls warning of Danger. The roof is in a poor state of repair. I suspect it has had a few vehicles on its roof. You can walk onto it by following the track up, the view is excellent from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1746.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394771.471&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner&#34; width=&#34;356&#34; height=&#34;475&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we settled up there and started to cook and set ourselves up for the night it started to feel a bit spooky. The girls were convinced it was haunted. Especially when something took exception to Wendy&amp;#039;s singing. For some reason after we all told her not to quit her day job, and that she did no justice to Black Betty, the radio in the car came on and started blaring!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We had a nice dinner which was made even better with the red wine we got from Connegliano to season it. Shortly after the clouds rolled in so we disappeared for what we thought would be a peaceful night. However with the girls convinced we were being watched by spooky ghosts, Wendy woke a few times to noises, saying she felt like someone was climbing the ladder to the roof tent. She then woke me up because she was too scared to go to the toilet! The conversation went along the lines of.... &#34;Do you need a pee. no. Can you come with me. Do I have too. Yes. Well I am not going twice get Cassie, we&amp;#039;ll have a family pee.&#34; Needless to say. There was no ghost waiting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1754.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394800.108&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Setup&#34; width=&#34;366&#34; height=&#34;275&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With hind sight I guess being parked with the ladder right against the Fort, between two very dark portals was probably adding to the girls apprehension. In the morning Carole got out of the tent having had no sleep, because she was also convinced ghost soldiers were marching across their tent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After breakfast we left a little tired and headed for Mount Jafferau, via a cool tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;If you want to download the GPS track from this post and the next you can download it here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiloc.com/wikiloc/view.do?id=3261982&#34;&gt;Wikiloc&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/view_trip.php?trip_id=1741579&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Everytrail&#34;&gt;Everytrail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Feel free to leave a comment if you want to know more. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antignano, Livorno - Italy</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/06/antignano-livorno-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 19:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/06/antignano-livorno-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9256.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-818 alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Poor Tusky&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel have decided that they would like to look for a small camping fridge. We looked for a Decathlon and used the GPS find our way. It was along the way and we were heading towards Bari now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We found a Decathlon, but were not in luck, they did not stock any fridges what-so-ever! As we were near the shops, we decided to stop off and get our food shopping done for the next few days. As we were packing the cars and fridge with our food shop, Dan and Daniel noticed an oil leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It turns out that the vacuum pump is seriously leaking. We need to get to a garage and get the right part to fix this situation. Dan used the GPS to locate the nearest Land Rover garage, and off we set on a search for this garage and a way to get the part we would require.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The first garage we find is no longer open to business. This is a set back that we did not expect or want. The day is wearing on and time is ticking. We managed to locate another Land Rover garage, and so the search continues. This time we are in luck! The garage is still in business, but we have now hit Siesta time and so we have to wait for 14.00hrs till we can find out if they have a part or can order one for us. We decide to go to a truck café we saw just down the road to have a snack and drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we get back to the garage, the guy is extremely helpful. He says that he can order the part, but it may take as long as 48hrs to be delivered. Give him an hour or so and he will see what he can do for us. It turns out that he is able to get the part delivered for the next day, we just have to collect it after 14.00hrs. We thank him profusely and set off to find a campsite that isn&amp;#039;t too far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The campsite we found was just up the road. It had a swimming pool, points for Cassie, and it had bungalows, points for Carole. Carole and Daniel rented a bungalow and we took a pitch. We decided to stay for 2 nights so that Dan had time to fit the pump and not worry. As we pulled up to our pitch, Dan got worried about being able to work on the Landy. It wasn&amp;#039;t a secluded spot. We went and had a look at a pitch that we would be able to &amp;#039;upgrade&amp;#039; to if we wanted. It was more expensive and came with it&amp;#039;s own sea view terrace. Dan was happier with the privacy this pitch provided, and so we moved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9240.jpg?w=225&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-817&#34; alt=&#34;The terrace adjoined to our pitch&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The time at he campsite was spent relaxing. The next day Wendy and Cassie spent the day at the pool whilst Dan worked on the Landy and Carole and Daniel did things they wanted to catch up on. It was a nice lazy stop despite the reason for stopping. We explored the beach, went for a swim in the sea and had a lovely braai on the terrace on the last evening. Ready to leave in the morning and do one mammoth drive. We were going to try and cover the whole distance to Bari tomorrow, making up for lost time.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1110456.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-820&#34; alt=&#34;Cassie &amp;amp; Wendy enjoying the sun &amp;amp; pool&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pisa &amp; Lucca - Italy</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/05/pisa-lucca-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 19:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/05/pisa-lucca-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf91791.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-810 alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Crossing the River Arno towards the Tower&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It was a rather later start to our day than we had expected, with the knock on affect of us arriving in Pisa at midday. As we searched for a parking space, the temperature signs showed that it was already 40°C ... it was going to be a scorcher! We parked on the outskirts and walked, following the signs for Torre Pendante.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As we drew nearer to the Tower, the crowds were building and so were the amount of restaurants and tourist shops. We soon found ourselves looking for a space where we could take that typical Leaning Tower of Pisa shot. Each of us assumed the pose, and so our &amp;#039;holding up the Tower&amp;#039; pictures were immortalised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9189.jpg?w=225&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-804&#34; alt=&#34;Wendy &amp;#039;holding&amp;#039; up the Tower&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The heat and the crowds were now slowly taking their toll on us, so we decided to not spend any more time than we had to, and leave. As it was so unbearably hot, we decided to stop at a café and have a long, cold drink to see us on the rest of the way back to the car. Here we decided that Lucca would be a nice place to stop, Dan had heard from a friend that the Old Town was a lovely place to explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Sated from our cool drink, we melted our way along back to the cars and headed off out into Lucca. It was lunch time when we pulled up outside the Old Town walls. We grabbed our lunch, the picnic blanket and a drink and sat under a tree to eat. There was a tourist office across the road, and so we paid it a visit to find the nearest campsite. It was just up the road a bit, so we hoped back in the cars and went in search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The campsite was more geared for motor homes, but they had a large field where tents were able to pitch. Carole and Daniel had to pitch their tents there, whilst we had a motor home spot, just opposite the field. Cassie was in luck, there was a swimming pool. Tents pitched, costumes on, it was off to the pool to cool off after a stinker of a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Cassie decided to stay at the pool, whilst Daniel, Dan and I wanted to head off into the Old Town for a little bit of an explore. It was a little trek into the Old Town, but we stopped off at a bar just inside the walls for a refreshing beer. We then spent the next couple of hours wondering around and admiring the cobbled street, beautifully decorated front doors and churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf92031.jpg?w=225&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-807 alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Statue of Puccini&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Back to camp for a spatch-cocked chicken on the braai and a nice early night. It&amp;#039;s time we started to head off in the direction of Bari to catch the ferry across to Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levanto, Cinque Terre - Italy</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/04/levanto-cinque-terre-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 20:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/04/levanto-cinque-terre-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7871688232_f83515ef75.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Windy road&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Another winding journey down off the mountain this morning. We stopped in a small, sleepy town and had the best coffee we have had so far on this holiday. From here, we decided to drive along the coast and make our way to Cinque Terre National Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The drive along the coast was lovely. We did not have far to travel, but as usual, the coastal roads proved to be slow going. We stopped at a restaurant and enjoyed a lunch of grilled fish, mussels and spaghetti. We decided that from here, we would make our way up onto the motorway for the last, short leg of the journey and miss all the coastal traffic, so we could have some beach time of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We arrived in the town of Levanto, where the GPS advised there was a campsite. There was one, and they had space. We got to our pitch, set up the tents and went in search of the local beach. There were many beaches where you had to pay for entry, so we headed to the free part of the beach. We found an empty patch of sand, and proceeded towards the water for a lovely, well deserved swim. The water was lovely, and after a shingle entry into the water, there was a sand bank further out where we could stand and relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7875031658_992a54aed9.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;414&#34; height=&#34;309&#34; alt=&#34;Levanto beach&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After a refreshing swim, we headed to the beach bar next door where we ordered a couple beers and a spritz. We sat and chatted here for awhile, enjoying relaxing on the seaside. We decided we would go from here and find a nice restaurant for dinner, as we had not brought anything to cook dinner with that evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;There was a free concert happening in the square that evening, and after mulching around, we decided to try a restaurant close by. We had a lovely meal of seafood again, and sampled some lovely local wine. The menu was, again, in English as well as all the other major European languages, which took the mystery of menu deciphering out of the picture. But, all the same, it was a fantastic meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7875017550_596d33e82d.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;436&#34; height=&#34;327&#34; alt=&#34;Enjoying the local seafood&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;From here we went across the road to a bar for another beer. A bit of a late night, but we are spending 2 nights here, so there is a lovely day of rest tomorrow for us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The day started out with a nice lie in. No rushing, did some clothes washing, had breakfast and showers, then decided to head into the town. Daniel needed some swimming shorts. Cassie decided she wanted to stay with Carole and Daniel, so we left them to their search and headed off in another direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan and I bought our obligatory, touristy tea towel from a rather jam packed, &amp;#039;a little bit of everything&amp;#039; shop. On our perusal through the town, we came across a small market on one of the side streets. Here I found a stall selling handmade leather handbags. I chose a green one, and my wonderful husband bought it for me as an anniversary gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We left the quiet back streets and went in search of Cassie, Carole and Daniel. We found them sitting in a restaurant waiting for their lunch. Dan and I were not that hungry, so we went for a short stroll after buying a gelato each. The road we strolled down was very touristy and had nothing but souvenir/beach tat. We headed back for the others at the restaurant. Cassie had a gelato for pudding, but unfortunately, both Cassie and I had had chocolate, it was very rich, we both soon started feeling ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7874995172_f4326588cd_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;302&#34; height=&#34;403&#34; alt=&#34;Mmm gelato&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We all headed for the supermarket to gather supplies for dinner, and then headed back to camp for a swift change into our beach wear, and headed straight down to the beach. Dan took Cassie&amp;#039;s snorkel and mask and went out for a dive. Daniel and Cassie stayed in the water and Carole and I sat on the beach and read our books. A lovely afternoon relaxing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;From the beach, we headed out in search for a beer. We found a bar just up the road, where we ordered a beer and watched in amusement as an Italian Metal band started setting up for what appeared to be a concert they would be giving that evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What we soon discovered was that, when ordering a few beers, after a certain time in Italy, you receive some tapas (or Italian equivalent, what is it called?). This was a nice and welcomed accompaniment to our afternoon beverages. Thus we seemed to have a few more beers here than we would usually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7874979240_eef3e297d0_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;321&#34; height=&#34;428&#34; alt=&#34;Enjoying the atmosphere at the bar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Back at camp we grabbed a communal Braai and braai&amp;#039;d some sausages for &amp;#039;hot dogs&amp;#039;. Dan and Daniel invited up an Englishman they&amp;#039;d been chatting to, also staying in the campsite. His name was John, and he had just left the army after his 22 years in service. He was spending some time travelling and relaxing before starting a job in London. He was good company and he brought us a gift of ration packs. Very thoughtful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After a lovely evening of beer and good company, we headed off to bed. Off again in the morning, making our way towards Bari and the overnight ferry to Croatia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Col Linaire, Col de Sanson, Pas de Colle Ardente - Mount Saccarel</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7871723104_817a4bd793.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;The next track&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;282&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After finishing up on Col de Tende we headed back down to the town of Tende for supplies and to freshen up at the local piscine (swimming pool) (If only they had known!), before we departed for the second section of our little off road trip. Again we planned to stay at least one night up on the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The local chap at the fuel station we met the day before, had been correct about Col de la Boaïra being block from the Fort Central end, so we decided to heed his advice again and took his recommended entry point to the next pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With a plan in place, we kicked off by heading south from Tende fully refreshed and clean towards St Dalmas de Tende, where we turned left to head east on the D43 past La Brigue. This took us to the turning for the D143 on the right that allowed us to get to what would be the start of our next off road excursion at Notre-Dame des Fontaines. Apparently this is worth a stop to have a look, we did not take the opportunity unfortunately but will next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed straight up towards Col Linaire, which would take us up through the forest &#34;Bois Du Pinet&#34; along what seemed considerably more dusty gravel tracks than the day before. On the way up we passed an old Willis Jeep heading down, the driver, his dog and Family looked local and to be having a great time. I guess the old Williss is ideal for adhoc dog walking on your local mountain. What an awesome playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Given the time we left Tende after our swim and restock, it was not long, probably 8 km from the church until we decided we would stop for a light lunch. We stopped at a 5 point junction that offered to easily get us lost. Luckily it was easy to work out the exit we needed, after removing the closed piste and the exit we arrived from! The junction on the map is at &#34;Cime du Pinet&#34;, which is the Top of the Pinet hill. There were various logs lying around for us to sit on to enjoy lunch. There must be a certain amount of forestry undertaken, perhaps to control the fire risk? While we were there another car was parked up with a local who had just gone mountain biking, he did not seem so friendly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7871721608_6d3de535d8.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Forest Roads&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After having lunch we continued up the fourth exit... Towards Col du Loup, this continued through the Forêt Communale de la Brigue it was great driving through the forests, they provided a welcome break from the heat. As we were driving up, I was conscious that although we had enough water to last us easily for at least two nights, we did not have a lot spare, so was keeping an eye open for a source that would allow is to fill the solar shower and water carrier. At this time of the year there did not seem to be many streams around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7871715168_50ec94991d_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Topping up with water&#34; width=&#34;227&#34; height=&#34;302&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily we happened upon a water trough that was reasonably full. The water looked clean enough for the intended purposes and had a steady flow into it, which meant it was not stagnant. We filled up the shower and most of the carrier. But it was a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14236.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Border marker&#34; width=&#34;339&#34; height=&#34;254&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After getting water, our final re-supply item we continued up to the border area to Col de Sanson / Baisse de Sanson. The next section hugs what I think is the 1947 border of France and Italy, it was fairly spectacular along the ridge or the south east side of Mont de Colle Ardente for the first 5 km or so, then the track pops over the top for the next roughly 6 km along the north west side of Mont Saccarel, I think this is Pas de colle Ardente or part of. This leads into Pas du Tanarel which will have you emerge on the eastern side of Mont Tanarel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15323.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track to Mont Saccarel &#34; width=&#34;322&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It is about 2 km south of this point you have the option to proceed down towards San Bernardo and off the mountain or as we did proceed towards Mont Saccarel which is at 2200 meters. Mont Saccarels&amp;#039; summit overlooks a 12 meter statue of Jesus, that was placed there is 1901. The statue has a fantastic view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we stayed on Mont Saccarel, just below the summit which had the remains of some old fortifications. When we arrived at the summit there were some local Italians having a braai, that had driven up in there 4x4&amp;#039;s. We parked above them on the summit and decided to walk to have a look at the statue, it was about 1 km walk and would allow us time to see what the local chaps did. As it goes they disappeared shortly after we started our stroll. So after taking some photos of us and the Jesus statue we wondered back and pitch camp where they had been. Our camp straddled the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-17542.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from the summit&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-16451.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Jesus Statue&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1646.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Group shot&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we used some of the water we collected on the way up, to boil up some pasta and washing up water, no one had the trotts in the morning so needless to say the water was fine. We had a hearty vegetable pasta dish for dinner followed by beer! The rest of the evening was spent admiring the changing view in the evening light and listening to the distant cattle grazing it&amp;#039;s way across the slopes below. Once the sun had gone down we went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night I got up to look at the stars (have a pee) which were almost blinding due to the lack of light pollution, in the distance far below us there was the orange clusters of street lights in local towns and villages. I spent a few minutes admiring until the cold got to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the morning, we woke to a definite chill as you&amp;#039;d expect from a clear night at that height, the morning was glorious and I could not wait to see the view first from inside the warm shelter of the tent, then while I enjoyed the warmth of a warm fresh coffee. There was a problem though, I first had to go for a climb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night we had visitors... My flip flop had gone for a walk, only one. So armed with one of Wendy&amp;#039;s on my once bare foot, I dug out the binoculars and eventually far below I spotted the outline of my black flip flop in the rocks and shrubs. Off I trekked to get it, shortly after I put the kettle on. On recovery of my flop, I was suspicious, apart from some sizeable teeth marks, there was also a fairly stinky deposit of what I think was pee. I suspect a fox or something decided to mark it&amp;#039;s territory on my flop flip. I promptly returned to camp to deal with the situation, both proud and puzzled. By this time the kettle was boiling and with my now clean flop, we enjoyed our coffee and I pondered the curious event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My flip flops will live another summer by the looks of things, I guess the wife&amp;#039;s did not smell nice enough for our visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-3-aug-2012-0659.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Solar shower&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having fed ourselves and packed up, we freshened up under the solar shower, the moon had little effect on it&amp;#039;s temperature thou, so it was rather refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We then headed down the track we arrived on before turning off down the mountain towards San Bernardo for a coffee, before we headed for Cinque Terre our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFNXBiaFM5VFBnSmM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Gps track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1528.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The road down&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1755.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Panoramic from summit&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;165&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baisse d&#39;Ourne, Col de Tende - Fort de la Marguerie, Fort Central</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning we woke at our Campsite in Barolo in Italy early, the plan was to get to Tende in France, stock up on supplies at the super market, fill up with diesel, grab some petrol for the stove and head up to Col de Tende. We did fairly well and managed to have breakfast, coffee and pack up to be on the road by 0920 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-10201.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tunnel de Tende&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;296&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the minor back roads from Barolo to enter France via the Tunnel de Tende, on the SS20/N204. The tunnel was interesting in that it was only open one way at a time. We arrived at the back end of a line going our way, so decided to stop at the restaurant by the tunnel for a coffee and a pastry. That also gave us the opportunity to investigate the oil pressure light that was coming on in the in-laws car. We found nothing that would explain the light... Kicking the tyres did the trick thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tende is a picturesque town, that has houses perched on top of one another, we found a supermarket on the main drag, which was conveniently located next to a souvenir shop followed by a cafe. After getting supplies we made a pitch at the cafe for a light refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-12071.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Tende town centre&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to get diesel just south of Tende, while filling up we met a local driving an old Toyota Land Cruiser, 80 series I think, who we got chatting to about the tracks on the surrounding mountains. He gave us the low down and a few decent pointers including telling us about some closures due to land slides etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this new info we headed back towards Tende, where we planned to pick up the road Chemin Des Spegi towards Gite d&amp;#039;Etape which we entered through some sleepy back streets of the town, we then planned to continue up to eventually camp near or at Fort de la Marguerie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13361.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Colla Megiana&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assent to Gite d&amp;#039;Etape was slow it took about an hour to get to the top, most of the corners required at least a three point turn, in a 110 Defender. There seemed to be a never ending flow of hair pin bends. Chemin Des Spegi eventually turns into Chemin Muletier Des Spegi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roads up the mountain are gravel, which is a welcome change after about a thousand miles on Tarmac since leaving the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surroundings are initially sparse coniferous forest and dry grey rock. The forest eventually gives way to open rocky, green vast land scapes. Occasionally the roads are fringed by sections of granite wall, some with vast sheer drops. It is very easy to imagine military vehicles on the roads. Meeting one on the assent would certainly make for an interesting manuvoure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way up we noticed that the in-laws car was starting to over heat and loose a bit of coolant from the expansion tank. It appeared the low range work and slow speeds were not allowing the engine to keep cool, we noticed that the car was missing it&amp;#039;s thermostat. This it would seem, was a good time to have lunch, we managed to find a spot were we could put the cars into the wind, top up the coolant and have a nice shady lunch, near the turning for Colla Megiana. After the break we never did see the temperature of the Pajero rise again. Apart from the missing thermostat I wonder if there was an airlock or something in the system after the major service and the radiator flush we had just before departing on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13311.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Recovery Time&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;232&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued after lunch towards the fort along Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino. We had originally planned to do a longer route to the fort, but during the day we lost a fair amount of time. With time now cracking on and it being after three we decided to go for the shorter option, so at Baisse de Peyrafique we kept to the right. We had originally planned to go left and do a loop via Mount Paracouerta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16121.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping to the shorter route kept us on Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino, this took us along spectacular gravel road all the way to our camp at the Fort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the Fort to find another nice Landy from Germany pearched just where I had planned to camp, with the view you could hardly blame them. I had a look there was still room for us, so decided to ask if they would mind us joining them. They were fine with that, I guess they had no choice really, but I asked anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16331.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from Camp&#34; width=&#34;534&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17081.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Camping spot next to the Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually felt sorry for them, it was very pieceful before we arrived, at least we could not destroy there view!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We manoeuvred the vehicles in to position then, set our selves up for the night. It was still light enought to allow us to go and explore the fort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from the UK it was surprising that we were able to roam freely in the fort. It is clear that some do not respect the fort as much as we did, there was plenty of graphitti and rubbish inside the fort. We spent about an hour looking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17111.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Is it spooky?&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Proud of her self!&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17231.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Room 44&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-1733.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;On top of the fort&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17431.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;From the draw bridge to the court yard&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17391.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The draw bridge&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-18021.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our camp site&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from the camp was super. Stretching towards the Italian border and Fort Central, we could also see Tende far below and Fort Tabourde and Fort Pepin in the distance, giving an appetiser for what would be comming in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner we had a simple vegetable pasta, lots of beer and kept warm as the sun disappeared over the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-19131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Simple dinner&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the binoculars we were able to spy on the sheep and a lone hand gliding camper at Fort Central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to take an early night, but... At about 2300 we were woken by a load rusling and a bit of a commotion, we had made a &#34;school-boy&#34; error. We left the rubbish out in a black bag. This of course had been found by a fox who seemed a bit brave for the wild. Needless to say, our rubbish was everywhere and I was running round in my boxers chasing the rubbish and the fox! Half way down a mountain freezing in boxers is something I will always remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are on the subject of rubbish. I personally found it really appalling that the land scape was scarred  with toilet paper and other rubbish. If you take a dump, take the paper with you and be considerate where you dump. As they say take only photos and leave nothing but a foot print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow once we had delt with the rubbish and the fox, if was off to sleep for a pleasant but cold night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0956.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Central&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke to a spectacular view. After breakfast and coffee, we packed up and headed towards fort central. It was surprising again for us to be able to look around. We spent about an hour scouting around and then explored the track towards Fort Pepin. We found that the track was closed due to a land slide, apparently the local authorities do not have the budget to restore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coming to a dead end we headed down to Tende via another thousand hair pin bends, where we used the local pool for a shower and a very pleasant swim. We also got a few more supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0940.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Sentry Post&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0959.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#039;s here&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1009.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1029.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking back to The fort&#34; width=&#34;453&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1026.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Gun points&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1014.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Inner buildings&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1022.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking up from a lower floor&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1041.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Driving through&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFMk5wUW92VzhIaWs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;GPS Track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little town of Barolo</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/31/little-town-of-barolo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 20:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/31/little-town-of-barolo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From St Jean D&#39;Aulps we were heading for Tende in Italy, but we couldn&#39;t make it in one go, so we decided to drive as far as we could manage and then stop for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our drive took us past the Mont Blanc glacier and through the Mont Blanc tunnel. The tunnel fare was a tad steep at €38.90! When we got through to the other side, we got some photos of the glacier.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7873944696_1750263a48.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mont Blanc Glacier&#34; width=&#34;397&#34; height=&#34;297&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made the decision to stay on toll roads to try make headway. We finally decided to stop in a small town called Barolo. The campsite was small and lovely. They served spritz at the camp bar, we bought some to serve as a refreshment whilst putting up tents. This was the start of a beautiful relationship between Carole and the spritz..one that I put money on would last well beyond this holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7873965772_dcbdd26649_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Great food and wine&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tents were in a sleep-able state, off we trotted to the local restaurant for dinner. What a find! We decided to go for the taster menu, where we were given an assortment of dishes from their menu. With this we tried some wine fro the local vineyard, we had a lovely bottle of red wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/7873970924_f776b77436.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ready for my dinner!&#34; width=&#34;349&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn&#39;t want to stay out too late as we were heading into the mountains tomorrow for a good few days of offloading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 23/24: 21/22 AUGUST 2011  Forno di Zaldo (Italy) – Altkirch (France)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 17:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Les Acaises €32 – 2 nights incl. electricity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were up late, but still managed to pack up and leave in good time! It was a long drive today. We managed to find a garage for diesel and luckily some better maps. We started our navigation out of Italy, through Austria, into Switzerland and finally…just through the border into France. Once in France we decided to stop for dinner as it was very late, then go and find a campsite. After a nice pizza and salad, we went in search for a campsite…what a search that was. After driving and driving we finally found signs to a campsite! We were saved! This was the latest we had ever left it to find a camp – 21.00hrs! We set up tents, had showers and put Cassie to sleep. We would spend 2 nights here so we could relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9639.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9636.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9646.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAY 24: MONDAY 22 AUGUST 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke up at leisure today. Wendy washed some more clothes and then we went in search of a supermarket. We didn’t have anything for breakfast, so stopped off and bought some croissants along the way. After wondering through town, we hadn’t found a supermarket, so we sat and had a coffee. We had also seen signs for a swimming pool, but couldn’t see find it anywhere. Dan asked a man if there was a supermarket and he gave us directions. We did minimal shopping as we had to carry it all the way back again, and it was a trek back to the campsite. Back at the campsite, we decided to hop into the car and go in search of the swimming pool… unfortunately we did not find it. Back at the campsite, Dan and Cassie went to the bar to use the internet. The couple that run the campsite have 2 children and they connected a hosepipe to a tap and started running in the spray. Cassie went and joined in. After a good run around, Cassie and the daughter came back to our camp to watch Lady and the Tramp. Dan did a few housekeeping bits to the Landy whilst Wendy baked in the sun. After awhile, Cassie went back to join the fun in the hosepipe, and Dan and Wendy joined them too. That evening we went up to the bar and partook in a couple of beers and iced tea for Cassie. After putting Cassie to bed sudden rain came down. It wasn’t hard, but strange as there were no clouds about to warn of rain. Dan and Wendy went to bed with Thunder and lightening. It didn’t last long, thankfully, as we dreaded the thought of having to pack wet tents in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 22: SATURDAY 20 AUGUST 2011 Plitvička Jezera (Croatia) – Forno di Zaldo (Italy)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Al Pez €26.80 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We were up, packed up and gone by 8.30hr! We had decided to miss out Venice as most of the campsites wanted a weeks booking, we only wanted to stay for 2 nights. Instead we were going to head for Northern italy, then using our already purchased Swiss Vignette to bomb through Switzerland and straight through France, using the fast motorways. We didn’t want to get stuck in expensive Austria or Switzerland again. Unfortunately we only had a large map of Italy to guide us. A day driving on toll roads, and as we left Croatia, we got stuck in a queu of Italian cars that were also leaving Croatia. We headed into Italy navigated by Wendy and maps. Needless to say, we took an incorrect exit and ended up in a horrendous traffic jam! Once through it, we found our way back onto the correct course. We finally beat all the traffic and navigational errors and found camping in a small mountain town. It was a no car next to tent camp, but the man let us camp in a field next to a motorhome. We noticed toilet paper in the spot we had to put our tent, so we decided to stay only one night. We put up our tent and then went in search of a beer. After being told that there wasn’t a bar, we wondered around and just happened upon a bar! We treated ourselves to an Italian beer. A pasta dinner and an early dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9577.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9578.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9580.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>