<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overland on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/overland/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overland on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/overland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 13 - Jablaničko Jezero to Kostanjica</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/08/day-13-jablanicko-jezero-to-kostanjica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 20:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/08/day-13-jablanicko-jezero-to-kostanjica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9981.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we headed for Montenegro, our cunning plan was to head out on the main roads so we could get there in good time to relax. That is where we went wrong!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed out from Konjic diligently following the signs to Nevesinje. Within a few miles the signs became vague and then non-existent. We were planning to get most of the way through Montenegro in order to get in to Albania asap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Round about when we got to Glavatičevo some 20 km after we started we took the first wrong turning. We passed a town name which we found on the map, Ladanica. This had a nice looking Cafe Restaurant so we stopped to have a coffee and get our bearings, apparently we should have gone right at the bridge. Which was a dirt track indicating a place we could not find on the map. Sceptical I asked someone passing, they confirmed we should have gone up there via, some other towns… Not shown on the map. This was not the main road we had hoped to be on. Still doubtful we tracked back to some shops up the road and asked some ladies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9987.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ladies eventually concluded we should follow them, it would be easier. These ladies drove an Audi with a German plate. They took us up the dirt track, after about 2 km, they pulled into a drive. We concluded this was there place. Handed us a hand drawn map, and said just keep going, don&#39;t turn left. The map showed two town names and a turning. They told us it was 10 km to Nevesinje. We soon realised that they would be able to go no further.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9989.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track continued to degrade, but remained ever present. We gradually climbed a fairly big mountain side. Emerging in some farm land, by this time we had passed about 10 turnings left. I was starting to loose faith. However eventually we came across a farm, with a driery looking guy sitting out side, he confirmed we were headed in the right direction. About 40 minutes later we came across another person, at a small house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enquired with the person about out destination, he suggested I need to keep going. As I walked off I became alarmed, by his gestures which he repeated when I looked at him questioningly. He was indicating or seemed to be suggesting it was a long way to Nevesinje. He did this by drawing his hand down from his chin as if twisting a beard. I think he was saying you&#39;ll have a beard by the time you get there. I laughed worried and told Wendy who looked slightly alarmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 30 minutes later we arrived on tarmac at a junction. I now concluded that the guy previously had a sense of humour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We opted to turn right. Headed for Luka. Within 1 km we were on gravel again precisely what we did not expect. We continued at speed but tentatively on the track for about 20 minutes before an old soviet truck approached us thundering. We asked if Nevesinje was the way we were going he indicated we had to turn around. We managed to do this some 500 meters later. We passed the truck again and he moved over to let us pass. We beeped in thanks and joy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this we seemed to be on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some two hours later we arrived at the wrong border crossing to Montenegro having been redirected once or twice. We had hoped to cross at Bileća, but had missed the turning ending up crossing in reverse where we entered Bosnia and Herzegovina two years ago at Dolovi. With this we took the easy option headed for the beach in an area we know to chill for two nights.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0018.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Kostanjica and just relaxed. Phew. What a great but unexpected day. Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11 - Jajce to Sarajevo</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 19:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130707.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We packed up fairly sharpish this morning the plan was to have coffee and breakfast in Jajce, then explore. We got in to town easily from the campsite and managed to find parking. Dan accidentally purchased a day of parking for 5 KM (about 2.5 euro). Jajce is a candidate for a Unesco site, so we expect to find something fairly special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked into what we thought was the Old Town, the traffic was immense. The heat was already building and we decided to stop and have a coffee and breakfast before we headed out to explore. This being easier said than done. All the cafés were a little strange, so we opted for the most full…going with the thought process that if it&#39;s full, it must be ok. We decided to order a cappuccino instead of a coffee…we will not do this again. We promptly drank up and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130714.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wondering around and down a slippery, pebble polished set of stairs (from all the wear), we had no idea where we were going. We couldn&#39;t find the Old Town or the waterfalls mentioned to fall from Jajce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we still had not eaten, our stomachs won and we headed for the Pekara (bakery) we had seen on our way in to get some breakfast, or now, brunch. Cassie asked if we could go to the underground church she had seen a sign for, so we headed for that. Low and Behold! We were in the the Old Town. We should have simply headed that way to begin with. We paid 6KM for all of us to go down into the catacombs. They weren&#39;t extensive, but still a lot cooler than outside as the heat was blaring and interesting. A shame that on many of the alls there was engraved graffiti as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p11307261.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130727.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we wondered up to the top of the Old Town walls, we had a look around and decided to start our journey to Sarajevo. The drive was a hot one. As we entered the city, we found it hard to navigate with our large scale map and a guide book city centre map. We eventually managed to get onto a road that was shown on the map in our Bradt guide book. From here we were able to navigate ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130747.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking … Oh parking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was none!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We navigated the one way system roughly 4 times before we decided to head on out of the city and find a hotel on the outskirts, with parking, and catch a taxi into the centre. Just on the fringe of the one way system there was a petrol station and a tiny hotel next door. It had parking! Dan pulled in and went to ask if they had a room for the night and the cost. BINGO! We were in. We decided to have a shower, a beer and then go out and explore Sarajevo and find some dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we wondered in, Dan had seen an Apple store at the Sarajevo School of Arts, so we decided to head there and see if they had some noise cancelling headphones for Dan and Cassie to use. Cassie wanted to cross the bridge on the entrance to the centre as it was &#34;curly&#34;. We then decided to get a city map so we could find the Turkish quarter (Baščaršija) where the guide book said it was the best place to get a feel for Sarajevo. After wondering a bit and finding the quarter, we explored the stalls and did some souvinir shopping. Cassie and I bought some clothing from a shop that sold only hand made Bosnian clothes. Cassie got a shawl/poncho and Wendy got a lovely top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130751.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went in search of a place that sold ćevapi, as we had seen everyone sitting outside on the street restaurants eating ćevapi. Ćevapi is a meat sausage made from lamb or beef, or a mix, in a pita type bread served with sour cream/yoghurt and onions. It was lovely! The restaurants were full and after wondering around a bit we found one where the waiter put us on a table with another lady. She happened to be a student from Holland doing her Thesis in Bosnia on Genoside and Reconciliation. She was very good company and a lovely dinner partner to chat to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130767.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we looked for a place to have a beer, but being in the muslim part of the town, beer was a tad hard to find being served. We decided to just head back to the hotel and have a beer there. An opportunity to update this blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130750.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready for the Summer</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 17:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-26-may-2013-1303.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the weather getting better and a short camping trip planned for next weekend, we decided this weekend was probably the most sensible time to get the tent on the Landy and the awning set up, ready for opportunities to go camping and the summer trip. The other good thing given that this weekend is a bank holiday is that next weekend should be quieter! The roads and transport systems in the UK just can&amp;#039;t cope when we all decide to move in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a friend giving me a lift getting the roof tent on was a breeze. This year, I have made some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first. The tent is mounted about 6 or 8 inches further forward. This I am hoping will make the car feel a little more stable, while still allowing the rear door to open easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second tweak, was to fit some locating pegs to the back of the tent to remedy the problem I mentioned in this blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that caused the base to sag and create an uncomfortable step. I&amp;#039;ll write about that further &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/&#34;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually we also made a third tweak. That was to create some drain holes in the lower side of the tent cover. We noticed when we removed the tent last year that we had some water sitting in the bottom of the cover. These holes should allow moisture to be dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to another thing I should mention. We have been working on ideas for the summer, we intend this year to again go on a &amp;#039;Big&amp;#039; trip. Note that I say ideas and not planning or plans. Why? Well we are not sure if our aspirations will match our plans. We had to have some house work done this year that cost a small fortune. We&amp;#039;ll reveal more in the near future on the trip though. So stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Stats - Summer 2012 Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In starting to consider this years plan, i thought i would post some recorded figures from last summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stats from our last trip from 27th July to the 26th August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We covered 3663.1 miles, about 5900 km.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used 606.42 litres of diesel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Averaged 27 miles per gallon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filled up 15 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid 26 tolls totalling 287.8 Euro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most expensive where for the Tunnel de Mont Blanc at 38.9 and tunnel de Frejus at 39.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used the channel tunnel for crossing the channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used a over night ferry from Bari to Dubrovnik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 night in a hotel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 attempted nights at a hotel night resulting in six police officers attending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 nights free camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 none catastrophic car part failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which do you want to know more about!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myway Serengeti 1.6m Roof Tent &amp; Boab Roof Bars</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 15:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-aug-2012-2004.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been trying to find the right sleeping solution for the three of us since, pretty much the first trip we ever went on. The problem we have always had is that we would prefer to be able to wild camp or free camp, but having a family tent made this almost impossible. Not to mention the time it takes to put up and take down a larger tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years that followed we moved onto two small back packing tents one for Cassie and one for us. A two and three man. The plan being in camp sites we use both, in the bush we use one. What we often found though, was that it was hard to find a decent spot for the Landy and a three man tent. If we were walking it would have been fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used the family tent for two years, then the small tents for about two years. We eventually slimmed our arsenal of tents down to the family tent, which will be sold this year, it was only kept for the in-laws on this last trip; the three man backpacking tent we will keep for walking and biking; Cassie&amp;#039;s pop up tent and now the latest addition is a roof tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this trip we took the pop up tent and the new roof tent. The plan being that we would all sleep in the roof tent in the wild, then at campsites we would use both tents to allow us to get a good nights sleep, without being kicked and punched by Cassie all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enquiries about purchasing the roof tent started about 6 or 7 weeks before we left. We were hoping to go and check one out, then get one shortly after. What ended up happening actually, was that we got really busy and were not able to get to a place to see one, it was quite a way. What also happened was that we had to wait for a delivery from Cape Town, South Africa by sea. Luckily we were able to secure one of the items which had already departed in the next batch to be delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-21-jul-2012-1525.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up paying a deposit and hoping the tents would not be delayed in customs. They were supposed to clear by the first week of July. We thought that would be perfect as we could get a couple of nights camping in to make sure everything was ok. Inevitably that did not happen as you would expect, nothing is that simple. We managed to get the tent the Friday before we left. Paul from Myway came down from Doncaster to fit it and train us! Which was a nice touch. Needless to say the tent is superb. One thing led to another and we were not able to get out camping that weekend, so would have to just wait till the actual trip. Fingers crossed everything would be ok! In the end we did manage to find time on the Southdowns to practice putting it up and down including the shower curtain. We also managed to get a few pictures of the process. The pictures below were taken in France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 1 - Position Car&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1716.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 2 - Remove Cover and Insert Ladder&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1718.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 3 - Close the Door and reach for the ladder!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17181.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 4 - Rotate about the hinge and open&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17182.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 5 - Remember something you forgot.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17183.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 6 - Position ladder and fit stays for the flysheet&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1720.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      And Relax!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1719.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spoken at length with Paul, we ended up with a Serengeti 1.6m tent, we had originally wanted to get an Evolution because it was lighter and not canvas and we wanted a 1.8m as it was wider. Paul assured us that the Serengeti was a good choice and that a 1.6 was plenty wide enough for us and Cassie. He was so confident that he assured me if we were not happy we&amp;#039;d sort &#34;something&#34; out! The man proved to know his stuff. The other advantage of the Serengeti was that the canvas would keep the light out in the morning. We found it easy to sleep till nine at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing this so far, I&amp;#039;ve missed a beat, in between paying a deposit and getting the tent I had to find a platform to mount the tent to on top of the Landy. I spent quite a lot of time trying to work out if I wanted a roof rack or roof bars. Roof tents in general are heavy. Myway tents are lighter than most, the 1.6m we were waiting for weighed in at circa 50kg. Most are about 20kg more, with some hitting the 90kg mark for family models. A decent roof rack is about 40 to 50kg, with the Landy and a lot of other cars rated at about 100kg for roof loads, I&amp;#039;d want the lightest mounting system possible. Roof bars are about 5kg approximately each. It seemed an obvious choice considering we did not need a rack at the moment and could do with saving some money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1550.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found various bars around, I wanted something sturdy though. Really because of the off roading factor and mounting the awning. I toyed with getting some boab / mantec bars, I forget what they are called, but dismissed that because I was not convinced they were robust enough for us. Boab also, did some other bars called Boab bars in a 40mm x 40mm or 40mm x 20mm section. I opted for the 40mm square option. I ordered three of these as I needed to mount my awning using u-bolts. This offered a significant weight and cost saving over a rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Construction and Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of construction the tent is made on an aluminium base frame which uses stainless brackets and bolts with aluminium rivets in places, this has a marine ply base attached via captive nuts and bolts. The base frame has a bolted stainless hinge arrangement on either side of the frame, this is the point at which the aluminium hoop tubes attach which support the main tent canvas. The canvas hangs on the hoops, this allows the fly sheet to lay over the top of the whole arrangement. This leaves about a 40 or 50mm gap between the inner tent and flysheet, depending on how the two are adjusted. This gap allows plenty of airflow and is probably a contributing factor to the lack of condensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canvas inner tent is coated with a waterproofing agent, as is the flysheet. With this coating the canvas is free from the normal leaks you get on the first outing. This did not mean we escaped unscathed. We suffered a small amount of leaking on the first night due to the fly sheet being incorrectly adjusted and hanging on the inner canvas, it was a very minor leak and we did not see the issue again after we adjusted and experimented a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tent is delivered with about a 40mm sponge mattress and a fitted green sheet. The foam is covered in nylon so you need the sheet. The mattress cover is arranged such that it hindges in the middle and folds flat when the tent is packed away. We found the mattress fairly soft, so was easy to feel the base underneath, it took a little getting used to. We tended not to notice so much when we slept in sleeping bags in colder climates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to leave some bedding in the tent when it is packed away, but it must be folded flat before the tent is folded. It should be left on the fixed half of the tent. Failure to fold the bedding flat will result in it bunching when the tent is put away and putting extra strain on the hinge, which could lead to failure of the hinge if excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights we did discover one issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design. The cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically linked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in the two plywood base halves. In order to remedy this we will be installing some locating pegs, which will actually be formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the underside of the folding half of the tent a channel is mounted to the base. This allows the addition of a &#34;shower curtain&#34; which is essentially three sides of a walled room with no ground sheet and a small cut out for the ladder, the Landy forms the fourth wall. The ladder is outside the room. We tried this briefly on the Downs but never used this on the trip. The way we have the tent mounted means that it would provide shelter at the back of the Landy into the rear door during inclement weather, with the door open. The additional kit comes in a small bag, so is light enough to carry around. I just never want to have to use it. It takes 2 or 3 minutes to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appart from the minor niggle above, we had a great time with the Serengeti this holiday. We enjoyed the quick set up and pack away times. Wendy and I got quite a good routine established that meant we could put our feet up quicker and be on the road sooner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of the quick set up time means it gives more confidence for camping discreetly as it can be set up at dusk and packed away at dawn when no one is around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of quality, the construction is excellent and modular, so if something needs changing it can be and would be fairly simple, probably without having to go to Myway for spares. The only thing I would pick up Myway (the factory) on is the construction process. We found a lot of swarf in the tent and on the aluminium components. This was because the components are drilled during assembly, rather than drilled cleared and then assembled. It would not be hard to fix this process issue and would save some customer annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short I would not be able to compare against other roof tents as I have not had the chance to look at them, but I can say with confidence that the Myway Serengeti 1.6 meter is an excellent buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeljava Airbase - The Former Yugoslavia&#39;s Most Secret Airfield</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 18:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889158964_c853f3ebe0.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;DC-3 abandoned&#34; width=&#34;427&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The main reason for heading up to the Plitvička National Park again, was not this time to visit those beautiful lake, which bring most tourists to the area. My research for interesting things to see on our travels, had caused me to stumble  upon the abandoned airbase at Zeljava. Some of which is on the Croatian side, the rest spans the border of Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having seen the lakes and tourist crowds a year ago, we decided to fore go the experience again. We planned the day such that the bio-in-laws, would disappear in the morning to the lakes, Cassie was desperate to join them so went to show them around. Then if they returned in time they would join Wendy and Myself to visit Zeljava to try and find the base. As it goes they did return and three of us disappeared to find the base. Cassie stayed at camp with Carole. We had spent the morning tidying up the car and catching up on what would be best described as administrative tasks. Oh, I also spent the morning superglue&amp;#039;ing the rear indicator lens back together, from two million pieces in the grass...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889406454/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889406454_5ea4028caf_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;209&#34; height=&#34;279&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;From our campsite across the valley we could see mount Plitvička and mount Gola which hid Zeljava from us, the summit is home to modern radio masts, probably cellular these days. Being over looked by this helped build up the anticipation for me, we had been longing to do something different since Mont Saccarel in Italy. We did not manage to get to the top of the hill to explore, although I had a gps track to find our way. I believe during the period that the base was in use, the mountain over the airbase housed a radar warning system which was part of a network for Yugoslavia, this formed a early warning system for the airspace around Yugoslavia similar to NORAD. Regardless of what was now at the top, it would have been nice to explore, and it probably would have provided great views of the base, back to the camp and also over Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889378116/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889378116_1a38622bd4.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889398448/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889398448_71685d1284.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the net there is a lot of interest around military bases and sites, Zeljava is no different. It did not take long to establish it&amp;#039;s location months before we departed the UK. I used google earth to verify and then generated a waypoint for the GPS. As I also had 1:200k maps of the area from our last visit, I drew a box around the area and highlighted it so I could find it during the trip. Before we departed the UK, I had been to Stanford Maps in London looking for more detailed maps, I would have preferred 1:50k or 1:25k, but they had nothing better than I had. I also had a look on the Internet for a source but was not successful, I don&amp;#039;t know if such detailed maps are produced for the area? Perhaps not for walkers, I guess the land mine risk is still very real, I expect military maps do exist thou, in fact I have seen extracts of Military maps, so am sure they exist. If you know a source please leave a comment or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889447928/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889447928_c316a60bd3.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889451114/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889451114_d4300e011a.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;357&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Getting to the Plitvička area had been a great drive the previous day, although it was slow. I set the GPS to go via a couple of minor towns along the border area, and also set it to minor and un-paved roads, avoiding highways and major roads. Oh how the route impressed us, we went through tiny habitations and along mostly single carrage roads were the Tarmac barely remained. One section saw us follow about 20 km along a gravel route to a lake, I think the people there before us had stayed the night, it was a watering hole for a horse trek also. Had we been on our own I think we would have stayed the night. At the exit of this track we took the oppurtunity to stop at a sign that said &#34;Med&#34;, which is honey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889430760/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889430760_9c19261aeb.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;321&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The locals sell their honey, local plum brandy known as Rijeka and often wine, being tourists, they took the oppurtunity to sell us the golden delight at a much inflated rate, not speaking Croation meant we had little choice, but to  either except or move on. Needless to say we choose the former, two gigantic jars of Honey for 150 Kuna. Working out the price I have no idea how we got to it, when we did not understand the man, he just shouted louder! Our indications to write it in the dirt got lost in translation. Oh well we leave richer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889428454/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889428454_84d179df0a.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;370&#34; height=&#34;277&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on the route took us along routes that over looked Bosnia and Herzegovina, where we could see old border walls from the conflict, deserted habitations and bullet ridden houses, signs for mines are still a fairly common sight and leave otherwise beautiful land abandoned. Croatia has always struck me as a country of contrast, in respect to redevelopment post conflict. The coast is very built up and apparently affluent, were as if you head inland, there are still areas were buildings are derelict and bare the bullet scares of the war. The people on the coast are mostly involved in some way with tourism, the people inland are hard working farmers and manual workers. They look honest and interesting, I wish I could converse with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Thanks to the net there is a lot of information available about the history of the base. It&amp;#039;s construction was started around 1948, at the time it was known as Objekat 505. The actual pooring of the concrete is in some of the info I read is supposed to have started a few year later in the 50&amp;#039;s. Construction was finished around 1968. On completion it was given the name &#34;Klek&#34; and had a military post cost of 4868, to reflect the start and finish years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The design of the base is such that the tunnels are semicircular, and big enough to allow fighter jets to enter, the tunnels are about two jets wide. When the tunnels were constructed they had positions for explosives to be placed, such that detonation would cause the facility to become unusable. The entrance to the tunnel is shaped to allow the tail of the aircraft to enter the tunnel like an upside down &#34;T&#34;shape, these could be blocked by 1 meter thick pressurised doors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The internal sections of the base are designed to withstand a 20 kilo-tonne nuclear bomb. Which I have read is equivalent to the nagashima bomb, in Japan during world war two. As you would expect being able to withstand such a blast would imply that the doors would have to be kept shut. The base internally had generators, fuel storage, waste storage and water. The most important facilities were all located in the tunnels, with a mess room capable of seating 1000 people. Fuel was piped from storage tanks located 10 to 20 km away in a mountain in Bosnia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Above the main tunnels in the mountain, accessed by elevator only from inside the tunnels, was a room that was used for strategic planning and by the operators of the early warning radar system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The base was in use until the 1990&amp;#039;s and at one stage was looked at with a view to modernisation around the late 1970&amp;#039;s. When it was first built it is said to have cost some where between 4 and 6 billion US dollars. Apparently the funding came from the world bank and was secured for development of communication routes (motorways and roads) in the former Yugoslavia. The construction was carried out by a Serbian firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the end, during the conflict it was the Yugoslav Peoples Army (JNA) who detonated the pre-prepared explosives for distruction of the base on there retreat. I guess the base would have been rather useful to advancing forces. Later there was further distraction of the base using 56 tonnes of explosives, by the military of Serbian Krajina, this was carried out in 1995. Articles on the web site locals as saying that the force shock local towns like an earth quake and that the tunnels smoked for 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889025612/in/set-72157631310217932&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889025612_623531420e_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;External to the tunnels there are five runways on the base three lead straight into tunnels. The last two were used for other aircraft to land. The total area I&amp;#039;d the base was on the order of 9km by 4km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Ordinarily staff at the base lived in the town of Bihać, which is in Bosnia now, this was the nearest city. I have read on one site that there was a dedicated bus service between Bihać and the base for staff to commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our Visit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Croatian side of the airbase comming from the Plitvička national park there is only really one way to get to the base by road. In order to this your arrival is via the small village of Zeljava, which seemed almost empty save for a few dozen people who live in the houses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the village and the base are various buildings that appear to be abandoned almost deralict in some cases. Shortly after the village on the main road on the left you pass gates, behind which it is possible to glimpse an old military plane. It is possible to see how cars have avoided the closed gates and damaged fence, to make there own path to the road behind the gates. Where it eventually leads who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued past the planes to the find the rest of the base, about 1 kilometre further, we came across what was our first sign of more to be seen. Buildings hidden on the right by trees, this time of the year the dense trees and shrubs provide good cover for the buildings and relics hidden around the base. We cut off the main approach road, to explore what appear to be vehicle maintenance or facility areas. We abandoned the car at this stage choosing instead to explore by foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceeding towards the runway areas south east from where we were brought us via vehicle inspection ramps to another open area, that we were not sure of the use of, but it was littered with hydraulic hoses and metal scraps, there were various bullet ridden sign posts and behind the trees, what looked like a discarded bomb, that was not / had not detonated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We continued towards the end of what was runway 4 and runway 3, which meet at the what looks like an apron, prior to the entrances to the tunnels 1 &amp;amp; 2. Turning right, past another mine warning, the open apron gives way to the approach to the tunnels, which was almost claustrophobic with the tree cover that was slowly reclaiming the base, making it feel close. As you approach the tunnel entrance you feel that there is something watching you. All the time listening to rustling and noises in the trees,never being able to identify what the source was. Eventually we knew we were close by the wall of cold air that hit us, emerging from the tunnels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Shortly before the tunnel entrance we noticed a strange metal object that although half complete looks like a soldier or guards metal hat. The tunnel mouth although visible is obscured on the lower half by a mount of dirt that has been placed to prevent people taking vehicles into the tunnels. Entrance by foot is possible, having no torches or breathing equipment we choose to avoid this option on this occasion, instead staring into the dim light. We chose to avoid entrance because of a report I had read warning of toxic chemicals in the dust and potentially radio active waste from the fire detection equipment that was unaccounted for. Appart from this entry is fairly hazardous due to the unstable nature, but probably would not have prevented us if we had not been fortunate enough to read the report (available in the site links below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After this we went on to explore tunnel entrance two, but were interrupted by the sudden noise of several 4x4&amp;#039;s at first we were unsure of the nature of these vehicles, as I had previously read of border police being sensitive in this area, probably because of the unguarded border to Bosnia and Herzegovina. Luckily the vehicles turned out to be civilians tourists. With this we recovered our vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We returned back with the vehicle to explore the remaining section beyond the apron towards the unmanned Bosnian border, along the approach we passed various buildings for fire and parking areas. In one area, we came across the remains of a military vehicle minus the chassis and engine on its side. This looked like it had been hit by something, judging by the holes in the body. Not sure what it was used for thou. Along the road we came across spent bullet shells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We proceeded further to the border, where we came across an eyry owl, that was remarkably tame. Was this some kind of sinister warning? After taking some film we stopped at the UN border barrier for some photos, before making our way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way out we wanted to look at the abandoned aircraft near the base entrance. These turned out to be a DC-3 and two F-84 fighters, I was not able to work out the exact type. But they proved an interesting addition to the visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References / More Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found most of the info I wanted by following links out of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C5%BDeljava_Air_Base&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia Zeljava Airbase&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeljava-lybi.com/Zeljava-index2_eng.html&#34;&gt;Zeljava Lybi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Col Linaire, Col de Sanson, Pas de Colle Ardente - Mount Saccarel</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871723104_817a4bd793.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;The next track&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;282&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After finishing up on Col de Tende we headed back down to the town of Tende for supplies and to freshen up at the local piscine (swimming pool) (If only they had known!), before we departed for the second section of our little off road trip. Again we planned to stay at least one night up on the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The local chap at the fuel station we met the day before, had been correct about Col de la Boaïra being block from the Fort Central end, so we decided to heed his advice again and took his recommended entry point to the next pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With a plan in place, we kicked off by heading south from Tende fully refreshed and clean towards St Dalmas de Tende, where we turned left to head east on the D43 past La Brigue. This took us to the turning for the D143 on the right that allowed us to get to what would be the start of our next off road excursion at Notre-Dame des Fontaines. Apparently this is worth a stop to have a look, we did not take the opportunity unfortunately but will next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed straight up towards Col Linaire, which would take us up through the forest &#34;Bois Du Pinet&#34; along what seemed considerably more dusty gravel tracks than the day before. On the way up we passed an old Willis Jeep heading down, the driver, his dog and Family looked local and to be having a great time. I guess the old Williss is ideal for adhoc dog walking on your local mountain. What an awesome playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Given the time we left Tende after our swim and restock, it was not long, probably 8 km from the church until we decided we would stop for a light lunch. We stopped at a 5 point junction that offered to easily get us lost. Luckily it was easy to work out the exit we needed, after removing the closed piste and the exit we arrived from! The junction on the map is at &#34;Cime du Pinet&#34;, which is the Top of the Pinet hill. There were various logs lying around for us to sit on to enjoy lunch. There must be a certain amount of forestry undertaken, perhaps to control the fire risk? While we were there another car was parked up with a local who had just gone mountain biking, he did not seem so friendly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871721608_6d3de535d8.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Forest Roads&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After having lunch we continued up the fourth exit... Towards Col du Loup, this continued through the Forêt Communale de la Brigue it was great driving through the forests, they provided a welcome break from the heat. As we were driving up, I was conscious that although we had enough water to last us easily for at least two nights, we did not have a lot spare, so was keeping an eye open for a source that would allow is to fill the solar shower and water carrier. At this time of the year there did not seem to be many streams around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871715168_50ec94991d_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Topping up with water&#34; width=&#34;227&#34; height=&#34;302&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily we happened upon a water trough that was reasonably full. The water looked clean enough for the intended purposes and had a steady flow into it, which meant it was not stagnant. We filled up the shower and most of the carrier. But it was a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14236.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Border marker&#34; width=&#34;339&#34; height=&#34;254&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After getting water, our final re-supply item we continued up to the border area to Col de Sanson / Baisse de Sanson. The next section hugs what I think is the 1947 border of France and Italy, it was fairly spectacular along the ridge or the south east side of Mont de Colle Ardente for the first 5 km or so, then the track pops over the top for the next roughly 6 km along the north west side of Mont Saccarel, I think this is Pas de colle Ardente or part of. This leads into Pas du Tanarel which will have you emerge on the eastern side of Mont Tanarel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15323.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track to Mont Saccarel &#34; width=&#34;322&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It is about 2 km south of this point you have the option to proceed down towards San Bernardo and off the mountain or as we did proceed towards Mont Saccarel which is at 2200 meters. Mont Saccarels&amp;#039; summit overlooks a 12 meter statue of Jesus, that was placed there is 1901. The statue has a fantastic view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we stayed on Mont Saccarel, just below the summit which had the remains of some old fortifications. When we arrived at the summit there were some local Italians having a braai, that had driven up in there 4x4&amp;#039;s. We parked above them on the summit and decided to walk to have a look at the statue, it was about 1 km walk and would allow us time to see what the local chaps did. As it goes they disappeared shortly after we started our stroll. So after taking some photos of us and the Jesus statue we wondered back and pitch camp where they had been. Our camp straddled the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-17542.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from the summit&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-16451.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Jesus Statue&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1646.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Group shot&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we used some of the water we collected on the way up, to boil up some pasta and washing up water, no one had the trotts in the morning so needless to say the water was fine. We had a hearty vegetable pasta dish for dinner followed by beer! The rest of the evening was spent admiring the changing view in the evening light and listening to the distant cattle grazing it&amp;#039;s way across the slopes below. Once the sun had gone down we went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night I got up to look at the stars (have a pee) which were almost blinding due to the lack of light pollution, in the distance far below us there was the orange clusters of street lights in local towns and villages. I spent a few minutes admiring until the cold got to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the morning, we woke to a definite chill as you&amp;#039;d expect from a clear night at that height, the morning was glorious and I could not wait to see the view first from inside the warm shelter of the tent, then while I enjoyed the warmth of a warm fresh coffee. There was a problem though, I first had to go for a climb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night we had visitors... My flip flop had gone for a walk, only one. So armed with one of Wendy&amp;#039;s on my once bare foot, I dug out the binoculars and eventually far below I spotted the outline of my black flip flop in the rocks and shrubs. Off I trekked to get it, shortly after I put the kettle on. On recovery of my flop, I was suspicious, apart from some sizeable teeth marks, there was also a fairly stinky deposit of what I think was pee. I suspect a fox or something decided to mark it&amp;#039;s territory on my flop flip. I promptly returned to camp to deal with the situation, both proud and puzzled. By this time the kettle was boiling and with my now clean flop, we enjoyed our coffee and I pondered the curious event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My flip flops will live another summer by the looks of things, I guess the wife&amp;#039;s did not smell nice enough for our visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-3-aug-2012-0659.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Solar shower&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having fed ourselves and packed up, we freshened up under the solar shower, the moon had little effect on it&amp;#039;s temperature thou, so it was rather refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We then headed down the track we arrived on before turning off down the mountain towards San Bernardo for a coffee, before we headed for Cinque Terre our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFNXBiaFM5VFBnSmM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Gps track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1528.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The road down&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1755.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Panoramic from summit&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;165&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baisse d&#39;Ourne, Col de Tende - Fort de la Marguerie, Fort Central</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning we woke at our Campsite in Barolo in Italy early, the plan was to get to Tende in France, stock up on supplies at the super market, fill up with diesel, grab some petrol for the stove and head up to Col de Tende. We did fairly well and managed to have breakfast, coffee and pack up to be on the road by 0920 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-10201.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tunnel de Tende&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;296&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the minor back roads from Barolo to enter France via the Tunnel de Tende, on the SS20/N204. The tunnel was interesting in that it was only open one way at a time. We arrived at the back end of a line going our way, so decided to stop at the restaurant by the tunnel for a coffee and a pastry. That also gave us the opportunity to investigate the oil pressure light that was coming on in the in-laws car. We found nothing that would explain the light... Kicking the tyres did the trick thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tende is a picturesque town, that has houses perched on top of one another, we found a supermarket on the main drag, which was conveniently located next to a souvenir shop followed by a cafe. After getting supplies we made a pitch at the cafe for a light refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-12071.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Tende town centre&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to get diesel just south of Tende, while filling up we met a local driving an old Toyota Land Cruiser, 80 series I think, who we got chatting to about the tracks on the surrounding mountains. He gave us the low down and a few decent pointers including telling us about some closures due to land slides etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this new info we headed back towards Tende, where we planned to pick up the road Chemin Des Spegi towards Gite d&amp;#039;Etape which we entered through some sleepy back streets of the town, we then planned to continue up to eventually camp near or at Fort de la Marguerie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13361.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Colla Megiana&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assent to Gite d&amp;#039;Etape was slow it took about an hour to get to the top, most of the corners required at least a three point turn, in a 110 Defender. There seemed to be a never ending flow of hair pin bends. Chemin Des Spegi eventually turns into Chemin Muletier Des Spegi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roads up the mountain are gravel, which is a welcome change after about a thousand miles on Tarmac since leaving the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surroundings are initially sparse coniferous forest and dry grey rock. The forest eventually gives way to open rocky, green vast land scapes. Occasionally the roads are fringed by sections of granite wall, some with vast sheer drops. It is very easy to imagine military vehicles on the roads. Meeting one on the assent would certainly make for an interesting manuvoure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way up we noticed that the in-laws car was starting to over heat and loose a bit of coolant from the expansion tank. It appeared the low range work and slow speeds were not allowing the engine to keep cool, we noticed that the car was missing it&amp;#039;s thermostat. This it would seem, was a good time to have lunch, we managed to find a spot were we could put the cars into the wind, top up the coolant and have a nice shady lunch, near the turning for Colla Megiana. After the break we never did see the temperature of the Pajero rise again. Apart from the missing thermostat I wonder if there was an airlock or something in the system after the major service and the radiator flush we had just before departing on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13311.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Recovery Time&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;232&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued after lunch towards the fort along Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino. We had originally planned to do a longer route to the fort, but during the day we lost a fair amount of time. With time now cracking on and it being after three we decided to go for the shorter option, so at Baisse de Peyrafique we kept to the right. We had originally planned to go left and do a loop via Mount Paracouerta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16121.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping to the shorter route kept us on Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino, this took us along spectacular gravel road all the way to our camp at the Fort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the Fort to find another nice Landy from Germany pearched just where I had planned to camp, with the view you could hardly blame them. I had a look there was still room for us, so decided to ask if they would mind us joining them. They were fine with that, I guess they had no choice really, but I asked anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16331.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from Camp&#34; width=&#34;534&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17081.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Camping spot next to the Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually felt sorry for them, it was very pieceful before we arrived, at least we could not destroy there view!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We manoeuvred the vehicles in to position then, set our selves up for the night. It was still light enought to allow us to go and explore the fort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from the UK it was surprising that we were able to roam freely in the fort. It is clear that some do not respect the fort as much as we did, there was plenty of graphitti and rubbish inside the fort. We spent about an hour looking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17111.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Is it spooky?&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Proud of her self!&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17231.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Room 44&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-1733.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;On top of the fort&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17431.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;From the draw bridge to the court yard&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17391.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The draw bridge&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-18021.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our camp site&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from the camp was super. Stretching towards the Italian border and Fort Central, we could also see Tende far below and Fort Tabourde and Fort Pepin in the distance, giving an appetiser for what would be comming in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner we had a simple vegetable pasta, lots of beer and kept warm as the sun disappeared over the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-19131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Simple dinner&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the binoculars we were able to spy on the sheep and a lone hand gliding camper at Fort Central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to take an early night, but... At about 2300 we were woken by a load rusling and a bit of a commotion, we had made a &#34;school-boy&#34; error. We left the rubbish out in a black bag. This of course had been found by a fox who seemed a bit brave for the wild. Needless to say, our rubbish was everywhere and I was running round in my boxers chasing the rubbish and the fox! Half way down a mountain freezing in boxers is something I will always remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are on the subject of rubbish. I personally found it really appalling that the land scape was scarred  with toilet paper and other rubbish. If you take a dump, take the paper with you and be considerate where you dump. As they say take only photos and leave nothing but a foot print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow once we had delt with the rubbish and the fox, if was off to sleep for a pleasant but cold night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0956.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Central&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke to a spectacular view. After breakfast and coffee, we packed up and headed towards fort central. It was surprising again for us to be able to look around. We spent about an hour scouting around and then explored the track towards Fort Pepin. We found that the track was closed due to a land slide, apparently the local authorities do not have the budget to restore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coming to a dead end we headed down to Tende via another thousand hair pin bends, where we used the local pool for a shower and a very pleasant swim. We also got a few more supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0940.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Sentry Post&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0959.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#039;s here&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1009.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1029.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking back to The fort&#34; width=&#34;453&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1026.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Gun points&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1014.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Inner buildings&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1022.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking up from a lower floor&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1041.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Driving through&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFMk5wUW92VzhIaWs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;GPS Track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Books for Travel and Planning</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/17/useful-books-for-travel-and-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 16:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/17/useful-books-for-travel-and-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-15-apr-2012-2218.jpg?w=234&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;234&#34; height=&#34;308&#34; alt=&#34;Unesco World Heritage Sites&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Over the last few years we have read and used various travel related books. Some have been good, some have been great and some we just did not get on with. This may not mean they are bad, it is just that certain types of writing suits certain people better than others. A good example of this is in travel guides, we tend to prefer Bradt guides over Lonely planet. Most people swear by Lonely Planet guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of our most frequently used books is the UNESCO World Heritage site guide, it is a massive book with loads of superb pictures a page or two on each site, not all sites have a photo though, it would be nice if they all did and were at least a page in size, perhaps in the next release? At the beginning of the book are nice maps on several pages showing all the site locations and page numbers, these form a nice geographical index. In the back is a compressive index of each site together with a handy index by country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1060012.JPG&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; height=&#34;249&#34; alt=&#34;Look out for our book!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This is actually our second copy. We think we lost the first in a vineyard in Portugal somewhere, when we were exploring off road. In case you are in the area, I think this is where it was! Near the bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We find this book is excellent when we are musing over ideas with our Michelin 1:1,000,000 Europe map for instance. It allows you to get an idea of what is enroute. Just beware after a few beers plans can get somewhat over enthusiastic! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-22231.jpg?w=128&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;197&#34; alt=&#34;Europe on a shoestring&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having said we prefer Bradt guides, which was actually a fairly late discovery. We do have a fair few Lonely planet guides and one we keep referring to is Europe on a shoestring. It seems to make it into the car every year. At over five years old it is not only getting out of date but also somewhat dog eared. If  you want a handy general guide this is one to have, if you need more detail, grab a specific guide for the country or preferably the area you want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What this book does well is gives you ideas of itineraries, budgets and key things or places to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2229.jpg?w=207&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;207&#34; height=&#34;273&#34; alt=&#34;No doctor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;For medical questions and some things you would rather not waste the doctor&amp;#039;s time with, we have often referred to Where There Is No Doctor. Horribly detailed and super useful, this one lives in the Landy. It is not really a first aid book, more of a Haynes manual for you body. If you are squeamish at the best of times look away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was very luck to get a good tip for purchasing my copy of Tom Sheppard&amp;#039;s book the Vehicle Dependent Expedition Guide. When I was looking I was shocked at the prices. When you have read the book you will understand why they command such a price. The level of detail is astonishing and will leave any other book on the topic standing in its shadow. The tip I got was to phone the Royal Geographic Society to purchase a discounted copy from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2240.jpg?w=189&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;189&#34; height=&#34;258&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I am still reading Tom&amp;#039;s book to this day, it lives beside my bed. The reason is that it is a good reference and I don&amp;#039;t think a cover to cover type read. You need to take your time to absorb the topics in this book. The devil is most definitely in the detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This book will answer all the questions you have from logging your trip in detail, maintenance of your vehicle to the type of sleeping arrangement you want. If you can think of a vehicle related question, the answer is probably in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Definitely a good book to start reading and referring to during what ever you are planning for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2255.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;273&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since I purchased this book I have also read another of Tom&amp;#039;s books called Quiet for a Tuesday. This book you should buy even if you only plan to look at the photos! It is an account of Tom&amp;#039;s trip to Algeria, where he had all his maps confiscated by officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily thanks to his insanely methodical record keeping, Tom managed to navigate and enjoy his journey in the Algerian Sahara. Whilst avoiding the authorities!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;He finds out during his covert travels whilst trying to recover the maps with the help of contacts back home, that the Authorities most definitely do not want him to stay! So having acknowledged this will probably be his last trip in Algeria he makes the most of the journey. Which will probably end up in him being banned from Algeria, due to a misunderstanding, which is exactly what happened in Libya.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boab Braai</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/03/25/boab-braai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 09:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/03/25/boab-braai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have been going thru cheap portable braai&amp;#039;s (aka bbq&amp;#039;s) like cheap toilet paper. They are generally made of very thin pressed sheet steel and don&amp;#039;t last. The cost of these and the disposibles we occasionally resort to has begun to add up. So we have resorted to buying a decent portable... The Boab Braai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1100423.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-232&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We purchased the braai from Boab.biz in 2010, they import stuff from South Africa and have a nice expanding product range. The first impression you get when it turns up is the sheer weight of the thing. This is not a Braai you walk far with. We live about 600 meters from the beach and it is hard work carrying it down just that far! It is perfect in the back of the Landy thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As you will no doubt know this braai is fairly well travelled, it has been used in over 12 countries with us and is now about to be used on the third summer trek. It is now obviously fairly dirty, but a good clean now and again brings it back to life. The surprising thing is how well the paint work has held out. We have actually been fairly rubbish at cleaning it etc, left it in the rain and there is little sign of corrosion. This is obviously a desirable feature in a braai. I keep thinking I will need to touch the paint up, but have so far put it off as it is no where near bad yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1100424.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-231&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Boab Braai - Hard at work on the South Downs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of the nice things about the Boab Braai, is the grill is of a decent size. Meaning you can easily cook for about 5 people depending on what you are cooking. The grill is also a heavy duty mesh and frame so does not buckle or get damaged with repeated cleaning or time. You will also fail to loose sausages through the grill due to the grill having a square pattern!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of the nice features of the Boab Braai is that the lid also has legs and becomes a handy cooking table for beer and utensils. One feature of the lid we have not tried is the griddle. Perhaps soon. Thou. The braai also comes with a handy pot holding arm, we use this for utensils, as we generally use out petrol Coleman stove for pots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The only downside with the Braai, is that due to the dimensions and design it can be tricky to get started if you are complacent in setting up the coals. This is because there is no vents for air to get in at the base of the fire. Since I purchased the Boab Braai they have added a log burner base to the accessories which would adress this. In reality if you are an experience fire starter (twisted fire started, sorry...) this will not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The great thing about the Boab Braai is that the grade of material allows for a decnt camp fire after dinner. Just don&amp;#039;t get done by a forest ranger like we did, who promptly doused the Boab Braai with water!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Verdict: Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Boab Braai Datasheet PDF&#34; href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/boab-ultimate-braai-factsheet.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the data sheet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Leave a comment let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/boab-braai-complete-large.jpg?w=512&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-230&#34; width=&#34;410&#34; height=&#34;819&#34; alt=&#34;Boab Braai Complete&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>