<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hungary on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/hungary/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hungary on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/hungary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 9: 15 AUGUST, Keszthely (Hungary) – Lake Tisza (Poroszlo, Hungary)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/16/day-9-15-august-keszthely-hungary-lake-tisza-poroszlo-hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 16:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/16/day-9-15-august-keszthely-hungary-lake-tisza-poroszlo-hungary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Not a long journey today distance wise, but a long journey due to road conditions and traffic. A very muggy day today. Cassie and Dan both sat in the car topless. We managed to successfully navigate our way through Budapest, but only after getting lost trying to find the M3 exit. Oh well…you can’t have it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since Bovec, we have experienced 4 thunderstorms. This time we drove straight into one. Trees were blown into the road, turning it into a slalom course. A branch was blown onto the landy at one point too! It was such a heavy storm, we had to stop and wait for it to pass. Then…it started to hail! What an experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed for our planned destination, only to get there and find that the camp site no longer existed. We had to continue onto the next town. We finally found a small camp site and changed our plan of 2 nights, to 1 night and a stay in a B&amp;amp;B at the next stop. We braaied for dinner. Over the cooking meat, we got chatting to a young couple about Hungary and places to visit. He recommended going to Tokaj, a Unesco World Heritage site for it’s wine making. We happened to already have it on our list, so decided to stop there for breakfast/lunch. An early night for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080639.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080640.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>