<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Croatia on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/croatia/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Croatia on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/croatia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9 - Duga Resa to Bihać</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/04/day-9-duga-resa-to-bihac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 19:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/04/day-9-duga-resa-to-bihac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well we had a surprisingly quiet night. We thought we would be woken up, having seen and heard the action at the bar, but managed to sleep through. We packed up promptly and made for a café in Duga Resa. The plan was to have some coffee and find something for breakfast. Duga Resa is a tiny place. At this stage I should point out that we still had not found a local cash machine and all I had was Euros. Which is fine for bigger places, but the lady in the café, did not accept them. By the time I remembered it was obviously too late and I had already ordered the coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the lady had a plan, there was a tiny tiny shop around the corner run by two ladies, who were obviously used to all the tourists from the campsite popping in for bits and bobs. I asked if they would mind changing some Euros for me, they agreed, but had to have a discussion about changing as much as 50 Euro, of course it was by this time too late for me to say &#34;How about 30, then?&#34; which fell on deaf ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now back at the café, I sat down for Wendy to tell me what she heard. I should mention that a fat man with a very bad blonde mullet with an irish accent, driving a slovenian plated white van, left the campsite at the same time as us and followed us in to the café. Anyhow, on entering the café I offered for him to go before us in the café while we procrastinated, he declined. After placing our order we heard him say in an irish accent to the Croatian lady &#34;Is the boss around?&#34; Thats unusual! Passing him on the way to the shop, I noticed them talking to a local inside the partially open rear door of the van, I think they used the term Cognac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130484.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I got back and Wendy said, she heard mullet man saying on the phone to a fellow traveller &#34;you better get up here now, there is a shed&#34; our suspicions were confirmed about this lot. About 20 minutes later another of the Irish envoy turned up, in a SUV. Now, remember none of these people speak Croatian. I heard them saying to each other that we spoke english and the language! We can order coffee, beer and juice and ask for the bill. But I have no idea how to say &#34;Do you have a shed we can store our dodgy alcohol in please?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130494.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we left them to it and returned to the shop to grab some stuff for lunch and headed off. We were headed towards Velika Kladuša on the back roads, which lead to some interesting views and sights. Arriving at the border crossing about an hour or so later. By the time we got to the crossing it was getting hot, we queued for about 30 minutes, left Croatia and tried to enter Bosnia and Herzegovina. To be told that the crossing did not have an insurance agent. This meant we would not be able to buy a green card, which meant we had to turn around and re-enter Croatia and head for the Bihać crossing near the Plitviča National Park. Luckily the border guard felt sorry for us and opened up the barrier so we could jump the queue. On the way back through, the Croatia guard recommended that we try to buy insurance at Slunj. We tried and failed there opting to just try at Bihać.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130496.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky at Bihać, the guard did not really care if we had insurance. Normally they hold a passport until you can demonstrate that you have insurance. They returned all our documents and trusted us to go to the offices a 200 meters on and get insurance. The agents building was dark and smelt really bad under the cigarette smoke, housing about 8 or 10 agents. Most of the offices had closed doors with people who did not really care for your presence. I approached a lady who looked at me with slight sympathy in one of the offices asking her for &#34;Osiguranje&#34;, insurance in Croat. She had no idea, knocking and asking on all the doors. Just as she was giving up she told me after a colleague suggested to knock on the last door. I was in luck. They agree to do it, but struggled to find the forms! 30 Euro for 17 days. Moments later I piped out in triumph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130595.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this we motored towards Bihać not quite sure were to go. We passed the town on the outskirts not really seeing any good parts, and found shortly afterwards a sign for &#34;Autokamp&#34;. We decided we wanted to rest and stopped, it was a camp almost empty in the grounds of an empty hotel, Hotel Ada. There was a Spanish van and a Dutch van on site when we arrived. Later two more arrived. The place was deserted. It was a nice campsite though, it had loads of well established trees which provided tons of shade, no need for the awning. We popped the tent up and explored the river bank for a place to swim in the Una. We were lucky the river was beautiful and nice and cool. We spent about an hour swimming before popping back for a shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night we opted for an early dinner at the next door restaurant. It was a fantasy land from a film, outside it had a spit roast lamb on the go. The main building was an old mill and the river weaved between it and pontoons that supported seating areas. In amongst the pontoons the river flowed clear enough to allow viewing the plants and fish, like being in an aquarium shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a kilogram of lamb with flat bread and salad for dinner, finished off with Baklava and several local beers. All in around 25 Euro and fantastic. We headed to bed after a brief chat with our neighbours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a great first day in Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8 - Bovec to Duga Resa</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/03/day-8-bovec-to-duga-resa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 13:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/03/day-8-bovec-to-duga-resa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided that today we needed to get cracking and head south. I would have loved to have stayed longer in Bovec, but the campsite was fully booked over the weekend, so we had to either find another site, or move on.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130475.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we spent sometime trying to work out where to head, without driving too far, whilst fitting in with our rough plan. We eventually decided to head for the wine road south-west of Zagreb in northern Croatia. This is a road that runs between Samobor and Jastrebarsko and is famed for its wine. We found the area and the road specifically, with no problems. The route was beautiful and the drive was ideal in the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if I have mentioned previously, but the Garmin Montana GPS is dead (my second one). It does not boot beyond the maps loading at start up, so we are navigating by one of the 1:200k maps we have. Not a problem. Luckily I love maps so have more than enough to compensate. Anyhow, we stopped to get our bearings for a minute, I killed the Landy while Wendy sorted herself out so I could have pee. Jumped back in and the engine did not turn over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I thought I had failed to activate the immobiliser correctly, so did it again. Same outcome. By the third time I could not hear the starter motor solenoid pull in. Ok, I would need a multimeter. Once I grabbed that, I popped off the fuse cover the starter relay was pulling in there was 12 volts on the contact to the solenoid. Which leaves a couple of items as likely causes. Either wiring or connection or starter motor. Engine was too hot and the afternoon was too hot to get close to check either. Not wanting to hang around and given that no one had passed us in 15 minutes, I decided to bump start the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were facing up hill and against the bushes… Luckily I managed to do it in about 2 meters in reverse. We carried on along the route for a while. About 20 minutes on and Cassie needed to wee now, so I stopped nose up a bank. Flicked the ignition and the starter flicked over, good sign… Killed the engine and it restarted, excellent. I suspect connections. I had a similar issue with a connection which was installed by a previous garage removing the stock alarm system. Which I fixed. This had prevented the fuel cut out solenoid activating about 18 months ago. I suspect the same issue here I hope. I&#39;ll replace the crimp when we stop for a couple of days somewhere and I am bored. At the moment the problem has not reoccurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, by this stage we were looking for one of the recommended Vineyards in the Bradt guide, which also had rooms. We found it. But no one was to be found. We waited for a few minutes before deciding to find the second recommendation. This was about another 30 minutes on. We had a different outcome with this, we found signs to the place and followed them diligently up gravel tracks, but the place was nowhere to be seen. We re-read the guide description. We asked locals who pointed up in the right direction. We found a place but it appeared to be another vineyard, by this time we had done the gravel track three or four times. Wendy and Cassie went to investigate, they followed the loud music, I saw a person from outside, they knocked, entered and found no one. Returning minutes later like the place was empty but having a ghost rave. We gave up and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130483.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well what do we do now? On the map a campsite was shown slightly south of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karlovac&#34;&gt;Karlovac&lt;/a&gt;. They make the famous beer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karlovačko&#34;&gt;Karlovačko&lt;/a&gt;. We eventually found a cool campsite south of Karlovac in Duga Resa. They were busy, but had an excellent river to swim in and a reasonable restaurant, which suited us, given, we were by this time absolutely knackered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically we were surrounded by a very big group of Irish travellers headed for Bosnia, they had large caravans. Fairly modern. Towed by Transit vans. The group as a whole were making a lot of noise. The kids were climbing all over the bathrooms. We were worried we would be associated with them, so stayed well clear despite out close proximity. They looked dodgy, why would you travel in such a large group. I am guessing 30 in total?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeljava Airbase - The Former Yugoslavia&#39;s Most Secret Airfield</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 18:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889158964_c853f3ebe0.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;DC-3 abandoned&#34; width=&#34;427&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The main reason for heading up to the Plitvička National Park again, was not this time to visit those beautiful lake, which bring most tourists to the area. My research for interesting things to see on our travels, had caused me to stumble  upon the abandoned airbase at Zeljava. Some of which is on the Croatian side, the rest spans the border of Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having seen the lakes and tourist crowds a year ago, we decided to fore go the experience again. We planned the day such that the bio-in-laws, would disappear in the morning to the lakes, Cassie was desperate to join them so went to show them around. Then if they returned in time they would join Wendy and Myself to visit Zeljava to try and find the base. As it goes they did return and three of us disappeared to find the base. Cassie stayed at camp with Carole. We had spent the morning tidying up the car and catching up on what would be best described as administrative tasks. Oh, I also spent the morning superglue&amp;#039;ing the rear indicator lens back together, from two million pieces in the grass...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889406454/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889406454_5ea4028caf_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;209&#34; height=&#34;279&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;From our campsite across the valley we could see mount Plitvička and mount Gola which hid Zeljava from us, the summit is home to modern radio masts, probably cellular these days. Being over looked by this helped build up the anticipation for me, we had been longing to do something different since Mont Saccarel in Italy. We did not manage to get to the top of the hill to explore, although I had a gps track to find our way. I believe during the period that the base was in use, the mountain over the airbase housed a radar warning system which was part of a network for Yugoslavia, this formed a early warning system for the airspace around Yugoslavia similar to NORAD. Regardless of what was now at the top, it would have been nice to explore, and it probably would have provided great views of the base, back to the camp and also over Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889378116/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889378116_1a38622bd4.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889398448/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889398448_71685d1284.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the net there is a lot of interest around military bases and sites, Zeljava is no different. It did not take long to establish it&amp;#039;s location months before we departed the UK. I used google earth to verify and then generated a waypoint for the GPS. As I also had 1:200k maps of the area from our last visit, I drew a box around the area and highlighted it so I could find it during the trip. Before we departed the UK, I had been to Stanford Maps in London looking for more detailed maps, I would have preferred 1:50k or 1:25k, but they had nothing better than I had. I also had a look on the Internet for a source but was not successful, I don&amp;#039;t know if such detailed maps are produced for the area? Perhaps not for walkers, I guess the land mine risk is still very real, I expect military maps do exist thou, in fact I have seen extracts of Military maps, so am sure they exist. If you know a source please leave a comment or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889447928/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889447928_c316a60bd3.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889451114/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889451114_d4300e011a.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;357&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Getting to the Plitvička area had been a great drive the previous day, although it was slow. I set the GPS to go via a couple of minor towns along the border area, and also set it to minor and un-paved roads, avoiding highways and major roads. Oh how the route impressed us, we went through tiny habitations and along mostly single carrage roads were the Tarmac barely remained. One section saw us follow about 20 km along a gravel route to a lake, I think the people there before us had stayed the night, it was a watering hole for a horse trek also. Had we been on our own I think we would have stayed the night. At the exit of this track we took the oppurtunity to stop at a sign that said &#34;Med&#34;, which is honey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889430760/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889430760_9c19261aeb.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;321&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The locals sell their honey, local plum brandy known as Rijeka and often wine, being tourists, they took the oppurtunity to sell us the golden delight at a much inflated rate, not speaking Croation meant we had little choice, but to  either except or move on. Needless to say we choose the former, two gigantic jars of Honey for 150 Kuna. Working out the price I have no idea how we got to it, when we did not understand the man, he just shouted louder! Our indications to write it in the dirt got lost in translation. Oh well we leave richer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889428454/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889428454_84d179df0a.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;370&#34; height=&#34;277&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on the route took us along routes that over looked Bosnia and Herzegovina, where we could see old border walls from the conflict, deserted habitations and bullet ridden houses, signs for mines are still a fairly common sight and leave otherwise beautiful land abandoned. Croatia has always struck me as a country of contrast, in respect to redevelopment post conflict. The coast is very built up and apparently affluent, were as if you head inland, there are still areas were buildings are derelict and bare the bullet scares of the war. The people on the coast are mostly involved in some way with tourism, the people inland are hard working farmers and manual workers. They look honest and interesting, I wish I could converse with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Thanks to the net there is a lot of information available about the history of the base. It&amp;#039;s construction was started around 1948, at the time it was known as Objekat 505. The actual pooring of the concrete is in some of the info I read is supposed to have started a few year later in the 50&amp;#039;s. Construction was finished around 1968. On completion it was given the name &#34;Klek&#34; and had a military post cost of 4868, to reflect the start and finish years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The design of the base is such that the tunnels are semicircular, and big enough to allow fighter jets to enter, the tunnels are about two jets wide. When the tunnels were constructed they had positions for explosives to be placed, such that detonation would cause the facility to become unusable. The entrance to the tunnel is shaped to allow the tail of the aircraft to enter the tunnel like an upside down &#34;T&#34;shape, these could be blocked by 1 meter thick pressurised doors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The internal sections of the base are designed to withstand a 20 kilo-tonne nuclear bomb. Which I have read is equivalent to the nagashima bomb, in Japan during world war two. As you would expect being able to withstand such a blast would imply that the doors would have to be kept shut. The base internally had generators, fuel storage, waste storage and water. The most important facilities were all located in the tunnels, with a mess room capable of seating 1000 people. Fuel was piped from storage tanks located 10 to 20 km away in a mountain in Bosnia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Above the main tunnels in the mountain, accessed by elevator only from inside the tunnels, was a room that was used for strategic planning and by the operators of the early warning radar system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The base was in use until the 1990&amp;#039;s and at one stage was looked at with a view to modernisation around the late 1970&amp;#039;s. When it was first built it is said to have cost some where between 4 and 6 billion US dollars. Apparently the funding came from the world bank and was secured for development of communication routes (motorways and roads) in the former Yugoslavia. The construction was carried out by a Serbian firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the end, during the conflict it was the Yugoslav Peoples Army (JNA) who detonated the pre-prepared explosives for distruction of the base on there retreat. I guess the base would have been rather useful to advancing forces. Later there was further distraction of the base using 56 tonnes of explosives, by the military of Serbian Krajina, this was carried out in 1995. Articles on the web site locals as saying that the force shock local towns like an earth quake and that the tunnels smoked for 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889025612/in/set-72157631310217932&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7889025612_623531420e_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;External to the tunnels there are five runways on the base three lead straight into tunnels. The last two were used for other aircraft to land. The total area I&amp;#039;d the base was on the order of 9km by 4km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Ordinarily staff at the base lived in the town of Bihać, which is in Bosnia now, this was the nearest city. I have read on one site that there was a dedicated bus service between Bihać and the base for staff to commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our Visit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Croatian side of the airbase comming from the Plitvička national park there is only really one way to get to the base by road. In order to this your arrival is via the small village of Zeljava, which seemed almost empty save for a few dozen people who live in the houses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the village and the base are various buildings that appear to be abandoned almost deralict in some cases. Shortly after the village on the main road on the left you pass gates, behind which it is possible to glimpse an old military plane. It is possible to see how cars have avoided the closed gates and damaged fence, to make there own path to the road behind the gates. Where it eventually leads who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued past the planes to the find the rest of the base, about 1 kilometre further, we came across what was our first sign of more to be seen. Buildings hidden on the right by trees, this time of the year the dense trees and shrubs provide good cover for the buildings and relics hidden around the base. We cut off the main approach road, to explore what appear to be vehicle maintenance or facility areas. We abandoned the car at this stage choosing instead to explore by foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceeding towards the runway areas south east from where we were brought us via vehicle inspection ramps to another open area, that we were not sure of the use of, but it was littered with hydraulic hoses and metal scraps, there were various bullet ridden sign posts and behind the trees, what looked like a discarded bomb, that was not / had not detonated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We continued towards the end of what was runway 4 and runway 3, which meet at the what looks like an apron, prior to the entrances to the tunnels 1 &amp;amp; 2. Turning right, past another mine warning, the open apron gives way to the approach to the tunnels, which was almost claustrophobic with the tree cover that was slowly reclaiming the base, making it feel close. As you approach the tunnel entrance you feel that there is something watching you. All the time listening to rustling and noises in the trees,never being able to identify what the source was. Eventually we knew we were close by the wall of cold air that hit us, emerging from the tunnels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Shortly before the tunnel entrance we noticed a strange metal object that although half complete looks like a soldier or guards metal hat. The tunnel mouth although visible is obscured on the lower half by a mount of dirt that has been placed to prevent people taking vehicles into the tunnels. Entrance by foot is possible, having no torches or breathing equipment we choose to avoid this option on this occasion, instead staring into the dim light. We chose to avoid entrance because of a report I had read warning of toxic chemicals in the dust and potentially radio active waste from the fire detection equipment that was unaccounted for. Appart from this entry is fairly hazardous due to the unstable nature, but probably would not have prevented us if we had not been fortunate enough to read the report (available in the site links below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After this we went on to explore tunnel entrance two, but were interrupted by the sudden noise of several 4x4&amp;#039;s at first we were unsure of the nature of these vehicles, as I had previously read of border police being sensitive in this area, probably because of the unguarded border to Bosnia and Herzegovina. Luckily the vehicles turned out to be civilians tourists. With this we recovered our vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We returned back with the vehicle to explore the remaining section beyond the apron towards the unmanned Bosnian border, along the approach we passed various buildings for fire and parking areas. In one area, we came across the remains of a military vehicle minus the chassis and engine on its side. This looked like it had been hit by something, judging by the holes in the body. Not sure what it was used for thou. Along the road we came across spent bullet shells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We proceeded further to the border, where we came across an eyry owl, that was remarkably tame. Was this some kind of sinister warning? After taking some film we stopped at the UN border barrier for some photos, before making our way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way out we wanted to look at the abandoned aircraft near the base entrance. These turned out to be a DC-3 and two F-84 fighters, I was not able to work out the exact type. But they proved an interesting addition to the visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References / More Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found most of the info I wanted by following links out of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C5%BDeljava_Air_Base&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia Zeljava Airbase&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeljava-lybi.com/Zeljava-index2_eng.html&#34;&gt;Zeljava Lybi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 19 - 21: 17 - 21 AUGUST 2011 Trogir (Croatia) – Plitvička Jezera Nationalni Park (Croatia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/22/day-19-21-17-21-august-2011-trogir-croatia-plitvicka-jezera-nationalni-park-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 17:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/22/day-19-21-17-21-august-2011-trogir-croatia-plitvicka-jezera-nationalni-park-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Korana 171KN per night – 3 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Well…what a record, up and gone by 8.15hrs!!! Plus, Wendy went to pay for the night and made a complaint about being put on a pitch that wasn’t a pitch but a dog toilet! Well…they didn’t like this, but they still gave us a “discount”. We just wanted to leave this awful place. We decided to head for Plitvička Jezera. No GPS to navigate us, so we decided to just head for the motorway. It was a toll road but fast, so we just sat back and drove. We finally made our exit and headed for the lakes. We found a campsite and decided 3 nights was a good stop. We were fairly early, so set up camp, went looking for a shop to buy lunch and dinner for today from. Back to camp and we just chillaxed, as Dan and Cassie say. Cassie and Dan watched a movie on the laptop while Wendy lay in the sun reading. Ah! Great to relax. We did some washing of clothes and got wifi at the information centre. Here we also got information on the lakes and entry prices. Had a beer at the bar and then headed back for our braai for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9547.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 20: THURSDAY 18 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Had a little lie in, but the heat of the sun coming over drove us out of our tents. We had a lazy breakfast and headed off to explore the lakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;SHEESH!!! Talk about crowds! It was 11.30hrs and the car park was packed. We wondered over to the entrance and joined the extremely long queu for tickets. Dan managed to get student price by showing his University of Birmingham student card and Cassie being 6yrs old, was free! Actually, thats been a good thing about travelling through most of these countries, under 6yrs and you aren’t charged for them…BONUS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So we followed the hoards into the national park, boy were there hoards. We made the choice to walk around and not catch the boat across the big lake. Once we got passed the point where everyone was boarding the boats, the crowds fizzled out and you could actually enjoy the walk. The walk took us 3½hrs and left the lakes at 15.00hrs. The lakes were beautiful. Crystal clear, you could see right down to the bottom of quite a few of them. Fish and ducks galore. We headed back to the supermarket for supplies. Back at camp, we lazed around and did a bit more washing etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A little accident happened to us the night before, we had bought 2 bottles of olive oil, one for us and one as a gift. Dan got ours out to cook with and when he went to open it, the cork popped out like gun fire. He asked me to find the second bottle, but I couldn’t find it. Dan eventually found it, exploded in the toiletry and medical box! Needless to say, we spent the next hour or so cleaning olive oil off our medicines. Not a happy moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we took the computer to the bar and had a pivo whilst checking emails etc. Then we went back to camp and had another braai for dinner. We were going to head for the Barać caves just up the road tomorrow, then come back, do house keeping ready to leave early the next morning before the sun’s heat becomes unbearable in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9455.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9457.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9469.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9494.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9506.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9514.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 21: FRIDAY 19 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Another lazy start with a leisurely breakfast. Dan and Cassie went to check emails whilst Wendy went to shower. All dressed, so off we set for the Barać caves. After a little navigating hiccup, we found our way there and set off for the tour. We were told by some nice Dutch couple that the caves were 9°C, we decided to brave it without a jumper. In a small group, with our guide, we headed up to the caves. Hard hat kitted out, we entered the cave and so the tour began. We were told that flashes on our cameras were not allowed, but people continued to use them and eventually our guide banned the use of cameras outright. We managed to get a few pictures though. And I didn’t use the flash I might add. Cave expedition over, and back to camp we headed. Again we did mundane house keeping – clothes washing etc. and then relaxed in the sun. That evening we packed up camp ready for an early rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9553.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9569.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 22: SATURDAY 20 AUGUST 2011 Plitvička Jezera (Croatia) – Forno di Zaldo (Italy)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Al Pez €26.80 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We were up, packed up and gone by 8.30hr! We had decided to miss out Venice as most of the campsites wanted a weeks booking, we only wanted to stay for 2 nights. Instead we were going to head for Northern italy, then using our already purchased Swiss Vignette to bomb through Switzerland and straight through France, using the fast motorways. We didn’t want to get stuck in expensive Austria or Switzerland again. Unfortunately we only had a large map of Italy to guide us. A day driving on toll roads, and as we left Croatia, we got stuck in a queu of Italian cars that were also leaving Croatia. We headed into Italy navigated by Wendy and maps. Needless to say, we took an incorrect exit and ended up in a horrendous traffic jam! Once through it, we found our way back onto the correct course. We finally beat all the traffic and navigational errors and found camping in a small mountain town. It was a no car next to tent camp, but the man let us camp in a field next to a motorhome. We noticed toilet paper in the spot we had to put our tent, so we decided to stay only one night. We put up our tent and then went in search of a beer. After being told that there wasn’t a bar, we wondered around and just happened upon a bar! We treated ourselves to an Italian beer. A pasta dinner and an early dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9577.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9578.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9580.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 18: TUESDAY 16 AUGUST 2011 Lumbarda, Korčula (Croatia) – Trogir (Croatia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/17/day-18-tuesday-16-august-2011-lumbarda-korcula-croatia-trogir-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 17:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/17/day-18-tuesday-16-august-2011-lumbarda-korcula-croatia-trogir-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Kamp Seget 191KN – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to leave early today, perhaps that was because we didn’t sleep due to the celebrations that consisted of loud music and singing. We reached Vela Luka at about 9.30hrs, purchased our tickets and went for a wonder around town. We had 4 hours to kill till the ferry. We managed to also find an exchange place that would exchange our Serbian Dinar! A relief as lots of places were simply saying no way. It was now simply a case of sitting and drinking coffee and waiting for the ferry. Oh and we are all covered in horse fly bites. We boarded the ferry and actually managed to get on first, meaning first off the ferry. We got our stuff together for the journey and made our way up to the saloon. We managed to find a table to sit at and here we stayed for the 2½ hr journey. Wendy got a little sea sick as she usually does on a ferry journey, so she wondered from occasion to help quell the sick feeling. Finally we pulled into split port and off we went. Dan was extremely excited to be first off the ferry. Off we headed for Trogir. We finally made it to Trogir and headed for the camp mentioned in the Bradt Guide. BOY! The traffic to cross the bridge into the little island Čiovo was awful…unfortunately this was where the camping was said to be so we sat in the queue. When we finally got to the campsite, they were full! We decided to carry on along the coast and see what we could find. We happened across a camp, and as it was getting late, decided to stay. Well, they put us next to the shower block where we swear fellow campers came to pooh their dogs. We assumed this as so many dog owners walked to where we were camped, stopped, stared and then walked away confused. Dan also swore blind that the place had fleas, so we deeted up, not wanting more bites. We went to take Cassie for a swim, the beach stank!! There was a motorhome toilet dump right at the entrance to the beach..you could see it as we sat and swam…disgusting!!! This was the straw that broke the camel’s back for us and so we opted to pack up early and leave. An early night, ready to skedaddle in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9415.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9427.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9434.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 16/17: 14/15 AUGUST 2011, Mostar (Bosnia) – Lumbarda, Korčula (Croatia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/16/day-1617-1415-august-2011-mostar-bosnia-lumbarda-korcula-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 17:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/16/day-1617-1415-august-2011-mostar-bosnia-lumbarda-korcula-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Camping costs: Autokamp Vela Pelarka 99KN per night + 20KN electricity – 2 nights (7KN = €1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Woken by the Call to Prayer, not heard that for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We went to see the Dervish house in Blagaj before setting off to Croatia. We went down and took a look, but they were busy doing conservation work to the house and rebuilding the surrounding houses around the dervish house. Cassie was amused as a dog followed us from the parking along to the path to the house, and it was waiting for us when we got back. The house seen, we had a coffee and planned our Croatia stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9229.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9232.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9239.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to head for the island of Korčula, first seeing what the ferry prices were like. We got to Ploče with an hour till the ferry. It was 218KN (€13) for the ferry, so we paid and waited. We boarded the ferry to Trbanj. The ferry took 1 hour and then we headed for the ferry to Korčula at Orebič. The drive there was great, but we only had 30min to do it to catch the next ferry,and, we were stuck behind a coach! We made it to the ferry port, Wendy hopped out to run and buy ferry tickets. We just made it onto the 14.30hr sailing. From Korčula we headed for Lumbarda. The guide book said it had nice beaches and the map showed camping. We made Lumbarda in good time and found some ok camping amongst some olive trees. Mainly motorhomes, but still, a place to pitch the tents. We set up the tents, Wendy got pivo and then went in search of the beach for a deserved swim! Spent the rest of the afternoon swimming, then returned to camp for dinner. Need to wash more clothes in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Cassie’s Notes: When we got to Lumbarda we went to the beach. I had so much fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9246.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9248.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9253.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9272.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9288.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9289.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9290.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9302.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 17: MONDAY 15 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have arrived in Lumbarda during their national holiday/festival. We seem to be following the holidays. We decided to go into Korčula old town today. Cassie wants to see medieval places as that is her topic at school when she starts back in September. We had a wonder around, bought some souvenirs and went back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9305.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9312.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9322.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9339.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan popped across to the supermarket to get some lunch and Wendy did some more clothes washing. We wondered down to the beach again and spent a few hours paddling around. Cassie found half a goggle and Dan took it along with the camera and did a little bit of diving. He took some photos of sea urchins, sea cucumbers and some fish. The sea here is so beautifully clear. After a wonderful afternoon in the sea, we went back to camp to shower. We decided to go out for a bight to eat, perhaps taste the wonders of the local fishermen. The restaurant recommended to us was fully booked, so we tried somewhere else. The restaurant we found was great, the owners were bringing in the fish caught that day, gutting and finning them right there and then, ready for the evenings service. We saw a dish: lobster and spaghetti for 2. We decided to order it. The dish consisted of 2 lobsters, mussels and prawns in a lovely bisque sauce on a bed of spaghetti. Not only was it a tasty dish, but it was also a tasty price. We ordered spaghetti bolognaise, lobster and spaghetti for 2, a couple of beers and juice and it all came to 350KN, a fair €50! You would definately have paid well over £100 for this meal in the UK. Back to camp for an early night so we could break camp early to catch the ferry from Vela Luka to Split the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9354.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9357.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9362.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9367.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9372.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9364.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 7: FRIDAY 5 AUGUST 2012 Dovje (Slovenia) – Velika (Croatia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/06/day-7-friday-5-august-2012-dovje-slovenia-velika-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 17:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/06/day-7-friday-5-august-2012-dovje-slovenia-velika-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Pension Basišiĉ 340.00 KN (Kuna) – 1 night (7KN = €1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As we only had 1 tent to pack up, and we woke up earlier than our alarm, we managed to leave at a fairly decent time today. We didn’t have far to go according to the GPS so we had a nice drive. We had to purchase a Slovenian Vignette for the toll roads and then when we got to Croatia we had our first boarder crossing. The fantastic Hannah Montana GPS, routed us into the truck driver passport control!! If it wasn’t for some nice truck drivers letting us through, we probably would have been stuck there for a lot longer than normal. Passports were finally shown to stern looking Policemen. Once through border control we had to pay a toll. Wendy didn’t listen to Dan very well, and Dan wasn’t clear enough in his instructions to Wendy (I might point out that nerves might have been a little frayed), however, we lost €4 as the toll was only 68 cents and Wendy paid with a €5 note and got NO change!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So, we made it through the border, but had no local currency. Our next step was to find a bank. As we drove along, we saw countless birds of prey, Dan and I thought that they were falcons. They were all just sitting alongside the roadside on the fence. Cassie got very excited about seeing them. We finally arrived in Velika, but could not find the campsite that was marked on our map as well as on the tourist information board. We drove around, even attempted to ask a local. Eventually, we decided to head for a Pension we had previously seen. When we finally found it, we were lucky that there was a local man (circa 80 years old) at the Pension who spoke Australian English… and helped us with the Pension owner, who spoke no English. The same guy showed us to a local restaurant, it was very kind of him. We went back to the Pension to have a shower and then went back to the restaurant for dinner. Our phrase book was next to useless! Luckily, we brought along our guide book, that had a little phrase book at the end of the book that, fortunately, allowed us to be able to order us some dinner. Cassie had a pizza, Dan had a mixed grilled and Wendy had a grilled kebab. We went back to the Pension, and as we had to drive to the restaurant, we had a beer in our room. Cassie got her fix of T.V and watched something in Croat. Alarm set and to bed we went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8558.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8559.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8583.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning the Summer 2011 Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/07/26/planning-the-summer-2011-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/07/26/planning-the-summer-2011-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This Summer Dan has managed to wangle 4 weeks off work. To add to that, Wendy has changed jobs and now has the school holidays off, so she has 6 weeks holiday over the Summer! This has allowed us to open up our plans, expand our horizons and we have this year decided to travel down to the Serbia, Montenegro and the Bosnia area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As usual we consulted our UNESCO World Heritage book for ideas of places to stop in the countries we would like to be visiting this year. We also bought Bradt travel guides for the same countries and started our “plan”, we only do this to amuse Wendy, Dan would rather just book the ferries point the Landy in the right direction and be done with it. Luckily the plans are never stuck too, not even the ferry bookings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have a Michelin Europe Map (705), which is on a really large scale (1:3 000 000), which is great for planning our trips. It gets more and more tatty each year, not to mention colourful. So, we sat down with our trusty old Europe map and plotted places we found in book, on-line and in the guides. With help from a few glasses of Vino, this is what we came up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8029.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had this plotted, we decided to draw up a Google map. Unfortunately Google won’t route you through Bosnia, so we have had to route around Bosnia to create our map. Pity really. We have shared this Google map with family so that they know the rough route we plan on travelling. We should really just say we are heading to Devon for a month, any mention of going further a field tends to instil panic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/summer-2011-overview-map.jpg?w=640&#34; width=&#34;515&#34; height=&#34;371&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Between the plan’s inception and leaving there were a few things to sort out. When you leave the EU you need an international driving permit (IDP), we got this at a local post office in WHSmiths, what a bad experience! The cue was massive and the staff a bit unfamiliar. Next time I think we will use the AA postal service. Apart from the IDP, insurance is an issue. The EU 3rd party cover will not be valid in some countries out side Europe, like Serbia. We managed to confirm that a green card would be available on the border. Prices vary wildly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Over and above paper work, maps needed sorting, both paper 1:200 000 and GPS. The car needed a service and a couple of niggles sorting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Only 4 days to go and the car needs to be packed up by Thursday as Dan has a meeting Friday. The flat once again looks like a camping store with piles here and boxes there… Clothes are being washed ready to get packed up. Pity the English weather isn’t being helpful in the way of supplying sunshine. But it looks like all is going ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>