<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slovenia on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/slovenia/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slovenia on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/slovenia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 7: FRIDAY 5 AUGUST 2012 Dovje (Slovenia) – Velika (Croatia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/06/day-7-friday-5-august-2012-dovje-slovenia-velika-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 17:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/06/day-7-friday-5-august-2012-dovje-slovenia-velika-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Pension Basišiĉ 340.00 KN (Kuna) – 1 night (7KN = €1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As we only had 1 tent to pack up, and we woke up earlier than our alarm, we managed to leave at a fairly decent time today. We didn’t have far to go according to the GPS so we had a nice drive. We had to purchase a Slovenian Vignette for the toll roads and then when we got to Croatia we had our first boarder crossing. The fantastic Hannah Montana GPS, routed us into the truck driver passport control!! If it wasn’t for some nice truck drivers letting us through, we probably would have been stuck there for a lot longer than normal. Passports were finally shown to stern looking Policemen. Once through border control we had to pay a toll. Wendy didn’t listen to Dan very well, and Dan wasn’t clear enough in his instructions to Wendy (I might point out that nerves might have been a little frayed), however, we lost €4 as the toll was only 68 cents and Wendy paid with a €5 note and got NO change!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So, we made it through the border, but had no local currency. Our next step was to find a bank. As we drove along, we saw countless birds of prey, Dan and I thought that they were falcons. They were all just sitting alongside the roadside on the fence. Cassie got very excited about seeing them. We finally arrived in Velika, but could not find the campsite that was marked on our map as well as on the tourist information board. We drove around, even attempted to ask a local. Eventually, we decided to head for a Pension we had previously seen. When we finally found it, we were lucky that there was a local man (circa 80 years old) at the Pension who spoke Australian English… and helped us with the Pension owner, who spoke no English. The same guy showed us to a local restaurant, it was very kind of him. We went back to the Pension to have a shower and then went back to the restaurant for dinner. Our phrase book was next to useless! Luckily, we brought along our guide book, that had a little phrase book at the end of the book that, fortunately, allowed us to be able to order us some dinner. Cassie had a pizza, Dan had a mixed grilled and Wendy had a grilled kebab. We went back to the Pension, and as we had to drive to the restaurant, we had a beer in our room. Cassie got her fix of T.V and watched something in Croat. Alarm set and to bed we went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8558.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8559.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8583.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 5/6: WEDNESDAY 3/4 AUGUST 2011, Bürserberg (Austria) – Dovje (Slovenia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/05/day-56-wednesday-34-august-2011-burserberg-austria-dovje-slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 17:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/05/day-56-wednesday-34-august-2011-burserberg-austria-dovje-slovenia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Camp Kamne €50.16 incl. electric – 2 nights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today was a long drive. We set off a little later than we should have and encountered lots of windy mountain passes. We went into Italy with a drastic scenery change, out and back into Austria and then finally into Slovenia. The hairpin bends we drove seemed almost endless. We stopped for diesel and managed to get some bread as well. We then spent a few hours trying to find a good spot for lunch. We finally pulled into a little side road and just picnicked off on the side. Lunch over, it was now time to crack on and make it to Slovenia. The road into Slovenia was another story all together! What a steep incline, to add to that it was another mountain pass, lined with various warning signs. Dan stopped and put the car in low range so we could make it up and ignore all the warnings. The pass over, we headed for the nearest campsite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we were settled and set up, we looked at the distance to our next planned stop and decided that we would stay 2 nights. We needed the break and not to mention the stretch of the legs. Maybe a nice leisurely stroll into the mountains tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8455.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8457.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8467.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 6: THURSDAY 4 AUGUST 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Last night there was an immense thunderstorm (What is it about Slovenia and the Bovec area?). We ended up with Cassie in the tent with us. It was an uncomfortable nights sleep due to the fact that little missy moo Cassie likes to spread herself out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We met a couple staying in the camp. They are from New Zealand have are travelling around Europe with their 2 kids for 6 weeks before moving back to New Zealand. They recommended going to see the nearby waterfall, Slap Peričnik. Here you can walk behind the waterfall too. Sounds cool. We decided to walk there, going to the nearby town of Mojstrana and to the information centre to ask about the weather. From here we walked up to the waterfall. It was along the road that we walked and had to move out of the way of a few cars now and then, but it quickly turned to a gravel track. When we got to the waterfall, it was another sharp hike up to the falls themselves. A little steep climb, we used this opportunity to show Cassie how to navigate these types of things independently. At the top the spray from waterfall was immense, refreshing and a little shocking. We walked along behind the waterfall, getting soaked in the process. It was lovely and refreshing after the long old walk to get there. We explored a bit and then we stopped at the picnic spot at the bottom for lunch, just simple bread and cheese. Next we went to the Café and had a beer. Cassie had a juice and Dan got her a souvenir cow bell. We saw another track on the map that went along the other side of the river, we decided to walk back along here. It was like we were in another place, walking through the trees, watching the butterflies and dipping our feet into the freezing stream. It was a lovely walk back. Overall, we walked 18km today. We stopped off at the supermarket in Mojstrana to get some supplies and headed back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we got back Cassie went for a swim with the little girl from the New Zealand couple we met. That night we had a concoction of a dinner, hoisin chicken stir fry with carrots, red peppers and onions with Mediterranean couscous. Cassie thought it was delicious, but Dan and I didn’t agree. We decided to pack up Cas’ tent and sleep all in the 1 again incase there was another storm. This time though, we put Cas’ mattress in as well to try and make it a little more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8473.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8478.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8490.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8491.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8497.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8505.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>