<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Summer 2011 on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/summer-2011/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Summer 2011 on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/summer-2011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Serbia, Unexpected off road</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/01/serbia-unexpected-off-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 09:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/01/serbia-unexpected-off-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just been playing with the iPad iMovie app. Last year when we were in Serbia, we were following the GPS to go from the Studenica monastery to Durmitor and ended up going along a grade gravel road. This as it turned out, was the foundation for a section of soon to be E-760, we think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;We ended up turning back after giving the workers a few laughs. We had fun, they got a laugh everyone&amp;#039;s a winner. After turning back we ended up following another proper farm track which turned out to be good fun. We got a little lost and came across a farmer who looked bemused!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we popped out the other side a little muddy and happy with the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first video shows were the GPS thought we were. The second shows the farm track that we eventually used.
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HWU9MqfHTYU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JB1uuHmhOEg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durmitor National Park, Montenegro - Garmin Maps</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/28/durmitor-national-park-montenegro-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 20:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/28/durmitor-national-park-montenegro-maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-11-sep-2011-10142.jpg?w=253&#34; alt=&#34;Durmitor National Park 1:25000 map&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we stayed in Durmitor National park, during our August 2011 trip, the guy who seemed to run the camp site at &lt;a title=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.durmitor-autocamp.com/home.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Autocamp Razvršje&lt;/a&gt;, gave us a great walking map, which I kept, being a map addict. Actually I think he gave one to everyone, so we weren&#39;t special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, by luck the other day they sent out a marketing email. Intrigued I browsed their site and noticed they had an electronic copy of the map and others on their site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are pretty good maps of the area in 1:25,000 scale. So I thought I would grab a copy for next time I am there. Anyway, follow the link above to their site to get a copy or there are links below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also if you need a place to stay, Autocamp Razvršje is as good as any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Some Garmin devices such as the Montana series allow the importing of custom maps. This is done via Google Earth. You have to import the map as a layer to Google Earth then align it (georeference), then save it as a KMZ. Once this is done you can import it to Garmin&#39;s Basecamp or upload it and save it to the Custom Map folder on your GPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a copy of the Durmitor KMZ I made click &lt;a title=&#34;Garmin Durmitor KMZ&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/Durmitor National Park Map 25k.kmz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructions on creating custom maps are available &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/custommaps_instruct.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:none;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-19491.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-19491.jpg?w=650&#34; alt=&#34;Durmitor&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;469&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:none;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1949.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1949.jpg?w=650&#34; alt=&#34;Tara Canyon&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;469&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/tara-kanjon-karta.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tara Canyon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/primorje.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Montenegro Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/060214_m.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Montenegro General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 27: THURSDAY 25 AUGUST 2011 Villey le Sec (France) – Hove (England)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/27/day-27-thursday-25-august-2011-villey-le-sec-france-hove-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/27/day-27-thursday-25-august-2011-villey-le-sec-france-hove-england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We woke up in the pouring rain! We decided to pack up and see how the weather goes as we drive. Needless to say, that it did not clear up rain, rain, rain. We stopped just outside reims to get some food from the supermarket. We made the decision that as we were only 200km (give or take), so we decided to just carry on all the way to Calais.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We arrived at 15.45hrs and were told we could board at 17.45hrs. We had 2 hours to kill. We wondered around the port for a bit, then got a coffee from the vending machine. Above the vending machine was a sign for a restaurant on the 2nd floor of the port building. We decided to go and find it. We wondered across but failed to gain access as we needed our ticket and passports. Dan decided to go and fetch them whilst Cassie and I waited. When we found the restaurant, we had some explosively expensive drinks and sat and whiled away time. We got to the car to load onto the ferry. Once on the ferry, we had a small snack to keep us going. Finally back in the UK…back to grey, cloudy, dreary UK. We made it home at 20.30hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The end to the 2011 Summer Adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 25/26: 23/24 AUGUST 2011  Altkirch (France) – Villey le Sec (France)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/25/day-2526-2324-august-2011-altkirch-france-villey-le-sec-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 17:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/25/day-2526-2324-august-2011-altkirch-france-villey-le-sec-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Camping de Villey le Sec €44.60 + electricity – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A little late rising, but not an issue as we had packed things up the night before. In the morning, tents packed up and off we went back to the supermarket to get a map so we could navigate back to Calais. Map bought, and off we went, in the right direction. We drove to Nancy and decided that we’d pull over and look for a supermarket for food and then a campsite. After our supermarket trip, we saw signs to a campsite and so we decided to follow them. The campsite was ok, so we decided to stay for 2 nights. We put up the tents, awning and had lunch. Dinner that night was simple, sausages, rolls, gherkins and mustard. As we cleaned up after dinner and put Cas to bed, we heard thunder rolling in, luckily Cas was asleep. The heavens opened up and it absolutely bucketed down! As the night wore on, the thunder got worse and such Cassie woke up. She ended up in our tent again for the night. To say that we got no sleep would be an understatement. The storm did not relent, it just got worse. The rain got heavier, and as we were camped between a river and a lake, we thought that with both rising we might actually wash away. At one point, the thunder was so loud, it scared the living daylights out of us. From the outside, the tent must have jumped off the ground with our fright! The tent held up despite the immense amount and heaviness of the rain, it did not leak once! Morning arrived and Cassie happened to be the only one out of us 3 that had managed to actually get a good nights sleep! The day seemed cloudy, but dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9648.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 26: WEDNESDAY 24 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Tired and worn from the previous nights storm and restless sleep, we got up and had breakfast followed by 2 coffees! We simply lazed around. Cassie took some bread from todays baguette and went to feed the ducks. Cassie and Dan then played Mario Bros. on her Nintendo DS… Dan got carried away and had to get to the point where you could actually save your game. After a stroll around the camp, Cassie started chatting to 2 English girls and so Dan and I got chatting to their parents. We shared holiday routes and jourmney lengths etc. They were travelling in a bongo and so Dan had a look out of interest for Carole and Daniel (Wendy’s Biological Parents who would be visiting us next Summer). The family were leaving that afternoon, and after a nice long chat we decided to let them pack up whilst we went back to the tent for lunch. The sky looked ominous, so we decided to string our tarp up over the tents. We then decided to take Cassie’s tent down, put her in our tent again, so that if it did rain again we’d only have 1 tent to take down in the rain. As we moved the tent under the tarp and got it semi to our desired set up, the heavens opened. We were thankful we’d put the tarp up and ate our lunch under the awning and tarp in dryness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As quickly as the heavens had opened, they cleared up and the sun showed it’s face again. We all moved our chairs out into the sunshine and sat reading and playing games. We idled the day away, playing with Cas in the park, playing music, Dan taught Cassie knots and before we knew it, dinner time was upon us. A simple dinner of steak and salad which Dan made whilst Cassie and Wendy played in the park. Dinner over and dishes washed, Cassie showered, it was bedtime. Now the skies were clear and blue, Murphy’s law, take precaustions and what you plan for never happens. Better to be prepared though. Time to move on again tomorrow, heading for Reims. We will try to get 200km covered so we are near enough to calais for the ferry and last stop. The eeking out of the last days of holiday. Lets hope they stay sunny!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9655.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9656.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9676.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 23/24: 21/22 AUGUST 2011  Forno di Zaldo (Italy) – Altkirch (France)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 17:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Les Acaises €32 – 2 nights incl. electricity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were up late, but still managed to pack up and leave in good time! It was a long drive today. We managed to find a garage for diesel and luckily some better maps. We started our navigation out of Italy, through Austria, into Switzerland and finally…just through the border into France. Once in France we decided to stop for dinner as it was very late, then go and find a campsite. After a nice pizza and salad, we went in search for a campsite…what a search that was. After driving and driving we finally found signs to a campsite! We were saved! This was the latest we had ever left it to find a camp – 21.00hrs! We set up tents, had showers and put Cassie to sleep. We would spend 2 nights here so we could relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9639.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9636.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9646.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAY 24: MONDAY 22 AUGUST 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke up at leisure today. Wendy washed some more clothes and then we went in search of a supermarket. We didn’t have anything for breakfast, so stopped off and bought some croissants along the way. After wondering through town, we hadn’t found a supermarket, so we sat and had a coffee. We had also seen signs for a swimming pool, but couldn’t see find it anywhere. Dan asked a man if there was a supermarket and he gave us directions. We did minimal shopping as we had to carry it all the way back again, and it was a trek back to the campsite. Back at the campsite, we decided to hop into the car and go in search of the swimming pool… unfortunately we did not find it. Back at the campsite, Dan and Cassie went to the bar to use the internet. The couple that run the campsite have 2 children and they connected a hosepipe to a tap and started running in the spray. Cassie went and joined in. After a good run around, Cassie and the daughter came back to our camp to watch Lady and the Tramp. Dan did a few housekeeping bits to the Landy whilst Wendy baked in the sun. After awhile, Cassie went back to join the fun in the hosepipe, and Dan and Wendy joined them too. That evening we went up to the bar and partook in a couple of beers and iced tea for Cassie. After putting Cassie to bed sudden rain came down. It wasn’t hard, but strange as there were no clouds about to warn of rain. Dan and Wendy went to bed with Thunder and lightening. It didn’t last long, thankfully, as we dreaded the thought of having to pack wet tents in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 19 - 21: 17 - 21 AUGUST 2011 Trogir (Croatia) – Plitvička Jezera Nationalni Park (Croatia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/22/day-19-21-17-21-august-2011-trogir-croatia-plitvicka-jezera-nationalni-park-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 17:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/22/day-19-21-17-21-august-2011-trogir-croatia-plitvicka-jezera-nationalni-park-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Korana 171KN per night – 3 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Well…what a record, up and gone by 8.15hrs!!! Plus, Wendy went to pay for the night and made a complaint about being put on a pitch that wasn’t a pitch but a dog toilet! Well…they didn’t like this, but they still gave us a “discount”. We just wanted to leave this awful place. We decided to head for Plitvička Jezera. No GPS to navigate us, so we decided to just head for the motorway. It was a toll road but fast, so we just sat back and drove. We finally made our exit and headed for the lakes. We found a campsite and decided 3 nights was a good stop. We were fairly early, so set up camp, went looking for a shop to buy lunch and dinner for today from. Back to camp and we just chillaxed, as Dan and Cassie say. Cassie and Dan watched a movie on the laptop while Wendy lay in the sun reading. Ah! Great to relax. We did some washing of clothes and got wifi at the information centre. Here we also got information on the lakes and entry prices. Had a beer at the bar and then headed back for our braai for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9547.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 20: THURSDAY 18 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Had a little lie in, but the heat of the sun coming over drove us out of our tents. We had a lazy breakfast and headed off to explore the lakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;SHEESH!!! Talk about crowds! It was 11.30hrs and the car park was packed. We wondered over to the entrance and joined the extremely long queu for tickets. Dan managed to get student price by showing his University of Birmingham student card and Cassie being 6yrs old, was free! Actually, thats been a good thing about travelling through most of these countries, under 6yrs and you aren’t charged for them…BONUS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So we followed the hoards into the national park, boy were there hoards. We made the choice to walk around and not catch the boat across the big lake. Once we got passed the point where everyone was boarding the boats, the crowds fizzled out and you could actually enjoy the walk. The walk took us 3½hrs and left the lakes at 15.00hrs. The lakes were beautiful. Crystal clear, you could see right down to the bottom of quite a few of them. Fish and ducks galore. We headed back to the supermarket for supplies. Back at camp, we lazed around and did a bit more washing etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A little accident happened to us the night before, we had bought 2 bottles of olive oil, one for us and one as a gift. Dan got ours out to cook with and when he went to open it, the cork popped out like gun fire. He asked me to find the second bottle, but I couldn’t find it. Dan eventually found it, exploded in the toiletry and medical box! Needless to say, we spent the next hour or so cleaning olive oil off our medicines. Not a happy moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we took the computer to the bar and had a pivo whilst checking emails etc. Then we went back to camp and had another braai for dinner. We were going to head for the Barać caves just up the road tomorrow, then come back, do house keeping ready to leave early the next morning before the sun’s heat becomes unbearable in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9455.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9457.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9469.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9494.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9506.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9514.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 21: FRIDAY 19 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Another lazy start with a leisurely breakfast. Dan and Cassie went to check emails whilst Wendy went to shower. All dressed, so off we set for the Barać caves. After a little navigating hiccup, we found our way there and set off for the tour. We were told by some nice Dutch couple that the caves were 9°C, we decided to brave it without a jumper. In a small group, with our guide, we headed up to the caves. Hard hat kitted out, we entered the cave and so the tour began. We were told that flashes on our cameras were not allowed, but people continued to use them and eventually our guide banned the use of cameras outright. We managed to get a few pictures though. And I didn’t use the flash I might add. Cave expedition over, and back to camp we headed. Again we did mundane house keeping – clothes washing etc. and then relaxed in the sun. That evening we packed up camp ready for an early rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9553.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9569.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 22: SATURDAY 20 AUGUST 2011 Plitvička Jezera (Croatia) – Forno di Zaldo (Italy)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Al Pez €26.80 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We were up, packed up and gone by 8.30hr! We had decided to miss out Venice as most of the campsites wanted a weeks booking, we only wanted to stay for 2 nights. Instead we were going to head for Northern italy, then using our already purchased Swiss Vignette to bomb through Switzerland and straight through France, using the fast motorways. We didn’t want to get stuck in expensive Austria or Switzerland again. Unfortunately we only had a large map of Italy to guide us. A day driving on toll roads, and as we left Croatia, we got stuck in a queu of Italian cars that were also leaving Croatia. We headed into Italy navigated by Wendy and maps. Needless to say, we took an incorrect exit and ended up in a horrendous traffic jam! Once through it, we found our way back onto the correct course. We finally beat all the traffic and navigational errors and found camping in a small mountain town. It was a no car next to tent camp, but the man let us camp in a field next to a motorhome. We noticed toilet paper in the spot we had to put our tent, so we decided to stay only one night. We put up our tent and then went in search of a beer. After being told that there wasn’t a bar, we wondered around and just happened upon a bar! We treated ourselves to an Italian beer. A pasta dinner and an early dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9577.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9578.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9580.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 18: TUESDAY 16 AUGUST 2011 Lumbarda, Korčula (Croatia) – Trogir (Croatia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/17/day-18-tuesday-16-august-2011-lumbarda-korcula-croatia-trogir-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 17:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/17/day-18-tuesday-16-august-2011-lumbarda-korcula-croatia-trogir-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Kamp Seget 191KN – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to leave early today, perhaps that was because we didn’t sleep due to the celebrations that consisted of loud music and singing. We reached Vela Luka at about 9.30hrs, purchased our tickets and went for a wonder around town. We had 4 hours to kill till the ferry. We managed to also find an exchange place that would exchange our Serbian Dinar! A relief as lots of places were simply saying no way. It was now simply a case of sitting and drinking coffee and waiting for the ferry. Oh and we are all covered in horse fly bites. We boarded the ferry and actually managed to get on first, meaning first off the ferry. We got our stuff together for the journey and made our way up to the saloon. We managed to find a table to sit at and here we stayed for the 2½ hr journey. Wendy got a little sea sick as she usually does on a ferry journey, so she wondered from occasion to help quell the sick feeling. Finally we pulled into split port and off we went. Dan was extremely excited to be first off the ferry. Off we headed for Trogir. We finally made it to Trogir and headed for the camp mentioned in the Bradt Guide. BOY! The traffic to cross the bridge into the little island Čiovo was awful…unfortunately this was where the camping was said to be so we sat in the queue. When we finally got to the campsite, they were full! We decided to carry on along the coast and see what we could find. We happened across a camp, and as it was getting late, decided to stay. Well, they put us next to the shower block where we swear fellow campers came to pooh their dogs. We assumed this as so many dog owners walked to where we were camped, stopped, stared and then walked away confused. Dan also swore blind that the place had fleas, so we deeted up, not wanting more bites. We went to take Cassie for a swim, the beach stank!! There was a motorhome toilet dump right at the entrance to the beach..you could see it as we sat and swam…disgusting!!! This was the straw that broke the camel’s back for us and so we opted to pack up early and leave. An early night, ready to skedaddle in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9415.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9427.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9434.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 16/17: 14/15 AUGUST 2011, Mostar (Bosnia) – Lumbarda, Korčula (Croatia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/16/day-1617-1415-august-2011-mostar-bosnia-lumbarda-korcula-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 17:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/16/day-1617-1415-august-2011-mostar-bosnia-lumbarda-korcula-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Camping costs: Autokamp Vela Pelarka 99KN per night + 20KN electricity – 2 nights (7KN = €1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Woken by the Call to Prayer, not heard that for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We went to see the Dervish house in Blagaj before setting off to Croatia. We went down and took a look, but they were busy doing conservation work to the house and rebuilding the surrounding houses around the dervish house. Cassie was amused as a dog followed us from the parking along to the path to the house, and it was waiting for us when we got back. The house seen, we had a coffee and planned our Croatia stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9229.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9232.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9239.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to head for the island of Korčula, first seeing what the ferry prices were like. We got to Ploče with an hour till the ferry. It was 218KN (€13) for the ferry, so we paid and waited. We boarded the ferry to Trbanj. The ferry took 1 hour and then we headed for the ferry to Korčula at Orebič. The drive there was great, but we only had 30min to do it to catch the next ferry,and, we were stuck behind a coach! We made it to the ferry port, Wendy hopped out to run and buy ferry tickets. We just made it onto the 14.30hr sailing. From Korčula we headed for Lumbarda. The guide book said it had nice beaches and the map showed camping. We made Lumbarda in good time and found some ok camping amongst some olive trees. Mainly motorhomes, but still, a place to pitch the tents. We set up the tents, Wendy got pivo and then went in search of the beach for a deserved swim! Spent the rest of the afternoon swimming, then returned to camp for dinner. Need to wash more clothes in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Cassie’s Notes: When we got to Lumbarda we went to the beach. I had so much fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9246.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9248.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9253.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9272.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9288.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9289.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9290.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9302.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 17: MONDAY 15 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have arrived in Lumbarda during their national holiday/festival. We seem to be following the holidays. We decided to go into Korčula old town today. Cassie wants to see medieval places as that is her topic at school when she starts back in September. We had a wonder around, bought some souvenirs and went back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9305.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9312.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9322.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9339.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan popped across to the supermarket to get some lunch and Wendy did some more clothes washing. We wondered down to the beach again and spent a few hours paddling around. Cassie found half a goggle and Dan took it along with the camera and did a little bit of diving. He took some photos of sea urchins, sea cucumbers and some fish. The sea here is so beautifully clear. After a wonderful afternoon in the sea, we went back to camp to shower. We decided to go out for a bight to eat, perhaps taste the wonders of the local fishermen. The restaurant recommended to us was fully booked, so we tried somewhere else. The restaurant we found was great, the owners were bringing in the fish caught that day, gutting and finning them right there and then, ready for the evenings service. We saw a dish: lobster and spaghetti for 2. We decided to order it. The dish consisted of 2 lobsters, mussels and prawns in a lovely bisque sauce on a bed of spaghetti. Not only was it a tasty dish, but it was also a tasty price. We ordered spaghetti bolognaise, lobster and spaghetti for 2, a couple of beers and juice and it all came to 350KN, a fair €50! You would definately have paid well over £100 for this meal in the UK. Back to camp for an early night so we could break camp early to catch the ferry from Vela Luka to Split the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9354.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9357.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9362.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9367.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9372.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9364.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 15: SATURDAY 13 AUGUST 2011 Donji Morinj (Montenegro) – Mostar (Bosnia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/14/day-15-saturday-13-august-2011-donji-morinj-montenegro-mostar-bosnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/14/day-15-saturday-13-august-2011-donji-morinj-montenegro-mostar-bosnia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Sobe (A dodgy private room) €25 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A fairly early start for us, with not far to travel either. The border crossing was uneventful, even for a Saturday. We managed to make it to Mostar by 14.30hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;FOOTNOTE: The Garmin screen has given up the ghost. Unable to use it to navigate, we are now subject to map (i.e Wendy) navigation. She seems to get a little better each year though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;No camps in Mostar, so we decided to enquire about room prices. The first one quoted €40 for a night, Dan said it was a nice place but a little to steep. Not by UK standards thou. We parked up in secure, paid parking and went on the quest for a room. After enquiring and being lead to the back of beyond, we got a fair enough price on a room for the night – €25. We accepted and then went to get a pivo + sok. We found a lovely bar overlooking the river and under the famous old bridge. Cassie managed to brave up and wonder down to the river to put her feet in. We watched a few teenagers dive into the river from a platform on the opposite side of the river. After our pivo, we went exploring. We wondered along the souvenir alley, here we got our obligatory fridge magnet, a plate for the wall, Cassie got a wooden box and Wendy got some harem trousers. After that we had another pivo. It was extremely hot. Not that it is an excuse! Then we went to find a recommended restorant in the Bosnia guide book. We ordered a mixed grill for 2 people – honestly this could have fed 4 people! We thought we’d hunt out a place called ABC, a sweet shop, said by the guide book, to be the best in Bosnia. We managed to find it and had a dessert. Dan had a cake, Wendy and Cassie had some ice cream. We then wondered back to Tusky to get our bits and bobs and back to our room. A good nights sleep for a change. Woke up fairly early and were showered and out by 8.00hrs…a record!! Off to Blagaj and the Dervish house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9093.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9118.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9124.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9199.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;100&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9130.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9151.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9156.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9165.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9174.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9208.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9213.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 13/14: 11/12 AUGUST 2011 Žabljak (Montenegro) – Donji Morinj (Montenegro)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/13/day-1314-1112-august-2011-zabljak-montenegro-donji-morinj-montenegro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 17:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/13/day-1314-1112-august-2011-zabljak-montenegro-donji-morinj-montenegro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Ravela €30 – 2 nights + €6 for electricity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today we drove down to the coast of Montenegro. We first took the scenic route out of Durmitor…what a drive. Amazing views and mountains. We stopped for a coffee along the way and Dan managed to buy himself a Durmitor t-shirt. When we arrived at the coast, and drove around the bay, the views were wonderful. Especially the drive down the mountain to the bay. We stopped off and bought some wine from a couple selling home made vino. We wanted to get as far around the bay as possible. But even so, we didn’t find a campsite till much later on. We were praying we wouldn’t have to stay in a pension as it looked like an expensive area. We finally found a nice little campsite nestled on a river with lime and olive trees planted around it. We even camped next to another Landy! We set up camp, it was late, so we wondered up to the mini market and got a small snack for dinner. An early-ish night, ready for the beach tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8981.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;101&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8982.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8983.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8992.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8998.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;99&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 14: Friday 12 August 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Last night there was very load Montenegrin music. Apparently there is a music festival happening over the weekend. Woke up and did some much needed clothes washing! The day was already stinking hot and the few bits and bobs Wendy washed yesterday were already dry. Once everything was hung up, we headed for the beach. It was a scorcher of a day but the sea was quite chilly. Wendy read her book and soaked up the rays whilst Dan and Cassie paddled and explored. After a couple of hours on the beach, we went and got some bits and bobs for lunch and took it all back to the campsite. Here we did some more washing, ate lunch and went on the internet. After the heat got to us a little more, we went back for another dip in the sea. We also investigated the local restorant to see what their prices were like…EXPENSIVE! Back to the supermarket to get a snack dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9010.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9014.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9027.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9041.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9058.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9059.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9065.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9086.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 11/12: 9/10 AUGUST 2011 Studenica (Serbia) – Durmitor National Park (Montenegro)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 17:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Razvršje €10 – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We attempted to have a lie in this morning, we managed to sleep until 7.50am! A shower to wash away the bed bugs and another cereal breakfast in our room. Off into the Monastery for a look see. The monastery was quiet, we seemed to be the only visitors at that time. The restoration team were there hard at work and inside the chapel it seemed like they had a lot of work on their hands and perhaps for a few many years. Off we went onto our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8851.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8869.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8883.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Back through that little town Ivanjeca, where this time we bought a plastic sealed drum/tub to act as our washing machine. Our washing was now getting out of hand. The border crossing into Montenegro was a breeze with the Green card only €15 this time! We finally made it to Durmitor and we found a campsite! A stop of 2 nights and a proper rest up. It was our anniversary, we wanted to go out for dinner, but town was a bit of a walk. Instead, we had dinner cooked by the campsite owner an elderly local lady. Trout, Bean soup, salad and potatoes oh and free beer. It was a lovely meal. They had erected an old military mess tent to act as a dining room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8914.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 12: WEDNESDAY 10 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It rained last night, not heavily, but a lot. And when we woke up, it was still raining. We stayed in the tent because of the rain. Dan got up and made us tea and coffee, we drank it inside the tent. Today was a day that having our big tent would have been useful with its big middle bit. We’d used up all the milk, so we decided to go into town to get breakfast. As we left we thought we’d look at the time…it was 11.30! We walked into town and attempted to change our Serbian Dinar into Euro, but no-one was having it. We went to the baker and got: 1 loaf of bread, 2 donuts, 1 pastry, 2 sausage rolls and 1 jam cake slice…all for €3.30! Bargain! It was off to the supermarket for supplies. As it was still raining on and off we decided to come back into town for dinner. We stopped for a coffee and juice and headed back to the camp. We made up a sandwich for Wendy, packed up the back pack and headed off for Crno Jezero or Black Lake. The walk was 20-25 min walk there. Along the way we walked through an abandoned Serbian holiday camp. Very eerie and spooky. When we got to the lake, we walked around it to find Tito’s cave where he’s said to have hid his supplies during the 2nd World War. The cave was no longer a cave, it seemed to have been blocked up. A little disappointing. We walked back to camp. The walk back was a little harder as all up hill. When we got back none of us were hungry, so we decided to just have a drink and snack and possibly an early night, with prayers of a sunny morning. We ended up ordering food from the lady again: pork chops, potatoes and salad, free beer too.. We had an early night, ready to move on in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8915.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8923.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8927.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8928.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8941.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8951.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8945.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8947.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 10: MONDAY 8 AUGUST 2011 Mokra Gora (Serbia) – Studenica (Serbia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/09/day-10-monday-8-august-2011-mokra-gora-serbia-studenica-serbia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 17:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/09/day-10-monday-8-august-2011-mokra-gora-serbia-studenica-serbia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: Studenica Hotel €15 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Up early with a breakfast of our cereal and milk. A shower and change and off to Mokra Gora Ŝargan Eight Railway. We got there early, so bought tickets, sorted out the back of the Landy and went to have a coffee. We saw crowds growing and the engine head for the carriages. Dan went to pay and Cassie and Wendy went to get a seat on one of the carriages. So the journey began. The train had speakers playing the story of the railway in Serbian, and surprisingly, English too! The journey up was interesting, a few tunnels we went through and a stop at the top where we bought an ice cream. Then, on the journey down the train stopped at all these platforms, the story referred to them as ‘crazy stops’, it made the journey back a lot longer than it needed to be. When we got back, we loaded ourselves up and set off for Studenica and the Monastery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8730.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8734.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8735.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The drive was hard going with the windy mountain passes. We stopped in a funny little town called Ivanjeca for lunch and to get some more money. We decided to have ice cream sundaes for lunch as non of us were particularly hungry…probably the stinking heat we were experiencing today. The sundaes we ordered turned out to be fruit salads with ice cream and cream. Dan’s was a kind of float sundae concoction. Yummy never the less. Off we trudged for the rest of our journey. As we drove we wondered where on earth the monastery was. It seemed as though we were just driving and getting no where! Finally, around the corner it came into view! Relief washed over us. We had made it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;First thing we saw was a great big sign telling us: NO SLEEVELESS SHIRTS, SHORT SKIRTS TO GO INTO THE MONASTERY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That counted that evening out as Wendy was in a boob-tube and skirt, Cassie was in a sleeveless shirt and Dan was in shorts…non of us were in the mood to change either. We decided to park at the sign that showed sobe/rooms and enquire about prices to stay. We thought that we would stay 2 nights, firstly to rest and secondly to explore and maybe take a swim in the river. The receptionist told us €15 for the 3 of us for 1 night. We agreed, got our key and went to investigate. The smell hit us first…damp, old and mothballs. Then the visual got us…pot hanging from the ceiling in the corner to catch water, ceiling masking taped together, light bulb cello-taped together and the list carried on. We thought this was the only place to stay, so we gathered our bits and bobs and put them into the room and went for a pivo and sok. The “hotel” had no kitchen so we had to walk up behind the monastery to get food. It turns out there’s another hotel, one in much better condition that we could have stayed at…oh well…too late now! A Serbian guy at the hotel, who was working at the monastery on a conservation project, told us that the hotel we were eating at and the Studenica Hotel were taken over by the Monastery. They were now just resting places. The one we ate at had just had some work done to it, but the one we were staying at hadn’t had anything done to it for at least 30 years! That night we slept wondering if bed bugs were going to gnaw us and if the ceiling would collapse on Wendy in the night. We woke up in one piece and decided to hit the road. One night was enough. It was off to Durmitor National Park in Montenegro. Good bye to the Hotel from the Shinning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8814.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8815.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8817.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8821.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 9: SUNDAY 7 AUGUST 2011 Fruŝka Gora (Serbia) – Mokra Gora (Serbia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/08/day-9-sunday-7-august-2011-fruska-gora-serbia-mokra-gora-serbia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 17:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/08/day-9-sunday-7-august-2011-fruska-gora-serbia-mokra-gora-serbia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Private room €20 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We went to see the Ravanica Monastery near Vrdnik. They were having a service, which was expected as it was Sunday. We respected Catholic culture and crossed ourselves as we entered the church. We stayed a few minutes and listened to the priest give his sermon, not that we could understand his Serbian. We left and decided to go to another Monastery. When we got to the next Monastery, there was a sign saying, “No short skirts or strappy tops”. Both Cassie and Wendy were wearing strappy tops and Dan didn’t feel comfortable going in wearing shorts. So we walked around the side to see if we could peak in, but the monastery had a high wall. We went back to the car and decided to go off and find the next monastery. Now this part was an adventure…. We followed the GPS directions and ended up following a gravel track. We carried on a bit further and found no monastery, so we decided to just head straight for Mokra Gora. The battery for the camera ran out at this point and we missed out on taking photos of the beautiful scenery we passed on the way to Mokra Gora. We stopped at a little bar for lunch and the lady made us, what we think was a Serbian Hamburger, it was more like a lardy shredded pork pattie. We then hopped back into the car and made our way. We stopped at a roadside stall to buy some Med (honey) and some Rakija, a plum brandy made in Serbia. We should have haggled with the ladies, but when you can only ask how much and understand the basics of what they are hand gesturing to you, bargaining isn’t quite on the cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Wendy had found a campsite mark on the map, so we tried to find it, to no avail. We don’t think they have campsites here and unfortunately, we just weren’t brave enough to free camp in the area as it looked to be mostly farmed land. As we saw the sign for Mokra Gora, we saw a sign for sobe. Dan went to go and enquire. The sobe turned out to be a small apartment. Cassie stayed free and it was €20 for Dan and Wendy for 1 night. Bargain! We stayed, and had to reverse Tusky into the track alongside the apartment. That was a little challenge. At one point Tusky tipped and it felt as if she was going to tumble sideways…but she didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we walked up to the film set town – Mećavnik to have dinner. The town was built by a Serbian film director for a movie. It is built as a typical 19th century Serbian town and serves typical Serbian dishes in it’s restaurants. There were some singers and a band performing classic Serbian songs. Which, according to Dan, gave the place a surreal feeling. We ate dinner, had a wonder around and walked back down to our room. We planned to leave early and catch the Ŝargan Eight Railway. After that, we were to head to Studenica and the monastery there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8688.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8699.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8707.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8701.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8724.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8702.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 8: SATURDAY 6 AUGUST 2012 Velika (Croatia) – Fruŝka Gora (Serbia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/07/day-8-saturday-6-august-2012-velika-croatia-fruska-gora-serbia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 17:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/07/day-8-saturday-6-august-2012-velika-croatia-fruska-gora-serbia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Camping Costs: Hotel/Pension Restoran Zmajevac €27 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to head off into Serbia today but stop in a town called Ilik to see a castle and war memorial. We stopped for coffee which was very nice. Afterwards we headed off to Ilok. The town holds a memorial for the 1991 war. We first stopped at the Ovĉara Memorial which is the site of a mass grave. The towns people of Vukovar were massacred by the Serbs during the invasion. 200 people fled and hid in the local hospital. The Serb army found them and mass murdered them, burying them in a mass grave. Ovĉara is a memorial on the sight where they were found. The floor is set with with all the bullets found in the grave. A very humbling experience. From there we stopped at a vineyard, as Ilok is a wine region and had lunch. The wine was Traminac and was VERY nice, so we bought some. From here we headed to the Serbian border, where we waited to get Green Card Insurance. Here we waited, in the steaming sun, for 40 min or more. The insurance turned out to be €110 for 1 month. When the man finally returned with our insurance, we started our adventure into Serbia. We looked for road signs to Fruŝka Gora, but didn’t see any till we got into the industrial area of Novi Sad. Serbia looks very different to the other countries we have been in so far. A lot more rural even in the city. We stopped for money and to try use the GPS to help navigate us. Serbia uses a cryillic alphabet, it makes reading road signs etc. a lot harder. We found ourselves at the top of the road turning in the Fruŝka Gora park, but not having seen any signs for camping. We decided to carry on looking. We saw some people pitched on the side of the road in a caravan, but we were a little nervous of free camping. We managed to find a sign that said “sobe”, meaning rooms, and headed in that direction. We found a restaurant that also had rooms above it. The price was €27 for all of us, (Cassie stayed free), including breakfast. We decided to stay. We got out the maps and guide books and planned for where to go next. We decided to go and see the monasteries in the park and then head for another national park where they have a little railway you can go on. Mokra Gora, the line used to run all the way to Sarajevo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8638.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8640.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8643.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8650.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8667.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>