<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipad on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/ipad/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ipad on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>iMovie App for the iPad - Trailer for last years holiday.</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/imovie-app-for-the-ipad-trailer-for-last-years-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 13:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/imovie-app-for-the-ipad-trailer-for-last-years-holiday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you read our blog regularly, you may have noticed that I am new to video editing stuff and that I have recently discovered the fun of the iMovie app for the iPad. Consquentially there are a few video clips starting to appear. We are armed with extra SD cards to allow more of this on the next trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two choices in iMovie if you want to produce a video clip, either a new trailer or a new project. I initially glossed over the trailer option. Choosing instead to try a project first, the initial project was a short clip about a track in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/01/serbia-unexpected-off-road/&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Serbia&lt;/a&gt;. I followed this with a couple of short &#34;photo&#34; films for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eY61icqtEMQ&amp;amp;sns=em&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;Bosnia and Herzegovina&lt;/a&gt;, then another about Montenegro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I started playing with the trailer feature, this requires a bit of a video library, which I found hard as I have very little stocked up and have not normally shot it. However from this day forward I hope to shoot more. The trailer feature allows you to make cinema style trailers of your video clips. In the app are a bunch of predefined templates in various styles, such as Bollywood, romantic, comedy and swash buckling (pirate). You can preview each one, which instantly leads to you being drawn in by the excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you choose the style of trailer you want and create a new clip, you are presented with a cast and crew list to populate, which includes some intro and text fields that appear in the trailer. You are also presented with a story board. You simply choose the items on the board and away you go select the video and the frames you wish to use. Once complete the iMovie app assembles them into a very captivating trailer akin to one you may see at the cinema!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our trailer for last summers trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y8SjVon9LVA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diagram below shows the process!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-8-jul-2012-1412.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;iMovie to YouTube via Blogsy to Wordpress&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>