<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crossmember on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/crossmember/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crossmember on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/crossmember/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Upstand/Upriser Re-Assembly</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0091.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now at the stage of re-assembly. It has been a slow road even to strip the back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mid-crossmember is galvanised and from YRM metal solutions. One of the nice features of the new one, is that the top brackets are loose rather than welded on this makes it easier to get the cross member under the fuel pipes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have had with the crossmember is that the holes, for mounting to the chassis rails where about 3mm out across the vehicle. I am not entirely sure why, but I eventually managed to get the bolts in. I suspect it may have been partially due to the camber of the road. I&#39;ve used stainless bolts so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0095.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note on the cross member is that the cut out for the fuel hoses on my vehicle is in the wrong location. This probably varies from vehicle to vehicle. One was YRM could improve this is to have a wider cut out. I have added additional protection and will tywrap the hoses out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the crossmember was in it was time to start fitting the upstand/upriser. The new item is a different size to the old one. In a good way. The lips are about another 10mm deep. This means that around the top a certain amount of fitting is required, this is around the spars under the floor and the doubler between the separate sections of floor near the doors. I only cut out these areas, I like the idea of the extra depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new item seemed longer also, I did not have to cut it down. The reason is that the old panel was tapered making the top shorter than the bottom edge. I spaced it evenly each side and it seems ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0102.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fitting done, I have now dry fitted it, drilled the holes for the top rivets and will tomorrow drill the sides pieces and seat brackets. At the moment the rivets are all loose. I will strip it out and paint it once I have dry assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The floor is in with a couple of screws at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>