<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Equipment on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/categories/equipment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Equipment on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/africanuhambo.github.io/categories/equipment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 19 - Bunec to Beach Cove via Butrint</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 07:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1140027.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a fairly ok nights sleep and woke early. We decided to avoid the breakfast spoken of last night as dinner was a little &#39;dodgy&#39;, for want of a better word. We opted for just a coffee instead. Outside our room we bumped into a lovely lady sitting with her grandson. She asked us where we were from and we told her, &#34;England, Brighton&#34;. She said she knew it and lived in Lewisham. She was on holiday with her family and investigating a business opportunity in Albania. I must add, she was Albanian. We chatted for a bit longer and then bid her farewell, we were off for that coffee.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being reinforced with a coffee, we headed out towards Butrint, we wanted to visit the Roman ruins there. After a long and hot drive, we arrived at the entrance car park to the ruins. Immediately we were accosted by a young urchin girl and her male companion. They demanded that we buy bracelets from them. Dan was in the firing line of their deluge and so we ended up buying a bracelet from the girl and one from the boy. By this time I had another little urchin at my window. She begged that I bought a bracelet from her too, I had to say no. The first young girl then came round to my window and asked if she could have my banana that I had sitting in the front. I laughed and had to admire her audacity. I gave her the banana. She immediately peeled it and ate it as she walked away, pleased at herself for getting another tourist in her trap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were now dripping and feeling a little hard done by, having been accosted by the urchins. We went for a cold drink at the restaurant before entering the sight. At the entrance to the ruins the prices were 700 LEK per foreign visitor, 500 LEK per foreign visitor in a group, 300 LEK for an Albanian visitor and 400 LEK for a child. So it was an entrance fee of 1,400 LEK and so we followed the cruise ship visitors that had just descended on the place by bus load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1140030.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked around the remains. The signs at the entrance had said no smoking, walk on the path and beware the insects and snakes. The last bit made us hopeful we&#39;d see something other than roman ruins. We waited at the first part, an amphitheatre, for the hoards to disappear. Here Cassie discovered a turtle in the water around the ruins. From here we wondered around, skirting the crowds. It was extremely hot, and we were all dripping in sweat by the end. Afterwrds Dan and Cassie got themselves and ice cream and I got a can of cold Coca Cola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1140071.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to head off and find a camp on the beach somewhere. Yesterday Dan had noticed that the radius arm bushes needed changing, especially if we wanted to tackle a few more gravel tracks during the holiday. We had seen plenty of &#39;Autoservis&#39; places along the road and so we went in search of one that could fit us in. We tried a few and they all pointed us to someone else as they were far to busy. Eventually on the way out of Butrint, we stopped at a small garage we had noticed on our way in. He was now quiet and Dan asked if he could do the work, it would only take 1 hour. The guy agreed. He spoke good english and so Dan changed into some shorts and negotiated the car above a pit. Cassie and I sat in the car trying not to expire, while Dan helped the guy change the bushes. All done for 2000 LEK. Luckily Dan had the spares in the car … Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were off now in search of a beach to stay on. They all looked packed and we could not find a turning to some. So, we decided to stop for lunch somewhere. We came across a little village and went to a restaurant. Here the owner spoke good english and we ordered lamb with a greek salad. The owner chafed to us about working on cruise ships and seeing the world, but how now he water to settle in Albania. We asked him about the ferries from Vlorë to Brindisi. He recommended going from Igoumenista instead and offered to let us use the internet to check fares.We thanked him and Dan did just that. The prices and info was not helpful as the ferry from Vlorë did not show up in the searches. We thanked the owner and hit the road once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0264.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we stopped at a little cove we had spotted on the way past yesterday. The water edge was lined with mobile homes, which we only assumed were stopping for the night. As we approached and stopped, a funny Albanian man came up to us and asked where we were from. We told him England and asked if it was ok to stay. He said sure no problem, just park. Dan asked if he wanted money, he said that wasn&#39;t necessary, we were his friends … we concluded he was a little strange and parked up anyway, changed into our kozzies, and went for a dip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1130968.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0270.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0279.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie immediately spotted sea urchins in the water, so we tried to avoid these. Later on we spoke to a lady who had stood n one and was trying to get the poison out her toe. Cassie got the snorkel and mask out and did a little look see in the water. She stayed in for ages! All of a sudden there was a ruckus, some locals nearby had caught an octopus. They started throwing it onto the rocks whilst screaming and shouting. I found this really upsetting. Why not just kill it humanely and hopefully not as sport, but to take it back and eat it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we had been sitting on the beach, the wind had been building. We decided to set the tent up and head for the restaurant for dinner across the road from the bay. As we had eaten a big lunch, we decided to go for a snack type dinner … this didn&#39;t really happen. Dan ordered calamari and I the seafood spaghetti, Cas shared both. The wind was now quite strong. We wondered back to the tent and got ready for bed. Whilst we lay in the tent, we were whipped and bashed. Dan and I worried about it not being safe in the tent with the wind at this strength, so we gathered up our sleeping stuff, closed up the tent and bundled into the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a night of horror! I personally got NO sleep … Dan says he managed a wink or two and I think Cassie was the luckiest out of us all. She probably managed an hour or so. To say we woke early would be an understatement. We were up before 6, teeth brushed and outta there. We were the walking dead but we still headed for Vlorë to see how much it would be to catch the ferry to Brindisi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 - Koplic, Lake Shkrodër</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to stay two nights at Lake Shkodër. Today we woke slowly, having been woken by Cassie in the middle of the night again. After we finally dragged her sleeping items into the tent, thunder rolled in. There had been a little rain too, but not a significant amount. Needless to say, it was a little bit of a restless night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was warming up already by mid morning, and I had decided that the sheets, towels and pillow cases needed to be washed. We also needed to get some food. We asked the owner of the campsite if here was a shop close by and he said yes, just walk up to the main road, over the bridge and there is a shop there. So we handed over our washing, as he had a machine, and set off for the shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1130897.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked we were shocked by the rubbish we saw on the side of the road and dumped in ditches, We passed two young boys by the overpass burning their rubbish. It was a reminder that Albania still had ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were perspiring by the time we got to the shop and had to stop for a cold drink at one of the bars. Afterwards we went to the shop and bought essentials .. water, beer, biscuits and other food items. Now for the walk back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the campsite, Cassie made friends with a young girl from a German family staying a few pitches down. She played all afternoon with Lea and her brother Nic. It was nice for her to have company, and Lea wanted to practice her English as she had recently started learning it at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day Thunder had been rumbling in the background but despite this, it had been warm and sunny.. with a slight cloudy haze. But by afternoon, the lightening started making an appearance and we decided to pack up Cassie&#39;s tent and head for the restaurant/bar. And a good thing we did, as the heavens opened with an almighty bang and gush of wind and it did not let up for hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had grabbed a table inside and here we stayed for the most of the evening. Eventually to be joined by Frank and Anjita, Cassie&#39;s new found friends&#39; parents. The evening was great. We swopped travelling stories, places to visit and even swopped blog addresses. It&#39;s always nice to make friends along the way, so thanks Fank and Anjita for a great evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a second Land Rover at the camp, owned by a Scottish couple that were travelling. We had spoken to them the day before about their set up and swopped maps for tips on places to travel. Anyway, Gus and Helen also ended up at the bar/restaurant and as our table was already full, they sat with a trio of Austrian guys next door to us. As the evening progressed, they ended up joining our table too. We all had a wonderful time drinking wine and beer and swopping stories. Thanks Gus and Helen for your tips and your extending fork!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0134.jpeg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needed a lightweight stove</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 20:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, I needed to get a lightweight stove for a quick camping microadventure on Saturday night. I did not want to buy one and was considering self heating meals and no coffee in the morning. Until I found inspiration from a post on twitter to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/64726512&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Allen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to have a go at building my own also. I had some mentholated spirit for fuel, I just needed a drink can to make the stove. After a quick trip to the local shop, and with my thirst quenched I had my raw material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1013.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10131.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10132.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10133.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimmed the top and bottom sections. Bottom section is about 30mm high, the top is about 50mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2035.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20351.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creat flues in the side of the can with a knife. Small at the top. Large at the bottom. These form the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20352.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mate both sections&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20353.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ridges are critical. They are small at the top, large at the bottom. They form the fuel generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small hole using a pin just under the top lip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20354.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small amount of fuel, approx 5mm deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20355.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light, wait 10 seconds for fuel to heat in the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10134.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once hot the fuel vaporises in the side ridges, which is the generator the flames only burn on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10135.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about 5 minutes to boil two cups of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1012.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weights very little too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10121.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field test!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2007.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised by the stove, it had no trouble heating my dinner or boiling water in my coffee maker. Just keep it out of the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how these work. Check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beverage-can_stove&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyWay Serengeti Modifications</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, we had some issues with the MyWay Serengeti tent, we loved it. But we need to get the niggles sorted. Luckily Paul was on hand with advice and apologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights in the tent we did discover the first issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top half cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base board, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically locked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in hight between the two plywood base halves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-1841.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to remedy this we installed some locating pegs, which are actually formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-18411.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second issue we found when we removed the tent from the Landy. This was that the lower half of the cover was holding a small amount of water. We had come back from France is some serious rain, I guess that must have made it through the overlap seal in the cover. I guess this would have been exacerbated by the fact we had to pack the tent away wet on the way back. Had we used the tent after the rain this would have had the chance to dry out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remedy this issue we cut some crosses into the lower cover about 20 mm in length, these are just two slices or lines that form a flap arrangement. We located these in three places. The first was central and the others were about 30 cm from each side in each corner on the hinge end of the tent. Hopefully any water collecting will have a route out now. I was originally planning to put five slots into the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess time will tell how these modifications work. We&amp;#039;ll let you know if we have an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready for the Summer</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 17:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-26-may-2013-1303.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the weather getting better and a short camping trip planned for next weekend, we decided this weekend was probably the most sensible time to get the tent on the Landy and the awning set up, ready for opportunities to go camping and the summer trip. The other good thing given that this weekend is a bank holiday is that next weekend should be quieter! The roads and transport systems in the UK just can&amp;#039;t cope when we all decide to move in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a friend giving me a lift getting the roof tent on was a breeze. This year, I have made some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first. The tent is mounted about 6 or 8 inches further forward. This I am hoping will make the car feel a little more stable, while still allowing the rear door to open easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second tweak, was to fit some locating pegs to the back of the tent to remedy the problem I mentioned in this blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that caused the base to sag and create an uncomfortable step. I&amp;#039;ll write about that further &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/&#34;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually we also made a third tweak. That was to create some drain holes in the lower side of the tent cover. We noticed when we removed the tent last year that we had some water sitting in the bottom of the cover. These holes should allow moisture to be dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to another thing I should mention. We have been working on ideas for the summer, we intend this year to again go on a &amp;#039;Big&amp;#039; trip. Note that I say ideas and not planning or plans. Why? Well we are not sure if our aspirations will match our plans. We had to have some house work done this year that cost a small fortune. We&amp;#039;ll reveal more in the near future on the trip though. So stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myway Serengeti 1.6m Roof Tent &amp; Boab Roof Bars</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 15:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-aug-2012-2004.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been trying to find the right sleeping solution for the three of us since, pretty much the first trip we ever went on. The problem we have always had is that we would prefer to be able to wild camp or free camp, but having a family tent made this almost impossible. Not to mention the time it takes to put up and take down a larger tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years that followed we moved onto two small back packing tents one for Cassie and one for us. A two and three man. The plan being in camp sites we use both, in the bush we use one. What we often found though, was that it was hard to find a decent spot for the Landy and a three man tent. If we were walking it would have been fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used the family tent for two years, then the small tents for about two years. We eventually slimmed our arsenal of tents down to the family tent, which will be sold this year, it was only kept for the in-laws on this last trip; the three man backpacking tent we will keep for walking and biking; Cassie&amp;#039;s pop up tent and now the latest addition is a roof tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this trip we took the pop up tent and the new roof tent. The plan being that we would all sleep in the roof tent in the wild, then at campsites we would use both tents to allow us to get a good nights sleep, without being kicked and punched by Cassie all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enquiries about purchasing the roof tent started about 6 or 7 weeks before we left. We were hoping to go and check one out, then get one shortly after. What ended up happening actually, was that we got really busy and were not able to get to a place to see one, it was quite a way. What also happened was that we had to wait for a delivery from Cape Town, South Africa by sea. Luckily we were able to secure one of the items which had already departed in the next batch to be delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-21-jul-2012-1525.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up paying a deposit and hoping the tents would not be delayed in customs. They were supposed to clear by the first week of July. We thought that would be perfect as we could get a couple of nights camping in to make sure everything was ok. Inevitably that did not happen as you would expect, nothing is that simple. We managed to get the tent the Friday before we left. Paul from Myway came down from Doncaster to fit it and train us! Which was a nice touch. Needless to say the tent is superb. One thing led to another and we were not able to get out camping that weekend, so would have to just wait till the actual trip. Fingers crossed everything would be ok! In the end we did manage to find time on the Southdowns to practice putting it up and down including the shower curtain. We also managed to get a few pictures of the process. The pictures below were taken in France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 1 - Position Car&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1716.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 2 - Remove Cover and Insert Ladder&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1718.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 3 - Close the Door and reach for the ladder!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17181.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 4 - Rotate about the hinge and open&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17182.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 5 - Remember something you forgot.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17183.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 6 - Position ladder and fit stays for the flysheet&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1720.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      And Relax!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1719.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spoken at length with Paul, we ended up with a Serengeti 1.6m tent, we had originally wanted to get an Evolution because it was lighter and not canvas and we wanted a 1.8m as it was wider. Paul assured us that the Serengeti was a good choice and that a 1.6 was plenty wide enough for us and Cassie. He was so confident that he assured me if we were not happy we&amp;#039;d sort &#34;something&#34; out! The man proved to know his stuff. The other advantage of the Serengeti was that the canvas would keep the light out in the morning. We found it easy to sleep till nine at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing this so far, I&amp;#039;ve missed a beat, in between paying a deposit and getting the tent I had to find a platform to mount the tent to on top of the Landy. I spent quite a lot of time trying to work out if I wanted a roof rack or roof bars. Roof tents in general are heavy. Myway tents are lighter than most, the 1.6m we were waiting for weighed in at circa 50kg. Most are about 20kg more, with some hitting the 90kg mark for family models. A decent roof rack is about 40 to 50kg, with the Landy and a lot of other cars rated at about 100kg for roof loads, I&amp;#039;d want the lightest mounting system possible. Roof bars are about 5kg approximately each. It seemed an obvious choice considering we did not need a rack at the moment and could do with saving some money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1550.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found various bars around, I wanted something sturdy though. Really because of the off roading factor and mounting the awning. I toyed with getting some boab / mantec bars, I forget what they are called, but dismissed that because I was not convinced they were robust enough for us. Boab also, did some other bars called Boab bars in a 40mm x 40mm or 40mm x 20mm section. I opted for the 40mm square option. I ordered three of these as I needed to mount my awning using u-bolts. This offered a significant weight and cost saving over a rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Construction and Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of construction the tent is made on an aluminium base frame which uses stainless brackets and bolts with aluminium rivets in places, this has a marine ply base attached via captive nuts and bolts. The base frame has a bolted stainless hinge arrangement on either side of the frame, this is the point at which the aluminium hoop tubes attach which support the main tent canvas. The canvas hangs on the hoops, this allows the fly sheet to lay over the top of the whole arrangement. This leaves about a 40 or 50mm gap between the inner tent and flysheet, depending on how the two are adjusted. This gap allows plenty of airflow and is probably a contributing factor to the lack of condensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canvas inner tent is coated with a waterproofing agent, as is the flysheet. With this coating the canvas is free from the normal leaks you get on the first outing. This did not mean we escaped unscathed. We suffered a small amount of leaking on the first night due to the fly sheet being incorrectly adjusted and hanging on the inner canvas, it was a very minor leak and we did not see the issue again after we adjusted and experimented a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tent is delivered with about a 40mm sponge mattress and a fitted green sheet. The foam is covered in nylon so you need the sheet. The mattress cover is arranged such that it hindges in the middle and folds flat when the tent is packed away. We found the mattress fairly soft, so was easy to feel the base underneath, it took a little getting used to. We tended not to notice so much when we slept in sleeping bags in colder climates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to leave some bedding in the tent when it is packed away, but it must be folded flat before the tent is folded. It should be left on the fixed half of the tent. Failure to fold the bedding flat will result in it bunching when the tent is put away and putting extra strain on the hinge, which could lead to failure of the hinge if excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights we did discover one issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design. The cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically linked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in the two plywood base halves. In order to remedy this we will be installing some locating pegs, which will actually be formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the underside of the folding half of the tent a channel is mounted to the base. This allows the addition of a &#34;shower curtain&#34; which is essentially three sides of a walled room with no ground sheet and a small cut out for the ladder, the Landy forms the fourth wall. The ladder is outside the room. We tried this briefly on the Downs but never used this on the trip. The way we have the tent mounted means that it would provide shelter at the back of the Landy into the rear door during inclement weather, with the door open. The additional kit comes in a small bag, so is light enough to carry around. I just never want to have to use it. It takes 2 or 3 minutes to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appart from the minor niggle above, we had a great time with the Serengeti this holiday. We enjoyed the quick set up and pack away times. Wendy and I got quite a good routine established that meant we could put our feet up quicker and be on the road sooner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of the quick set up time means it gives more confidence for camping discreetly as it can be set up at dusk and packed away at dawn when no one is around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of quality, the construction is excellent and modular, so if something needs changing it can be and would be fairly simple, probably without having to go to Myway for spares. The only thing I would pick up Myway (the factory) on is the construction process. We found a lot of swarf in the tent and on the aluminium components. This was because the components are drilled during assembly, rather than drilled cleared and then assembled. It would not be hard to fix this process issue and would save some customer annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short I would not be able to compare against other roof tents as I have not had the chance to look at them, but I can say with confidence that the Myway Serengeti 1.6 meter is an excellent buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bloggin on the Road, Cheapo iPad Camera Connection Kit</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/28/bloggin-on-the-road-cheapo-ipad-camera-connection-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 12:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/28/bloggin-on-the-road-cheapo-ipad-camera-connection-kit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1423.jpg?w=280&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;280&#34; height=&#34;285&#34; alt=&#34;Cheap iPad camera connection kit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So having found Blogsy which is the app that we would like to use, to write our travel blog posts on the road, we realised that we would still need to be able to get images from our camera onto the iPad.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard iPad camera connection kit costs about £25 and is fairly expensive for what it does. Looking around on EBay and Amazon, it is obvious there are a fair few copies around. At about a tenth of the cost delivered. I decided I would take the risk, I purchased one on Amazon. Within a couple of days the connection kit fell through the letter box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impression was that it was well packaged and reasonably well built for something so cheap. It also accepts several different memory cards or a straight camera connection via USB. To change modes there is a switch on the side that allows the user to toggle between with USB or memory card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1312.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing I did after freeing the device from the packaging was stick a memory card in and test it. On connection to the iPad, the photo app loads to a screen that allows the selection of what is imported or deleted from the card. When a selection is imported the user has a choice of keeping or removing imports from the card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once imported the pictures are placed in a folder in the photo app, called last imported. From there you can do as you wish. Older imports are then placed into a dated folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did notice is that on occasion if the reader is left with an empty card slot, but connected to the iPad, a message would show that said device not supported. But I just clicked ok and all was fine. I am not sure if this is normal behaviour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1313.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;168&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not sure how this device will cope on a long term test, but it seems ok and I have no reason to doubt it will survive a decent trip. Time will tell, I&amp;#039;ll report back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1425.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;275&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-14231.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;193&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1422.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys Locked in - The Frostfire Mooncode 1555 Portable Key Storage</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/24/keys-locked-in-the-frostfire-mooncode-1555-portable-key-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 20:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/24/keys-locked-in-the-frostfire-mooncode-1555-portable-key-storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-20-may-2012-0855.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;285&#34; alt=&#34;Frostfire Mooncode 1555&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you have read about our trip last year, you will know that we locked the keys in the Landy in Croatia. We normally have at least a door key on us each, in order to try and prevent this situation. However it was quite late in the holiday and the inevitable happened. Both doors slam, I see the keys swinging in the ignition. I can also see Wendy&amp;#039;s bag on the passenger floor. Just to confirm, I ask where her keys are. My suspicion is confirmed!...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been saying every year we must do something about this. But what do you do? Leaving a key stashed is tricky and potentially easy to find, added to that most solutions are magnetic, which is useless on a landy. I wanted something of a more robust and secure nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing the net I came across the Mooncode key safe, which is an oversized padlock shaped device with a combination code to open. The body has space sufficient to allow stashing of a key and bank card. The padlock mechanism would allow it to be locked to the landy. The device looked ideal. I ordered one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way I will say now, this will only be used while we are away. I have no intention of leaving it fitted or broadcasting where it is fitted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-24-may-2011-1227.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; alt=&#34;Closed Mooncode Key Safe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On arrival I was keen to check out the new toy, first impression was that it is fairly robust and heavy device, the padlock clasp is covered in transparent rubber to help prevent it rattling, the rear of the body is covered in fairly heavy duty rubber foam, both of these also help protect car paint work. In my case it will help prevent the rattling in the eventual stowage location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to release the clasp of the padlock you have to know the code, this is a good feature. The release mechanism is internal to Moodcode&amp;#039;s body. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-24-may-2011-12271.jpg?w=441&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;441&#34; height=&#34;251&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that would be an improvement, is if the Moodcode was waterproof. The body will prevent splashes and light rain entering the chamber that contains the keys etc, by the shape of the closing edges, the inside and outside edges overlap but will not prevent water ingress. I did wonder if I could seal it with some stick rubber strip, I&amp;#039;ll have a play sometime on that one. Obviously for the use of overlanders and 4wd&amp;#039;s it would be much better If waterproof. If the manufacturers considered this they would also need to consider the code wheels and mechanism as I am sure this would not take long to suffer from dust ingress and seize up. I think to help it survive the latter it will have the code wheels taped up in situ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not decide where it will go yet. We&amp;#039;ll let you know how it survives the holiday this year. Have any of you got a decent solution to locking your keys in the car?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re taking Blogsy on a road trip.</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/20/were-taking-blogsy-on-a-road-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 09:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/20/were-taking-blogsy-on-a-road-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-19-apr-2012-1947.jpg?w=164&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; alt=&#34;Blogsy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have traditionally kept a Moleskin notebook with us when we are on the road, the current one is on its third trip. I would hate for it to go missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the back we record all the cool things like mileages, fuel costs and locations we fill up at. This enables us to keep a log of our fuel consumption. Potentially a sign of an impending problem. We also record accommodation, ferry and toll costs. I often think it would be good if there was more cost information available for overlanders. My intention is to look at the general cost per unit of distance. I believe an accurate assumption can be made for longer trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the front we use it as a diary or journal we record how the day went, what we did, what was said, funny moments and other such things. The journal itself is a good read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Traditionally when we get home we have every intention of putting our journal story on the web, this often happens many months later. The moment has passed and the story element is lost. Reading the past storys can be a slog. This is for a few reasons; the delay in transferring the story to the site, the size of the task. We are aware of these issues and hate that the moment can be lost in the writing, as the journeys to us are so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;To try and improve on these issues we are still going to use our journal, but have decided we will post the story in the style of a blog rather than a webpage. To do this we will use the iPad to post the blog as we go. We often camp and it is at these moments we have time, we are relaxed and in the mood to write these entries. The iPad is the ideal tool for this. The important part of this is we will be immersed in the trip while we are writing, so still living the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;To enable us to do this we are going to use a few tools, firstly we will be using Blogsy which is a blogging app for the iPad, I suggest you check it out by the way, it is the best of what I have tried. For some reason this app makes you want to post, it has a great feel and brings together everything you need in a great interface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We will also be using iPhoto to manage, edit and upload photos. To do this we will be getting a camera connection kit for the iPad shortly. I&amp;#039;ll update you on this soon on this. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boab Braai</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/25/boab-braai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 09:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/25/boab-braai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have been going thru cheap portable braai&amp;#039;s (aka bbq&amp;#039;s) like cheap toilet paper. They are generally made of very thin pressed sheet steel and don&amp;#039;t last. The cost of these and the disposibles we occasionally resort to has begun to add up. So we have resorted to buying a decent portable... The Boab Braai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1100423.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-232&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We purchased the braai from Boab.biz in 2010, they import stuff from South Africa and have a nice expanding product range. The first impression you get when it turns up is the sheer weight of the thing. This is not a Braai you walk far with. We live about 600 meters from the beach and it is hard work carrying it down just that far! It is perfect in the back of the Landy thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As you will no doubt know this braai is fairly well travelled, it has been used in over 12 countries with us and is now about to be used on the third summer trek. It is now obviously fairly dirty, but a good clean now and again brings it back to life. The surprising thing is how well the paint work has held out. We have actually been fairly rubbish at cleaning it etc, left it in the rain and there is little sign of corrosion. This is obviously a desirable feature in a braai. I keep thinking I will need to touch the paint up, but have so far put it off as it is no where near bad yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1100424.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-231&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Boab Braai - Hard at work on the South Downs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of the nice things about the Boab Braai, is the grill is of a decent size. Meaning you can easily cook for about 5 people depending on what you are cooking. The grill is also a heavy duty mesh and frame so does not buckle or get damaged with repeated cleaning or time. You will also fail to loose sausages through the grill due to the grill having a square pattern!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of the nice features of the Boab Braai is that the lid also has legs and becomes a handy cooking table for beer and utensils. One feature of the lid we have not tried is the griddle. Perhaps soon. Thou. The braai also comes with a handy pot holding arm, we use this for utensils, as we generally use out petrol Coleman stove for pots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The only downside with the Braai, is that due to the dimensions and design it can be tricky to get started if you are complacent in setting up the coals. This is because there is no vents for air to get in at the base of the fire. Since I purchased the Boab Braai they have added a log burner base to the accessories which would adress this. In reality if you are an experience fire starter (twisted fire started, sorry...) this will not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The great thing about the Boab Braai is that the grade of material allows for a decnt camp fire after dinner. Just don&amp;#039;t get done by a forest ranger like we did, who promptly doused the Boab Braai with water!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Verdict: Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Boab Braai Datasheet PDF&#34; href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/boab-ultimate-braai-factsheet.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the data sheet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Leave a comment let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/boab-braai-complete-large.jpg?w=512&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-230&#34; width=&#34;410&#34; height=&#34;819&#34; alt=&#34;Boab Braai Complete&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weaco CF-18 Portable 12 Volt Fridge</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/21/weaco-cf-18-portable-12-volt-fridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 19:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/21/weaco-cf-18-portable-12-volt-fridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/waeco-cf-18.jpg&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-212 alignleft&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;185&#34; alt=&#34;Waeco CF-18&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After two years of road trips into Europe and the prospect of more lengthy and exotic trips in the future, the struggle with not having enough cold beer got too much. We decided to look at our options for a portable car fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the land of 12 volt fridges all is not equal. The cheap ones you generally see in places like Halfords (local automotive accessory store) tend to work by making use of the Peltier Junction effect. Basically it is an electrical junction. You stick the fridge on one side of the junction and a heat sink and fan on the other. Electrically charge the junction blow the heat of the top and the other side gets cold. Simples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The downfall of these fridges is that they are generally quite power intensive and have a limited cooling differential from ambient. This is not ideal in warmer European countries, but may well be sufficient in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The better option is to get a fridge such as the Waeco CF-18, it has a Danfoss compressor, similar to that which is used in a standard fridge or air conditioner. The whole unit is fairly efficient and works on a refrigerant circuit the same as your fridge at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We got this fridge for Summer 2009, on the advice of a friend, who tends to buy decent stuff. We have now used it for three years in countries from Portugal to Montenegro. It is superb and will run for up to three days on our split charging system, depending on the temperature in the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/waeco-cf-18-diamentions.jpg?w=244&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-213 alignright&#34; width=&#34;244&#34; height=&#34;148&#34; alt=&#34;Waeco Dimensions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One word of advice. This fridge has worked well for us. It would be nice to have a larger one thou, so buy bigger if you can afford to and can store it between trips. This fridge is big enough for two two litre bottles some small items of meat, yoghurt and butter and milk. Oh and the odd chocolate bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Secondly watch out for the insulation level. If the manufacturer offers an insulating sleeve or blanket buy it. It will help in the hottest environments. Remember you car parked in the sun with windows closed could easily reach over 45 degrees Celsius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120323-00107.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-240 alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Insulating Cover&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cover for the CF-18 seems to be of a reasonable quality, a decent fit , with lashing eyes and additional pockets. It will cost about an extra £35 delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom is removable, by using the zipper provided. The foil lining should make for easy cleaning. The only downside is the black top material, a light grey would have been better. Having said that thou the material is certainly tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120323-00120.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-239 alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Insulating Cover Removable Bottom&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120323-001141.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-242&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Insulating Cover Vent&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Verdict: If you are after a smaller Fridge. We would definitely recommend this fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Others to consider are National Luna and Engel. For an in depth review of bigger 12 volt fridges check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.expeditionportal.com/resources/equipment-review-and-testing/556-overland-journal-portable-12v-fridge-review.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post on Expedition Portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What fridge do you use on Overland journeys? Leave a comment and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>