<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Land Rover on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/land-rover/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Land Rover on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/land-rover/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 19 - Bunec to Beach Cove via Butrint</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 07:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140027.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a fairly ok nights sleep and woke early. We decided to avoid the breakfast spoken of last night as dinner was a little &#39;dodgy&#39;, for want of a better word. We opted for just a coffee instead. Outside our room we bumped into a lovely lady sitting with her grandson. She asked us where we were from and we told her, &#34;England, Brighton&#34;. She said she knew it and lived in Lewisham. She was on holiday with her family and investigating a business opportunity in Albania. I must add, she was Albanian. We chatted for a bit longer and then bid her farewell, we were off for that coffee.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being reinforced with a coffee, we headed out towards Butrint, we wanted to visit the Roman ruins there. After a long and hot drive, we arrived at the entrance car park to the ruins. Immediately we were accosted by a young urchin girl and her male companion. They demanded that we buy bracelets from them. Dan was in the firing line of their deluge and so we ended up buying a bracelet from the girl and one from the boy. By this time I had another little urchin at my window. She begged that I bought a bracelet from her too, I had to say no. The first young girl then came round to my window and asked if she could have my banana that I had sitting in the front. I laughed and had to admire her audacity. I gave her the banana. She immediately peeled it and ate it as she walked away, pleased at herself for getting another tourist in her trap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were now dripping and feeling a little hard done by, having been accosted by the urchins. We went for a cold drink at the restaurant before entering the sight. At the entrance to the ruins the prices were 700 LEK per foreign visitor, 500 LEK per foreign visitor in a group, 300 LEK for an Albanian visitor and 400 LEK for a child. So it was an entrance fee of 1,400 LEK and so we followed the cruise ship visitors that had just descended on the place by bus load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140030.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked around the remains. The signs at the entrance had said no smoking, walk on the path and beware the insects and snakes. The last bit made us hopeful we&#39;d see something other than roman ruins. We waited at the first part, an amphitheatre, for the hoards to disappear. Here Cassie discovered a turtle in the water around the ruins. From here we wondered around, skirting the crowds. It was extremely hot, and we were all dripping in sweat by the end. Afterwrds Dan and Cassie got themselves and ice cream and I got a can of cold Coca Cola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140071.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to head off and find a camp on the beach somewhere. Yesterday Dan had noticed that the radius arm bushes needed changing, especially if we wanted to tackle a few more gravel tracks during the holiday. We had seen plenty of &#39;Autoservis&#39; places along the road and so we went in search of one that could fit us in. We tried a few and they all pointed us to someone else as they were far to busy. Eventually on the way out of Butrint, we stopped at a small garage we had noticed on our way in. He was now quiet and Dan asked if he could do the work, it would only take 1 hour. The guy agreed. He spoke good english and so Dan changed into some shorts and negotiated the car above a pit. Cassie and I sat in the car trying not to expire, while Dan helped the guy change the bushes. All done for 2000 LEK. Luckily Dan had the spares in the car … Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were off now in search of a beach to stay on. They all looked packed and we could not find a turning to some. So, we decided to stop for lunch somewhere. We came across a little village and went to a restaurant. Here the owner spoke good english and we ordered lamb with a greek salad. The owner chafed to us about working on cruise ships and seeing the world, but how now he water to settle in Albania. We asked him about the ferries from Vlorë to Brindisi. He recommended going from Igoumenista instead and offered to let us use the internet to check fares.We thanked him and Dan did just that. The prices and info was not helpful as the ferry from Vlorë did not show up in the searches. We thanked the owner and hit the road once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0264.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we stopped at a little cove we had spotted on the way past yesterday. The water edge was lined with mobile homes, which we only assumed were stopping for the night. As we approached and stopped, a funny Albanian man came up to us and asked where we were from. We told him England and asked if it was ok to stay. He said sure no problem, just park. Dan asked if he wanted money, he said that wasn&#39;t necessary, we were his friends … we concluded he was a little strange and parked up anyway, changed into our kozzies, and went for a dip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130968.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0270.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0279.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie immediately spotted sea urchins in the water, so we tried to avoid these. Later on we spoke to a lady who had stood n one and was trying to get the poison out her toe. Cassie got the snorkel and mask out and did a little look see in the water. She stayed in for ages! All of a sudden there was a ruckus, some locals nearby had caught an octopus. They started throwing it onto the rocks whilst screaming and shouting. I found this really upsetting. Why not just kill it humanely and hopefully not as sport, but to take it back and eat it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we had been sitting on the beach, the wind had been building. We decided to set the tent up and head for the restaurant for dinner across the road from the bay. As we had eaten a big lunch, we decided to go for a snack type dinner … this didn&#39;t really happen. Dan ordered calamari and I the seafood spaghetti, Cas shared both. The wind was now quite strong. We wondered back to the tent and got ready for bed. Whilst we lay in the tent, we were whipped and bashed. Dan and I worried about it not being safe in the tent with the wind at this strength, so we gathered up our sleeping stuff, closed up the tent and bundled into the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a night of horror! I personally got NO sleep … Dan says he managed a wink or two and I think Cassie was the luckiest out of us all. She probably managed an hour or so. To say we woke early would be an understatement. We were up before 6, teeth brushed and outta there. We were the walking dead but we still headed for Vlorë to see how much it would be to catch the ferry to Brindisi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18 - Kepi i Kalas to Bunec via our Secret beach</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 07:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0254.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Being in a hotel last night meant getting away quickly was easy. We had a local style breakfast of feta, tomato, cucumber and bread. Washed down with a few coffees.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Our plan was to check out a beach I had found on Google earth that looked almost isolated due to the track you had to use to get to it. Due to the GPS problems I had circled it on the map. This meant it was another day heading to a circle. The drive to the beach took about an hour or so. We first had to negotiate some spectacular steep roads with tight hairpins over the surrounding mountains. The roads had various bits missing and loads of fallen rocks which claimed a few victims to punctures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130959.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The turning to the beach was immediately of the bottom of the steep decent. There had been a few attempts to grade it, but the track was pretty bad. On the was down we got held up by a truck rescuing an Italian mobile home who had been over ambitious. Both looked frustrated. The tow rope was in taters. The owner said something to me as we squeezed by. I promised to return with my tow strap and shackles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;By the time I had stopped 50 meters on and returned they appeared to on there way so I returned and we continued to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we got to the bottom we were delighted, we found an almost empty beach except for a couple of 4x4&#39;s and 2 or 3 like minded over landing campers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The beach was made up by sandy white pebbles. The top of the beach had a sand track which was easy to traverse. We headed most of the way along the track then turned down to the sea. Parking 10 meters from the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0253.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Here we swam in crystal clear water and lounged around for the morning. Cassie loved it. Spending most of the time checking out the fishies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on we decided to leave, I was a little apprehensive, as I had noted the sand and shingle made for horribly difficult driving. I had deflated the tyres a little and even in low diff lock, I struggled. I had to repeatedly reverse to get any momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My first attempt to get up the beach failed, I thought I had enough speed but could not get into low third without grinding to a halt and sinking. I stopped and let some more air out of the tyres and reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Foot to the floor I headed slightly back down towards the sea and managed to get some speed and into third. This allowed me to managed the engine speed and get enough velocity to get over the sand up to the slightly better surface to get off the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once I was back on the track at the top, I was hot! So we headed to a small makeshift bar a local had erected in the rock walls of the mountain that encapsulated the beach. I had a fanta and a beer to chill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had received we headed south to find a place to stay. We had again opted out of camping as we had no supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130983.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We eventually after some chaos ended up at a tiny restaurant at Bunec beach, which had rooms. The owning family lived in a tent. They were very nice and cooked us a traditional pasta dish and we drank loads of beer and swam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130990.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The rooms in these places are basic but functional and clean. We paid 30 euro with breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17 - Koplic to Kepi i Kalas via the Karavasta Lagoon.</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 18:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130905.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the heat we did quite well this morning and managed to get packed up and on the road by 0945, after we had a slow coffee and showers all round. Our original plan was to head up to Thethi, which is said to be beautiful, but have a difficult road, especially after rain. Given that the last two days there had been storms in the area, we decided we would not attempt that, but perhaps try on the return route. Instead today we would head for the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gus and Helen who we met at the campsite had lent us a map which they had been given, by another traveller in Albania on a bike. Many of the circles were on the places we had read about, some were alien to us. Anyhow I copied the circles to our map. Todays plan was based on circles. We would head to the circle at Karavasta Lagoon. We had no idea what was there so Wendy read up in the guide book on the way between navigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary was that it is a wet land with many birds and lots of wild life. At night it is apparently a mosquito hell hole. Cool, sounds like an ideal place to visit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130908.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we left we found the roads in the area where we stayed all seemed ok, well sign posted and smooth. Petrol stations everywhere. It was not long before we were in chaos though, Sckoder was manic and it was every man for himself. The roads had occasional road markings, round abouts and traffic signals. Pedestrian crossings never mind those. We encountered various types of traffic, bikes, people, horse and cart, three wheel trucks and even motor bikes which had a tray arrangement welded to the from that formed a kind of three wheel truck thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic involved people and cyclists moving the wrong way and or on the wrong side of the road. Putting themselves in danger. The drivers used their horn to say either hello, we are over taking or we are coming through regardless. Undertaking was the norm. This was probably because the fast lane was used to avoid the chaos at the side of the road with the triple parked vehicles and other oddities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At roundabouts most people don&#39;t bother indicating, if they do it means nothing because they forget to change it as the filter off with the opposite indication. The roundabouts work a bit like a drain hole. In that no one stops, they just continue being sucked into the vortex and some break free when they need to leave. Occasionally you&#39;ll get some one a little bit more crazy who will just fly across the round about breaking the vortex. You&#39;ll have warning if you are lucky by way of continuous multiple beeping of the horn. Beep Beep beep beep beep beep beep beep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually made it out of Sckoder, shocked but unharmed! It was exciting. The only negative for me was the begging on the out skirts at the traffic lights which meant we locked the doors and put the windows up. Sorry. I felt really bad about that, but did not want to encourage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the main road overtaking is an art, you&#39;ll often be confronted by a speeding car in your lane flashing lights at you. They are overtaking. They expect you to assist be moving out of the way. Several occasions having held my ground, I took evasive action, either by braking, making use of the dirt hard shoulder or swerving. These guys are good at Chicken. I think I saved us a few times from accidents by braking to allow people to hop from behind and avoid the front of busses by feet, not meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We endured this for several hours, even trying the motor way, which although wider had limited road markings and was just a bigger play ground.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0156.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually arrived at Karavasta. Here we headed along dirt tracks, paid a toll and continued to the beach, we were able to drive all the way up the beach until we found a quiet spot. You can&#39;t do that in many places. Here we relaxed for an hour or so had a swim and lunch. Previously we had tried about 4 km up the beach, but being near a river outlet there was a lot of plan debris on the beach making it look undesirable amongst all the rubbish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having refreshed ourselves and having convinced ourselves it was not an ideal place to camp, we headed back out on the dirt road which we entered, this then lead us to take a turning to follow one of the waterways of the lagoon. We came across some locals fishing and checked with them we were headed in the right direction. They basically as usual said keep going!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0182.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were not headed basically down a raised section of the lagoon that had a track on it. The track continued for about 5 km, it was wet but ok. I was obviously concerned as it may have got very boggy. It was just wide enough for a car.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0190.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we saw loads of small birds, which appeared not to have the ability to fly, but to merely run around scatter brained. There were also lots of herons. The star of the afternoon was a tortoise we came across just wandering the track. We jumped out to get photos quickly, before it disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0198.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time we got out of there it was getting late, so we headed just south of Vlora to hunt down a room to stay in. We found a nice hotel perched on a cliff top with a private beach for 35 Euro a night with breakfast. We had a swim, then freshened up for the evening opting to eat at the hotel and drink a few beers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 - Koplic, Lake Shkrodër</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to stay two nights at Lake Shkodër. Today we woke slowly, having been woken by Cassie in the middle of the night again. After we finally dragged her sleeping items into the tent, thunder rolled in. There had been a little rain too, but not a significant amount. Needless to say, it was a little bit of a restless night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was warming up already by mid morning, and I had decided that the sheets, towels and pillow cases needed to be washed. We also needed to get some food. We asked the owner of the campsite if here was a shop close by and he said yes, just walk up to the main road, over the bridge and there is a shop there. So we handed over our washing, as he had a machine, and set off for the shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130897.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked we were shocked by the rubbish we saw on the side of the road and dumped in ditches, We passed two young boys by the overpass burning their rubbish. It was a reminder that Albania still had ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were perspiring by the time we got to the shop and had to stop for a cold drink at one of the bars. Afterwards we went to the shop and bought essentials .. water, beer, biscuits and other food items. Now for the walk back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the campsite, Cassie made friends with a young girl from a German family staying a few pitches down. She played all afternoon with Lea and her brother Nic. It was nice for her to have company, and Lea wanted to practice her English as she had recently started learning it at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day Thunder had been rumbling in the background but despite this, it had been warm and sunny.. with a slight cloudy haze. But by afternoon, the lightening started making an appearance and we decided to pack up Cassie&#39;s tent and head for the restaurant/bar. And a good thing we did, as the heavens opened with an almighty bang and gush of wind and it did not let up for hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had grabbed a table inside and here we stayed for the most of the evening. Eventually to be joined by Frank and Anjita, Cassie&#39;s new found friends&#39; parents. The evening was great. We swopped travelling stories, places to visit and even swopped blog addresses. It&#39;s always nice to make friends along the way, so thanks Fank and Anjita for a great evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a second Land Rover at the camp, owned by a Scottish couple that were travelling. We had spoken to them the day before about their set up and swopped maps for tips on places to travel. Anyway, Gus and Helen also ended up at the bar/restaurant and as our table was already full, they sat with a trio of Austrian guys next door to us. As the evening progressed, they ended up joining our table too. We all had a wonderful time drinking wine and beer and swopping stories. Thanks Gus and Helen for your tips and your extending fork!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0134.jpeg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11 - Jajce to Sarajevo</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 19:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130707.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We packed up fairly sharpish this morning the plan was to have coffee and breakfast in Jajce, then explore. We got in to town easily from the campsite and managed to find parking. Dan accidentally purchased a day of parking for 5 KM (about 2.5 euro). Jajce is a candidate for a Unesco site, so we expect to find something fairly special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked into what we thought was the Old Town, the traffic was immense. The heat was already building and we decided to stop and have a coffee and breakfast before we headed out to explore. This being easier said than done. All the cafés were a little strange, so we opted for the most full…going with the thought process that if it&#39;s full, it must be ok. We decided to order a cappuccino instead of a coffee…we will not do this again. We promptly drank up and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130714.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wondering around and down a slippery, pebble polished set of stairs (from all the wear), we had no idea where we were going. We couldn&#39;t find the Old Town or the waterfalls mentioned to fall from Jajce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we still had not eaten, our stomachs won and we headed for the Pekara (bakery) we had seen on our way in to get some breakfast, or now, brunch. Cassie asked if we could go to the underground church she had seen a sign for, so we headed for that. Low and Behold! We were in the the Old Town. We should have simply headed that way to begin with. We paid 6KM for all of us to go down into the catacombs. They weren&#39;t extensive, but still a lot cooler than outside as the heat was blaring and interesting. A shame that on many of the alls there was engraved graffiti as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p11307261.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130727.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we wondered up to the top of the Old Town walls, we had a look around and decided to start our journey to Sarajevo. The drive was a hot one. As we entered the city, we found it hard to navigate with our large scale map and a guide book city centre map. We eventually managed to get onto a road that was shown on the map in our Bradt guide book. From here we were able to navigate ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130747.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking … Oh parking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was none!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We navigated the one way system roughly 4 times before we decided to head on out of the city and find a hotel on the outskirts, with parking, and catch a taxi into the centre. Just on the fringe of the one way system there was a petrol station and a tiny hotel next door. It had parking! Dan pulled in and went to ask if they had a room for the night and the cost. BINGO! We were in. We decided to have a shower, a beer and then go out and explore Sarajevo and find some dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we wondered in, Dan had seen an Apple store at the Sarajevo School of Arts, so we decided to head there and see if they had some noise cancelling headphones for Dan and Cassie to use. Cassie wanted to cross the bridge on the entrance to the centre as it was &#34;curly&#34;. We then decided to get a city map so we could find the Turkish quarter (Baščaršija) where the guide book said it was the best place to get a feel for Sarajevo. After wondering a bit and finding the quarter, we explored the stalls and did some souvinir shopping. Cassie and I bought some clothing from a shop that sold only hand made Bosnian clothes. Cassie got a shawl/poncho and Wendy got a lovely top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130751.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went in search of a place that sold ćevapi, as we had seen everyone sitting outside on the street restaurants eating ćevapi. Ćevapi is a meat sausage made from lamb or beef, or a mix, in a pita type bread served with sour cream/yoghurt and onions. It was lovely! The restaurants were full and after wondering around a bit we found one where the waiter put us on a table with another lady. She happened to be a student from Holland doing her Thesis in Bosnia on Genoside and Reconciliation. She was very good company and a lovely dinner partner to chat to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130767.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we looked for a place to have a beer, but being in the muslim part of the town, beer was a tad hard to find being served. We decided to just head back to the hotel and have a beer there. An opportunity to update this blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130750.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10 - Bihac to Jajce</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/05/day-10-bihac-to-jajce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 16:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/05/day-10-bihac-to-jajce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130633.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a short day today, we left the campsite at a leisurely pace and drove around 150km to Jajce. It looked to be a fairly simple drive following the road numbered 5 for Sarajevo. Jajce was before Sarajevo but signs did not appear until about 70km from Bihac.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130623.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this thing about having to have my headlights on in the summer, I know it is the law in a lot of countries. But I just don&#39;t like it. I would understand in the winter, but in the summer it does nothing but waste fuel! Anyhow this again got me pulled over by the Police (it also happened in Serbia twice and once in Montenegro), I did not see them in time to put the lights on, a grumpy cop pulled me over in a Serbian part of the country as we passed through. I apologised pretending to be forgetful, he asked me to get out and demanded documents, we had everything so he did not seem too fussed. He asked where we were going, I pointed at Jajce on the map. He sent us on the way. We joked that had it not been in the Serbian part the cops would not have cared. We did pass lots of Police prior to the incident and got away with it. Oh well. It was fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway we got to Jajce in time for lunch by the lake, followed by a swim and a beer in the local lake side restaurant, Cassie spent time looking at the fish and getting Damsel flies to land on her hand. The lake was nice and had interesting mills, but was not the most pleasant place to swim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later we went looking for the &#34;Autocamp&#34; we had passed, it was simple, not next to the lake and once we were in, fairly pleasant. We spent the afternoon catching up on stuff. Reading on the grass and checking maps etc. I also checked out routes to Lukomir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, Jajce is a candidate for a UNESCO site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished the evening by having dinner and several locals beers. We also booked into a Sarajevo Hotel online to allow us to explore tomorrow. Tomorrow we planned to have a look around Jajce and head for Sarajevo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8 - Bovec to Duga Resa</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/03/day-8-bovec-to-duga-resa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 13:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/03/day-8-bovec-to-duga-resa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided that today we needed to get cracking and head south. I would have loved to have stayed longer in Bovec, but the campsite was fully booked over the weekend, so we had to either find another site, or move on.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130475.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we spent sometime trying to work out where to head, without driving too far, whilst fitting in with our rough plan. We eventually decided to head for the wine road south-west of Zagreb in northern Croatia. This is a road that runs between Samobor and Jastrebarsko and is famed for its wine. We found the area and the road specifically, with no problems. The route was beautiful and the drive was ideal in the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if I have mentioned previously, but the Garmin Montana GPS is dead (my second one). It does not boot beyond the maps loading at start up, so we are navigating by one of the 1:200k maps we have. Not a problem. Luckily I love maps so have more than enough to compensate. Anyhow, we stopped to get our bearings for a minute, I killed the Landy while Wendy sorted herself out so I could have pee. Jumped back in and the engine did not turn over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I thought I had failed to activate the immobiliser correctly, so did it again. Same outcome. By the third time I could not hear the starter motor solenoid pull in. Ok, I would need a multimeter. Once I grabbed that, I popped off the fuse cover the starter relay was pulling in there was 12 volts on the contact to the solenoid. Which leaves a couple of items as likely causes. Either wiring or connection or starter motor. Engine was too hot and the afternoon was too hot to get close to check either. Not wanting to hang around and given that no one had passed us in 15 minutes, I decided to bump start the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were facing up hill and against the bushes… Luckily I managed to do it in about 2 meters in reverse. We carried on along the route for a while. About 20 minutes on and Cassie needed to wee now, so I stopped nose up a bank. Flicked the ignition and the starter flicked over, good sign… Killed the engine and it restarted, excellent. I suspect connections. I had a similar issue with a connection which was installed by a previous garage removing the stock alarm system. Which I fixed. This had prevented the fuel cut out solenoid activating about 18 months ago. I suspect the same issue here I hope. I&#39;ll replace the crimp when we stop for a couple of days somewhere and I am bored. At the moment the problem has not reoccurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, by this stage we were looking for one of the recommended Vineyards in the Bradt guide, which also had rooms. We found it. But no one was to be found. We waited for a few minutes before deciding to find the second recommendation. This was about another 30 minutes on. We had a different outcome with this, we found signs to the place and followed them diligently up gravel tracks, but the place was nowhere to be seen. We re-read the guide description. We asked locals who pointed up in the right direction. We found a place but it appeared to be another vineyard, by this time we had done the gravel track three or four times. Wendy and Cassie went to investigate, they followed the loud music, I saw a person from outside, they knocked, entered and found no one. Returning minutes later like the place was empty but having a ghost rave. We gave up and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130483.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well what do we do now? On the map a campsite was shown slightly south of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karlovac&#34;&gt;Karlovac&lt;/a&gt;. They make the famous beer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karlovačko&#34;&gt;Karlovačko&lt;/a&gt;. We eventually found a cool campsite south of Karlovac in Duga Resa. They were busy, but had an excellent river to swim in and a reasonable restaurant, which suited us, given, we were by this time absolutely knackered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically we were surrounded by a very big group of Irish travellers headed for Bosnia, they had large caravans. Fairly modern. Towed by Transit vans. The group as a whole were making a lot of noise. The kids were climbing all over the bathrooms. We were worried we would be associated with them, so stayed well clear despite out close proximity. They looked dodgy, why would you travel in such a large group. I am guessing 30 in total?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost gone</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/26/almost-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 18:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/26/almost-gone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130726-190547.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well we are at this time just over 40 minutes late on our booked departure time, the board is saying we&#39;ll depart an hour and six minutes late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily apart from not having a place to stay yet when we get to France, we have nowhere important to be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seen a nicely refurbished Mercedes truck, which has been converted for overland travel, it is from Switerland. I remember seeing those things as a kid in the desert with water tanks on the back tackling dunes. Nice ride, wish I got a pic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair done</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 17:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130724-184907.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The landy is now back to normal the whole repair is done, seats are in soundproofing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have the fun of packing for the trip. Sorry I did not take a picture of the finished article! But the picture above shows the first of three seats fitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must dash need to iron my pants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upriser/Upstand in</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 16:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not quite as far as I would have liked today. Missed the nut and bolt store. They close at 1400 on a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to get the Upstand and floor fitted and the two central seat brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130720-173701.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow when my drill is charged again, I&#39;ll get ready for the last two seat brackets, when I get the bolts on Monday they&#39;ll be fitted. I should also be able to refit the sound proofing tomorrow, that is the rubber chequer plate stuff from write off road. As sold to the MOD. I had not finished fitting it due to this repair, needing to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am going for a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There Upstand Assembly</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0109.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much of an update tonight, with the ongoing repair apart from to show some pictures of the panel now it has been fully tweaked and drilled to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished of the drilling tonight and deburred everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final job for the night was to give another coat of etch primer and paint the seat brackets and new panels with stone chip paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are now drying, so tomorrow I&#39;ll start fitting it for real. The only thing I need to do is drill the seat brackets in location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful with a push, I should have it done tomorrow or Sunday at the latest. Not wishing to tempt fate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0111.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Upstand/Upriser Re-Assembly</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0091.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now at the stage of re-assembly. It has been a slow road even to strip the back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mid-crossmember is galvanised and from YRM metal solutions. One of the nice features of the new one, is that the top brackets are loose rather than welded on this makes it easier to get the cross member under the fuel pipes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have had with the crossmember is that the holes, for mounting to the chassis rails where about 3mm out across the vehicle. I am not entirely sure why, but I eventually managed to get the bolts in. I suspect it may have been partially due to the camber of the road. I&#39;ve used stainless bolts so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0095.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note on the cross member is that the cut out for the fuel hoses on my vehicle is in the wrong location. This probably varies from vehicle to vehicle. One was YRM could improve this is to have a wider cut out. I have added additional protection and will tywrap the hoses out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the crossmember was in it was time to start fitting the upstand/upriser. The new item is a different size to the old one. In a good way. The lips are about another 10mm deep. This means that around the top a certain amount of fitting is required, this is around the spars under the floor and the doubler between the separate sections of floor near the doors. I only cut out these areas, I like the idea of the extra depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new item seemed longer also, I did not have to cut it down. The reason is that the old panel was tapered making the top shorter than the bottom edge. I spaced it evenly each side and it seems ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0102.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fitting done, I have now dry fitted it, drilled the holes for the top rivets and will tomorrow drill the sides pieces and seat brackets. At the moment the rivets are all loose. I will strip it out and paint it once I have dry assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The floor is in with a couple of screws at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair continues</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130717-141934.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll need to forgive the posts at the moment, they are short and sweet. This is because I am under pressure and because I am feeling guilty about not posting, all I would like to on what has happened and what I want to happen. I am doing them on the run with the Wordpress app.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow an update on the floor repair of the landy. The second row floor is out. This was a bit of hassle as all the screws were seized. I have no power at the vehicle so a grinder was not an option. The up stand/ upriser is out and the mid cross member is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also cleaned up around the mid cross member mountings and put stone chip paint on it to give it some protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0086.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albania Off Road Guide</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/albania-off-road-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/albania-off-road-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130717-140602.jpg&#34;&gt;
I have been in touch by chance via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/&#34;&gt;Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; with a chap called Matthew over the last few months. He is planning on travelling to Albania at a similar time to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway via Matthew I have found this book which I thought I would recommend, about routes in Albania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I like the book is that it not only takes off road, but also cover sites to see on route. One nice feature of the book is that the Author attempts to give you an idea of difficulty and what vehicles the route was covered in.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition there is a decent section on cuisine and the differences between regions and a small section on language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bebaweb.cz/albania-offroad-guide.php&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It was about 19 euro delivered to the UK and took a couple of days to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the back of the book so you can see it and the isbn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130717-140758.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>