<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Land Rover on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/tags/land-rover/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Land Rover on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/africanuhambo.github.io/tags/land-rover/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Upriser/Upstand in</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 16:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not quite as far as I would have liked today. Missed the nut and bolt store. They close at 1400 on a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to get the Upstand and floor fitted and the two central seat brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130720-173701.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow when my drill is charged again, I&#39;ll get ready for the last two seat brackets, when I get the bolts on Monday they&#39;ll be fitted. I should also be able to refit the sound proofing tomorrow, that is the rubber chequer plate stuff from write off road. As sold to the MOD. I had not finished fitting it due to this repair, needing to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am going for a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There Upstand Assembly</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0109.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much of an update tonight, with the ongoing repair apart from to show some pictures of the panel now it has been fully tweaked and drilled to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished of the drilling tonight and deburred everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final job for the night was to give another coat of etch primer and paint the seat brackets and new panels with stone chip paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are now drying, so tomorrow I&#39;ll start fitting it for real. The only thing I need to do is drill the seat brackets in location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful with a push, I should have it done tomorrow or Sunday at the latest. Not wishing to tempt fate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0111.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Upstand/Upriser Re-Assembly</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0091.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now at the stage of re-assembly. It has been a slow road even to strip the back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mid-crossmember is galvanised and from YRM metal solutions. One of the nice features of the new one, is that the top brackets are loose rather than welded on this makes it easier to get the cross member under the fuel pipes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have had with the crossmember is that the holes, for mounting to the chassis rails where about 3mm out across the vehicle. I am not entirely sure why, but I eventually managed to get the bolts in. I suspect it may have been partially due to the camber of the road. I&#39;ve used stainless bolts so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0095.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note on the cross member is that the cut out for the fuel hoses on my vehicle is in the wrong location. This probably varies from vehicle to vehicle. One was YRM could improve this is to have a wider cut out. I have added additional protection and will tywrap the hoses out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the crossmember was in it was time to start fitting the upstand/upriser. The new item is a different size to the old one. In a good way. The lips are about another 10mm deep. This means that around the top a certain amount of fitting is required, this is around the spars under the floor and the doubler between the separate sections of floor near the doors. I only cut out these areas, I like the idea of the extra depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new item seemed longer also, I did not have to cut it down. The reason is that the old panel was tapered making the top shorter than the bottom edge. I spaced it evenly each side and it seems ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0102.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fitting done, I have now dry fitted it, drilled the holes for the top rivets and will tomorrow drill the sides pieces and seat brackets. At the moment the rivets are all loose. I will strip it out and paint it once I have dry assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The floor is in with a couple of screws at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair continues</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130717-141934.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll need to forgive the posts at the moment, they are short and sweet. This is because I am under pressure and because I am feeling guilty about not posting, all I would like to on what has happened and what I want to happen. I am doing them on the run with the Wordpress app.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow an update on the floor repair of the landy. The second row floor is out. This was a bit of hassle as all the screws were seized. I have no power at the vehicle so a grinder was not an option. The up stand/ upriser is out and the mid cross member is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also cleaned up around the mid cross member mountings and put stone chip paint on it to give it some protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0086.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand Corrosion Repair</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130715-194202.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promised to do some posts about our planned trip, which we are due to depart on in 11 days. As of now we have not even booked the channel tunnel crossing or got our international driving permits. We are cutting it fine this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo shows some horrible corrosion I needed to get fixed before we go. It is in the area of the second row seat brackets on the upstand. Fairly typical of what happens when you combine steel and aluminium. Electrolytic corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I am in the throws of stripping the floor and getting the panel out. The end caps were particularly hard due to a hidden solid rivet under the c post bracket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New panels are from YRM, I got the upstanding and end brackets from them. I also have a galvanised crossmember I am not sure if I will fit that yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to post more pictures as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130715-195412.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Warm Up and Last Minute Fuel Pump Change</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 08:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-30-may-2013-1644.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend we got lucky with the weather, mostly. We spent a couple of nights camping in Wales. On the way we decided we&amp;#039;d break the journey, by stopping the night at a pub that allows camping in their garden. So we stopped in Wiltshire at The Parish Lantern, highly recommended. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole journey avoided the motorways and took us through many little interesting towns and funny back roads, on the way back we managed to include a couple of green lanes near Salisbury and the Stone Henge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1518.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1536.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to departure, I thought I&amp;#039;d change the fuel filter, the Landy will get it&amp;#039;s service any day, but in the mean time I though that I&amp;#039;d do the filter because I felt it had been a bit sluggish when I had occasionally driven it over the winter. As you&amp;#039;d expect the filter was quick and easy to change. But.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems occurred during priming, I was not able to prime the filter with the lift pump handle. I though it may have been the position of the pump lever on the cam, flicking the engine over a few times did not improve that. I managed to get the engine started though after several attempts without the lift pump for assistance, then just to confirm my suspicion cracking the bleed screw on the filter housing did not give a stream of diesel. This in my eyes proved the lift pump was failed and that it was not pressurising the filter, etc. It was getting late on the night before we left at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I had a new genuine lift pump in my spares box complete with olives, nuts and gasket. I would have to make a decision. Live with it and fit a new one on return or fit the spare in the morning before we left. The problem is that I did not want to have a sluggish vehicle on a long journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the task seemed mostly simple I took the gamble to fit it in the morning. In the pouring rain. My only apprehension was that the bolts to the block interface plate could be seized. They were not, so after establishing that, I spent an hour and the problem was fixed. Pump on and decent pressure restored at the pump bleed screw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside of it all was that we got off earlier on our weekend trip and managed to have an early pint at the pub we stayed at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the annual trip approaching over the next couple of weeks, I have to get a service done on the Landy and fix the second row seat up riser corrosion which is a big job. For that I managed to get a galvanised mid cross member from YRM metal solutions together with the aluminium panels I need. I just hope I can get it all apart! I&amp;#039;ll keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirations for 2013&#39;s Trip</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 19:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2013-1900.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as I mentioned earlier in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, we have been thinking about what we might do this summer. Actually we have been thinking since last summer. I guess we are probably not alone on this, we tend to think from trip to trip, from day to day, even during a trip. I guess most people who enjoy travelling have this problem. Is it wrong? I don&amp;#039;t want to wish my life away, but I love thinking about possibilities, getting the map out while drinking wine or beer in camp. Is that dreamin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us we have been to lots of places in Europe, we still have much of Northern Europe to go and places on our own door step such as Scotland and Ireland, but the weather makes life tricky in those places. We don&amp;#039;t want to be confined, confined to a hotel. We want the option to camp, we like camping. No we are not poor, we just like to get away from it. I camp in hotels all year for work, I really don&amp;#039;t like it. So I guess sooner or later we need to take the plunge and face the weather, before we loose the opportunity to see the places we take for granted on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we have been thinking about travel this August. Unfortunately during tourist season, we are bound to this because of school holidays, we tend to get away lightly due to the places we visit, not always. Our plans have been a little hampered this year, domestics are getting in the way! We had to have the kitchen done... I guess you are wondering what the hell I am on. Well it is all about economics. The kitchen cost a fortune (it is still not finished). This has hampered our trip money saving ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this has meant that, although we have &amp;#039;planned&amp;#039;, the plan is more of an &amp;#039;aspiration&amp;#039;. Let me explain. I guess what we are saying is that, we refuse to give up the opportunity of our annual trip. Regardless of how far we have saved, we&amp;#039;ll see how far we can go on what we&amp;#039;ve got! So if we don&amp;#039;t know what we will be able to do we should plan for what we&amp;#039;d like to do. So I guess you&amp;#039;d say plan for your aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that explained. We&amp;#039;d like this year to explore some more dirt roads in the Alps, there is a warren up there and plenty of places to wild camp without having to part with Euros. After that we&amp;#039;d also like to explore Kosovo, Albania and Macedonia. These are completely new to us and potentially very exciting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-may-2013-2022.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we get from the Alps to Albania and the surrounding areas, would either be by road or by sea. We used a ferry last year from Bari to Croatia which made life very easy, but expensive. The easiest ferry option for Albania is from Ancona to Durrës. This costs circa €400 but saves probably about three days in raw driving, that is really more because we stop and take a non direct route. The ferry crossing is around 20 hours. The saving is definitely not in fuel, even in a Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of getting to Albania from Ancona, is that we can use the days saved to spend more time exploring before heading back, it is probably about 1500 miles (2600 km) to Brighton from there. Which would be about 7 days driving, we&amp;#039;d need to allow about 10 so we could chill a bit. This would leave us about 2 weeks in the area we want to be. In reality I&amp;#039;d hope to be able to build some of the return days into the route to allow us to look at possibly Kosovo, Montenegro and Bosnia and Herzegovina a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks we&amp;#039;ll be looking at every country we aspire to visit this year and posting a bit about sites and areas that have caught our attention. This will hopefully culminate with a rough route plan. Hopefully we&amp;#039;ll be able to research some more Alps routes too. So stay tuned if you want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Minutes jobs are never 5 minutes</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/19/5-minutes-jobs-are-never-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 20:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/19/5-minutes-jobs-are-never-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it every job on my Landy that should be five minutes, takes hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changed the front mud flaps on the Land Rover yesterday... and today. Passenger side easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drivers side was a different story. One of the bolts was heavily corroded into the rivnut. This meant that the rivnut spun... Only choice was to rip the rivnut out and replace it. Luckily I managed to fit a new one of the same size. All without the proper tool to clamp it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice trick with a bolt, washer and nut. Let me know if you can&#39;t figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway another five minute job done in 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just some of the Jobs on Tusky</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/18/just-some-of-the-jobs-on-tusky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 12:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/18/just-some-of-the-jobs-on-tusky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;sites-canvas-main-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;When we got Tusky, it was clear that after 150,000+ miles she was going to need certain items doing. Most of these have been done by us, either on the road outside our flat or behind the flats in a quite space we have managed to get access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The jobs below are really things that needed doing to get her back up to spec.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;jot-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;table id=&#34;goog-ws-list-table&#34;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Panhard rod bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace panhard rod bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Trailing arm refurb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace trailing arm bushes, strip and paint arms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Radius arm refurbishment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace radius arm &amp;amp; chassis bushes, strip and paint arms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Anti-Roll bar bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace anti-roll bar bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Remove rear side facing seats&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Remove the rear most seats to make way for storage.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Steering Box Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The steering box had a typical leak from the output shaft. As per most land rovers. The solution was to change the box for an reconditioned item.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Steering Hose Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The hose from the steering reservoir to the pump was leaking. This was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Oil Cooler Hose Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Pipe to the oil cooler was leaking this was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Cyclone Breather Change&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The cyclone breather was changed because it was old and very dirty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Turbo Heat Shield&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The turbo heat shield was cracked and about ready to fall off this was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Vacuum Pump Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Vacuum Pump was leaking and noisy this was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Air Filter Mounting Rubbers - Perished&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The air filter housing bracket mounting rubbers where all perished. These have all been changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Upper steering UJ Play&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The upper steering UJ had a lot of play this has been changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Gearbox Recondition and Clutch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;After a long drive, luckily near our home the gearbox selector packed up, turned out to have ended up in the box acording to the garage. So we had our box reconditioned and a new clutch fitted.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Rear Diff Pinion Seal - Salisbury Axle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The rear axle is leaking from the pinion seal. I need to get this changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>