<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gale on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/gale/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gale on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/gale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 - Neufchateau to Weimheim</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/28/day-2-neufchateau-to-weimheim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 23:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/28/day-2-neufchateau-to-weimheim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided that Cassie was to sleep in her own tent last night. We set her up and put her to bed. Dan and Wendy enjoyed another beer and Dan went off for a shower. While Dan was on his way back from the shower, Cas got up for a wee, but only for Wendy to grab her and hold her as a LARGE GALE swept across the area. Dan mentioned branches falling as he walked back to camp, meanwhile Cassie and Wendy were holding down the ladder in hope the Landy and Tent would not blow over sideways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was with some trepidation that we decided to sleep in the roof tent. At one point the gale blew from below the roof tent, seeming like the whole thing was blowing up off the roof of the Landy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a pretty sleepless night, (for Dan and Cassie…not Wendy, she went to sleep in the comfort knowing Dan was looking after everyone), we woke to a wet morning. A quick pack up, yet again no breakfast, and a coffee at the campsite restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie had made friends with the neighbours, a couple and their kids from the Netherlands, the evening before. The kids spoke English and this appealed to Cassie. The Dad came over and asked us how we had faired over the night. We exclaimed that we were glad we had not been carried off into the night, flying in the roof tent. They had lost their awning in the gales and might require some parts to med it…not only that but their battery was dead, and please may we give them a jump start? Of course we obliged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After showers, a jump start and a coffee or two (in Dan&#39;s case), we headed out onto the road. The weather seemed to follow us and we seemed to drive all day in the rain. It finally cleared at about 1400hrs. We decided to find a campsite after spending a good day on the road. The GPS led us to a monstrosity of a campsite, (The ones with a pool and hundreds of caravans). It had been a long day and Cas wanted to swim in the pool, so we relented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we set up the roof tent, The clouds and weather front moved in on us. Cas was so hell bent on going for a swim, we chivvied her into putting her kossie on and getting into the pool. She at least got 20min swimming before we legged it back to the tent. We decided to grace the restaurant at the campsite due to the weather and enjoyed good beer…food not so much to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We shall try and head into Austria tomorrow, out running the weather that seems to be following us!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>