<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Czech Republic on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/czech-republic/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Czech Republic on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/czech-republic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Photos from Jihlava</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/02/25/photos-from-jihlava/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 16:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/02/25/photos-from-jihlava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-19-feb-2013-2119.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368462949986.5693&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Írovica&#34; width=&#34;341&#34; height=&#34;455&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After meeting our friends in Prague, we went with them to their home town, Jihlava. Spent a few days there exploring the surrounding area and &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few more pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-20-feb-2013-0056.jpg?w=500&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/8497954365_e264ca77a0_c.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368462949983.1238&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Nice tree&#34; width=&#34;456&#34; height=&#34;608&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/8497955315_a158142ea2_c.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368462949996.988&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/8499060706_888e212640_c.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368462949962.5664&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/8497956251_a527112808_c.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368462949968.956&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Pictures from the Czech Republic - Prague</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/02/23/some-pictures-from-the-czech-republic-prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 20:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/02/23/some-pictures-from-the-czech-republic-prague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February we took 6 days out, to visit our friends Kamil and Helena, who were taking a holiday from their overland trip driving from Hove to Australia. The reason for their break was because the car was being shipped from Japan to Australia. Need less to say it was freezing. &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent the first day in Prague, then went to Jihlava to see their home town and then returned to Prague for another day. Short but sweet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some photos of Prague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/8499031550_fee0552bb6_c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/8499032544_76a51ab8ff_c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 16: 22 AUGUST,Teplice nad Metuji – Ĉeský Krumlov</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/23/day-16-22-augustteplice-nad-metuji-cesky-krumlov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 16:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/23/day-16-22-augustteplice-nad-metuji-cesky-krumlov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We woke early today. Breaking camp and packing up was easier with our wonderful new tents. Today we are off to Ĉeský Krumlov, stopping along the way at the Church of Bones in Kostince near Kutná Hora. We were traffic lucky today and made it to Kostnice in good time. The church is the outcome of an estimated 40 000 to 70 000 peoples bones used to decorate the church. The church is said to be a reminder of our humanity, that without redemption we cannot enter heaven. It was an extremely interesting place. We bought some souvenirs and headed out looking for lunch. We set off after lunch for Ĉeský Krumlov. It turns out that Cassie has gained a wobbly tooth..oh the woes of being a child. We went through Ĉeský Budějove, home of Budweiser, on our way to Ĉeský Krumlov. Not much to write home about really. The outskirts of Ĉeský Krumlov looked a bit like a building site. We drove through and found a campsite on the outskirts of Ĉeský Krumlov. The camp we found was in a solar farm, very bizarre. We paid for only 1 night as we were unsure if we wanted to stay or not. What we ended up deciding on was having dinner in the camp restaurant, breaking cmp early and heady off into Ĉeský Krumlov for breakfast so that we could beat the tourists and still see the town. We sat outside and ate our dinner under candle light..romantic? Not really, we couldn’t see what it was we were eating! Another early night, this time with an alarm wake up for 7am so we could make town for breakfast and head off in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080995.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090024.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090038.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090044.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090045.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 14/15: 20/21 AUGUST  Martin (Slovakia) – Teplice nad Metuji (Czech Republic)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/22/day-1415-2021-august-martin-slovakia-teplice-nad-metuji-czech-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 16:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/22/day-1415-2021-august-martin-slovakia-teplice-nad-metuji-czech-republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: 560 Crowns – 2 nights = €23.00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After an initial hiccup of taking the wrong exit and having to do a big loop, we finally made our way to the Czech. Unfortunately for us the road was VERY slow going. Not a motorway, still a major road, but FULL of trucks and slow moving vehicles making it a long journey. We stopped at 12pm for lunch and a drink, but we were still stuck at about 2pm in a traffic jam with still roughly 90km to go till we get to Adršpach. The traffic was driving us crazy, so we deviated off onto smaller roads. Turned out to be a wise decision and we finally made it to a camp site in Teplice nad Metuji. It was a lovely, quiet camp site. We found a nice quiet spot and set about putting up the new tents. They went up in no time! A HUGE difference from the other tent.We had managed to find a supermarket and cash machine along the way. More ‘funny money’ to get used to. We bought pasta for dinner tonight as we already had bits and bobs to turn it into a feast. We had our pasta with some toast made from the bread that needed to be finished. Wasn’t the best meal, but it wasn’t the worst either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080861.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080862.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080865.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 15: 21 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan discovered some maps for the area. The guy at the office said that we could catch the train to Adršpach. We decided to catch the train there and walk back. When we got to the station we discovered that Dan got the times wrong. We changed our plan and instead walked to Adršpach and caught the train back. It was a magnificent walk. You had to pay to get into the National Reserve – 150 Crowns for 2 adults and 1 child. The walk took us through forest, over peat bogs, up steps over the rocks and down steps into the rocks. Overall, we walked for 3 &amp;amp; half hours. Casie did amazingly well considering in some places the steps were so steep and precarious Dan had to carry her! After a good 12mile walk, we finally reached the end. Here we treated ourselves to some chips. We got some souvenirs for Cassie’s friends. We found the train station and awaited our train back to town. Once back at the camp site, we washed and headed out to find some dinner. We had some local food and drank some Czech white wine. We headed back to camp for an early night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080894.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080903.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080925.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080941.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080952.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>