<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tito on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/tito/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tito on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/tito/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 11/12: 9/10 AUGUST 2011 Studenica (Serbia) – Durmitor National Park (Montenegro)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 17:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Razvršje €10 – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We attempted to have a lie in this morning, we managed to sleep until 7.50am! A shower to wash away the bed bugs and another cereal breakfast in our room. Off into the Monastery for a look see. The monastery was quiet, we seemed to be the only visitors at that time. The restoration team were there hard at work and inside the chapel it seemed like they had a lot of work on their hands and perhaps for a few many years. Off we went onto our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8851.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8869.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8883.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Back through that little town Ivanjeca, where this time we bought a plastic sealed drum/tub to act as our washing machine. Our washing was now getting out of hand. The border crossing into Montenegro was a breeze with the Green card only €15 this time! We finally made it to Durmitor and we found a campsite! A stop of 2 nights and a proper rest up. It was our anniversary, we wanted to go out for dinner, but town was a bit of a walk. Instead, we had dinner cooked by the campsite owner an elderly local lady. Trout, Bean soup, salad and potatoes oh and free beer. It was a lovely meal. They had erected an old military mess tent to act as a dining room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8914.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 12: WEDNESDAY 10 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It rained last night, not heavily, but a lot. And when we woke up, it was still raining. We stayed in the tent because of the rain. Dan got up and made us tea and coffee, we drank it inside the tent. Today was a day that having our big tent would have been useful with its big middle bit. We’d used up all the milk, so we decided to go into town to get breakfast. As we left we thought we’d look at the time…it was 11.30! We walked into town and attempted to change our Serbian Dinar into Euro, but no-one was having it. We went to the baker and got: 1 loaf of bread, 2 donuts, 1 pastry, 2 sausage rolls and 1 jam cake slice…all for €3.30! Bargain! It was off to the supermarket for supplies. As it was still raining on and off we decided to come back into town for dinner. We stopped for a coffee and juice and headed back to the camp. We made up a sandwich for Wendy, packed up the back pack and headed off for Crno Jezero or Black Lake. The walk was 20-25 min walk there. Along the way we walked through an abandoned Serbian holiday camp. Very eerie and spooky. When we got to the lake, we walked around it to find Tito’s cave where he’s said to have hid his supplies during the 2nd World War. The cave was no longer a cave, it seemed to have been blocked up. A little disappointing. We walked back to camp. The walk back was a little harder as all up hill. When we got back none of us were hungry, so we decided to just have a drink and snack and possibly an early night, with prayers of a sunny morning. We ended up ordering food from the lady again: pork chops, potatoes and salad, free beer too.. We had an early night, ready to move on in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8915.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8923.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8927.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8928.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8941.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8951.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8945.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8947.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>