<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mostar on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/mostar/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mostar on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/mostar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 15: SATURDAY 13 AUGUST 2011 Donji Morinj (Montenegro) – Mostar (Bosnia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/14/day-15-saturday-13-august-2011-donji-morinj-montenegro-mostar-bosnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/14/day-15-saturday-13-august-2011-donji-morinj-montenegro-mostar-bosnia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Sobe (A dodgy private room) €25 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A fairly early start for us, with not far to travel either. The border crossing was uneventful, even for a Saturday. We managed to make it to Mostar by 14.30hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;FOOTNOTE: The Garmin screen has given up the ghost. Unable to use it to navigate, we are now subject to map (i.e Wendy) navigation. She seems to get a little better each year though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;No camps in Mostar, so we decided to enquire about room prices. The first one quoted €40 for a night, Dan said it was a nice place but a little to steep. Not by UK standards thou. We parked up in secure, paid parking and went on the quest for a room. After enquiring and being lead to the back of beyond, we got a fair enough price on a room for the night – €25. We accepted and then went to get a pivo + sok. We found a lovely bar overlooking the river and under the famous old bridge. Cassie managed to brave up and wonder down to the river to put her feet in. We watched a few teenagers dive into the river from a platform on the opposite side of the river. After our pivo, we went exploring. We wondered along the souvenir alley, here we got our obligatory fridge magnet, a plate for the wall, Cassie got a wooden box and Wendy got some harem trousers. After that we had another pivo. It was extremely hot. Not that it is an excuse! Then we went to find a recommended restorant in the Bosnia guide book. We ordered a mixed grill for 2 people – honestly this could have fed 4 people! We thought we’d hunt out a place called ABC, a sweet shop, said by the guide book, to be the best in Bosnia. We managed to find it and had a dessert. Dan had a cake, Wendy and Cassie had some ice cream. We then wondered back to Tusky to get our bits and bobs and back to our room. A good nights sleep for a change. Woke up fairly early and were showered and out by 8.00hrs…a record!! Off to Blagaj and the Dervish house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9093.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9118.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9124.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9199.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;100&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9130.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9151.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9156.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9165.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9174.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9208.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9213.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>