<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walking on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/categories/walking/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Walking on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/africanuhambo.github.io/categories/walking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend stroll - Ford to Littlehampton, West Sussex</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/28/weekend-stroll-ford-to-littlehampton-west-sussex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 19:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/28/weekend-stroll-ford-to-littlehampton-west-sussex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the weather forecast looking good, we decided that today we were going for a walk, a walk with criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The criteria was that it had to have a start and finish at a railway station and that we wanted to say away from crowds. It also had to have locations that would be suitable for a picnic lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said we decided to head on the train to Ford from our local station, 36 minutes away. The plan was to follow the river Arun towards the beach the follow the foot paths and a byway to bring us on to the beach circa 2 miles west of Littlehampton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/fordtolittlehamptonwalk.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had lunch on the beach then headed for the railway station in Littlehampton to head home. We timed it perfectly arriving three minutes before the 1414 to London departed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This route took us about 2.5 hours and is pretty flat, it is just under 10 kilometers. So with lunch we averaged about 4 km/h.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to download the GPX file, you can grab it from &lt;a title=&#34;GPS Route&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B3lq5J_TSkjFMDBmTmU3TnZ2dzg/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durmitor National Park, Montenegro - Garmin Maps</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/28/durmitor-national-park-montenegro-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 20:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/28/durmitor-national-park-montenegro-maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-11-sep-2011-10142.jpg?w=253&#34; alt=&#34;Durmitor National Park 1:25000 map&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we stayed in Durmitor National park, during our August 2011 trip, the guy who seemed to run the camp site at &lt;a title=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.durmitor-autocamp.com/home.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Autocamp Razvršje&lt;/a&gt;, gave us a great walking map, which I kept, being a map addict. Actually I think he gave one to everyone, so we weren&#39;t special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, by luck the other day they sent out a marketing email. Intrigued I browsed their site and noticed they had an electronic copy of the map and others on their site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are pretty good maps of the area in 1:25,000 scale. So I thought I would grab a copy for next time I am there. Anyway, follow the link above to their site to get a copy or there are links below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also if you need a place to stay, Autocamp Razvršje is as good as any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Some Garmin devices such as the Montana series allow the importing of custom maps. This is done via Google Earth. You have to import the map as a layer to Google Earth then align it (georeference), then save it as a KMZ. Once this is done you can import it to Garmin&#39;s Basecamp or upload it and save it to the Custom Map folder on your GPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a copy of the Durmitor KMZ I made click &lt;a title=&#34;Garmin Durmitor KMZ&#34; href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/Durmitor National Park Map 25k.kmz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructions on creating custom maps are available &lt;a href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/custommaps_instruct.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:none;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-19491.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-19491.jpg?w=650&#34; alt=&#34;Durmitor&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;469&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:none;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1949.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1949.jpg?w=650&#34; alt=&#34;Tara Canyon&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;469&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/tara-kanjon-karta.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tara Canyon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/primorje.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Montenegro Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/060214_m.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Montenegro General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ford Railway Station to Devils Dyke Walk</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/19/ford-railway-station-to-devils-dyke-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 17:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/19/ford-railway-station-to-devils-dyke-walk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Wendy and I, have recently walked from Ford railway station to Devils Dyke, we followed the Arun river up-stream past Arundel to Amberley, were we spent the night. From there we walked along the South Downs Way to Devils Dyke. We spent the night in Amberley which is a fantastic little village in Sussex. We recorded the journey with Everytrail, you can follow the link &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/view_trip.php?trip_id=683253&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in the Everytrail recording. We plan to do some more walks in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/ford-to-devils-dyke.jpg&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-163&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;604&#34; height=&#34;324&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;For our overnight stay we managed to get a booking at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.streamcottage.co.uk/intro.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Stream Cottage&lt;/a&gt; which is in the heart of Amberley and run by a wonderful couple. The breakfast is superb! Unfortunately I was unable to eat it all... For dinner there are a few pubs in Amberley, I had the Mixed grill at the Black Horse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080082.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The Arun&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Click &lt;a title=&#34;Ford to Devils Dyke GPS Track in GPX format&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFNjY2ZmQ3ODUtZmY2Zi00ODdlLTg5YjItMGVjOTU4YmE2ZmZm&amp;amp;authkey=CMHtv8MC&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is you would like the GPS track. Below are a few pictures from the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080085.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Arundel Castle&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080092.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The Black Rabbit watering hole&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080120.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Amberley&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080124.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Lovely poppies!&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080131.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;This is Us&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080151.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Finish at the Devils Dyke&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 11/12: 9/10 AUGUST 2011 Studenica (Serbia) – Durmitor National Park (Montenegro)</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 17:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Razvršje €10 – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We attempted to have a lie in this morning, we managed to sleep until 7.50am! A shower to wash away the bed bugs and another cereal breakfast in our room. Off into the Monastery for a look see. The monastery was quiet, we seemed to be the only visitors at that time. The restoration team were there hard at work and inside the chapel it seemed like they had a lot of work on their hands and perhaps for a few many years. Off we went onto our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8851.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8869.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8883.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Back through that little town Ivanjeca, where this time we bought a plastic sealed drum/tub to act as our washing machine. Our washing was now getting out of hand. The border crossing into Montenegro was a breeze with the Green card only €15 this time! We finally made it to Durmitor and we found a campsite! A stop of 2 nights and a proper rest up. It was our anniversary, we wanted to go out for dinner, but town was a bit of a walk. Instead, we had dinner cooked by the campsite owner an elderly local lady. Trout, Bean soup, salad and potatoes oh and free beer. It was a lovely meal. They had erected an old military mess tent to act as a dining room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8914.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 12: WEDNESDAY 10 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It rained last night, not heavily, but a lot. And when we woke up, it was still raining. We stayed in the tent because of the rain. Dan got up and made us tea and coffee, we drank it inside the tent. Today was a day that having our big tent would have been useful with its big middle bit. We’d used up all the milk, so we decided to go into town to get breakfast. As we left we thought we’d look at the time…it was 11.30! We walked into town and attempted to change our Serbian Dinar into Euro, but no-one was having it. We went to the baker and got: 1 loaf of bread, 2 donuts, 1 pastry, 2 sausage rolls and 1 jam cake slice…all for €3.30! Bargain! It was off to the supermarket for supplies. As it was still raining on and off we decided to come back into town for dinner. We stopped for a coffee and juice and headed back to the camp. We made up a sandwich for Wendy, packed up the back pack and headed off for Crno Jezero or Black Lake. The walk was 20-25 min walk there. Along the way we walked through an abandoned Serbian holiday camp. Very eerie and spooky. When we got to the lake, we walked around it to find Tito’s cave where he’s said to have hid his supplies during the 2nd World War. The cave was no longer a cave, it seemed to have been blocked up. A little disappointing. We walked back to camp. The walk back was a little harder as all up hill. When we got back none of us were hungry, so we decided to just have a drink and snack and possibly an early night, with prayers of a sunny morning. We ended up ordering food from the lady again: pork chops, potatoes and salad, free beer too.. We had an early night, ready to move on in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8915.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8923.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8927.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8928.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8941.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8951.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8945.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8947.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 5/6: WEDNESDAY 3/4 AUGUST 2011, Bürserberg (Austria) – Dovje (Slovenia)</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/05/day-56-wednesday-34-august-2011-burserberg-austria-dovje-slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 17:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/05/day-56-wednesday-34-august-2011-burserberg-austria-dovje-slovenia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Camp Kamne €50.16 incl. electric – 2 nights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today was a long drive. We set off a little later than we should have and encountered lots of windy mountain passes. We went into Italy with a drastic scenery change, out and back into Austria and then finally into Slovenia. The hairpin bends we drove seemed almost endless. We stopped for diesel and managed to get some bread as well. We then spent a few hours trying to find a good spot for lunch. We finally pulled into a little side road and just picnicked off on the side. Lunch over, it was now time to crack on and make it to Slovenia. The road into Slovenia was another story all together! What a steep incline, to add to that it was another mountain pass, lined with various warning signs. Dan stopped and put the car in low range so we could make it up and ignore all the warnings. The pass over, we headed for the nearest campsite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we were settled and set up, we looked at the distance to our next planned stop and decided that we would stay 2 nights. We needed the break and not to mention the stretch of the legs. Maybe a nice leisurely stroll into the mountains tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8455.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8457.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8467.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 6: THURSDAY 4 AUGUST 2012&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Last night there was an immense thunderstorm (What is it about Slovenia and the Bovec area?). We ended up with Cassie in the tent with us. It was an uncomfortable nights sleep due to the fact that little missy moo Cassie likes to spread herself out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We met a couple staying in the camp. They are from New Zealand have are travelling around Europe with their 2 kids for 6 weeks before moving back to New Zealand. They recommended going to see the nearby waterfall, Slap Peričnik. Here you can walk behind the waterfall too. Sounds cool. We decided to walk there, going to the nearby town of Mojstrana and to the information centre to ask about the weather. From here we walked up to the waterfall. It was along the road that we walked and had to move out of the way of a few cars now and then, but it quickly turned to a gravel track. When we got to the waterfall, it was another sharp hike up to the falls themselves. A little steep climb, we used this opportunity to show Cassie how to navigate these types of things independently. At the top the spray from waterfall was immense, refreshing and a little shocking. We walked along behind the waterfall, getting soaked in the process. It was lovely and refreshing after the long old walk to get there. We explored a bit and then we stopped at the picnic spot at the bottom for lunch, just simple bread and cheese. Next we went to the Café and had a beer. Cassie had a juice and Dan got her a souvenir cow bell. We saw another track on the map that went along the other side of the river, we decided to walk back along here. It was like we were in another place, walking through the trees, watching the butterflies and dipping our feet into the freezing stream. It was a lovely walk back. Overall, we walked 18km today. We stopped off at the supermarket in Mojstrana to get some supplies and headed back to camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we got back Cassie went for a swim with the little girl from the New Zealand couple we met. That night we had a concoction of a dinner, hoisin chicken stir fry with carrots, red peppers and onions with Mediterranean couscous. Cassie thought it was delicious, but Dan and I didn’t agree. We decided to pack up Cas’ tent and sleep all in the 1 again incase there was another storm. This time though, we put Cas’ mattress in as well to try and make it a little more comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8473.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8478.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8490.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8491.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8497.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8505.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>