<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wild Camping on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/wild-camping/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wild Camping on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/wild-camping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Needed a lightweight stove</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 20:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, I needed to get a lightweight stove for a quick camping microadventure on Saturday night. I did not want to buy one and was considering self heating meals and no coffee in the morning. Until I found inspiration from a post on twitter to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/64726512&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Allen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to have a go at building my own also. I had some mentholated spirit for fuel, I just needed a drink can to make the stove. After a quick trip to the local shop, and with my thirst quenched I had my raw material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1013.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10131.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10132.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10133.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimmed the top and bottom sections. Bottom section is about 30mm high, the top is about 50mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2035.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20351.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creat flues in the side of the can with a knife. Small at the top. Large at the bottom. These form the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20352.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mate both sections&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20353.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ridges are critical. They are small at the top, large at the bottom. They form the fuel generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small hole using a pin just under the top lip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20354.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small amount of fuel, approx 5mm deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20355.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light, wait 10 seconds for fuel to heat in the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10134.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once hot the fuel vaporises in the side ridges, which is the generator the flames only burn on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10135.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about 5 minutes to boil two cups of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1012.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weights very little too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10121.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field test!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2007.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised by the stove, it had no trouble heating my dinner or boiling water in my coffee maker. Just keep it out of the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how these work. Check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beverage-can_stove&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyWay Serengeti Modifications</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, we had some issues with the MyWay Serengeti tent, we loved it. But we need to get the niggles sorted. Luckily Paul was on hand with advice and apologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights in the tent we did discover the first issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top half cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base board, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically locked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in hight between the two plywood base halves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-1841.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to remedy this we installed some locating pegs, which are actually formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-18411.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second issue we found when we removed the tent from the Landy. This was that the lower half of the cover was holding a small amount of water. We had come back from France is some serious rain, I guess that must have made it through the overlap seal in the cover. I guess this would have been exacerbated by the fact we had to pack the tent away wet on the way back. Had we used the tent after the rain this would have had the chance to dry out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remedy this issue we cut some crosses into the lower cover about 20 mm in length, these are just two slices or lines that form a flap arrangement. We located these in three places. The first was central and the others were about 30 cm from each side in each corner on the hinge end of the tent. Hopefully any water collecting will have a route out now. I was originally planning to put five slots into the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess time will tell how these modifications work. We&amp;#039;ll let you know if we have an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Stats - Summer 2012 Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In starting to consider this years plan, i thought i would post some recorded figures from last summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stats from our last trip from 27th July to the 26th August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We covered 3663.1 miles, about 5900 km.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used 606.42 litres of diesel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Averaged 27 miles per gallon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filled up 15 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid 26 tolls totalling 287.8 Euro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most expensive where for the Tunnel de Mont Blanc at 38.9 and tunnel de Frejus at 39.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used the channel tunnel for crossing the channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used a over night ferry from Bari to Dubrovnik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 night in a hotel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 attempted nights at a hotel night resulting in six police officers attending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 nights free camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 none catastrophic car part failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which do you want to know more about!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Jafferau and Lago Di Rochemolles</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1220.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125197.9639&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track Up To Fort Jafferau &#34; width=&#34;417&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After spending the night at &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/&#34;&gt;Fort Pramond&lt;/a&gt;, we had a plan today to driver up to Mount Jafferau then on to a nearby Lake that is now a reservoir, we were hoping to spend the night by the river there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to pack up fairly promptly and were on the way by the time the day was heating up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-0911.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125203.729&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Exit of the exciting tunnel&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was kind of excited about the day, because we were heading along a track that showed a cool tunnel on the map. I dunno how I came to that conclusion,  just by looking at the map. The tunnel on the track is circa 800 meters long, unlit, unpaved and leaks more than you would see in a normal road tunnel as it is not lined. This leak leads to a stream of water in the tunnel that is often a few inches deep. Oh and the end never seemed to appear, leading to a further sense of excitement under the dim light of the Landys head lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1213.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125156.5093&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Jafferau&#34; width=&#34;358&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The other thing about the day that excited me was the climb to the Fort on Mount Jafferau, this sits at circa 2800 meters and promises spectacular views. We were not let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Most of the track up to Jafferau is easy in a 4 x 4, I am not sure how far you&amp;#039;d want to go in a ordinary car. There are some fairly rocky sections, not hard but difficult in most cars. If the weather was bad, you would not consider it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the way up to Mount Jafferau, we were listening on the CB to other people that we could not see. We could hear that they were watching us, as they were mentioning the English vehicles. Even with the aid of the binoculars we could not see who was watching us and nor could we find them. It was rather creepy being in a valley, with all the ex military sites and the creepy night we had the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The track we were following stopped at Jafferau... Sort of. We had a plan to asses the situation at the end. This was because we had a map that showed a 500 meter foot path then the start of a new track down the other side of Mount Jafferau. Well when we got there we found that there was a track down, that was fairly steep and circa 1000m descent. Linking the track up and the track down was actually the easy bit. We did the whole descent in low range 1st gear, but had to occasionally slow the descent a little on top. It was great because we were following the Ski run literally, so naturally this led to us arriving at the top of the bubble lift and at the restaurant at the top of the lift. A convenient place to stop for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1311.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125181.358&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Nice Lunch Stop&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel had a double helping of home made Lasagne, made by the Owners Wife and Wendy and I had a local platter of meats and cheeses. After a good fill. We carried on our descent, we had about another thousand meters to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed down towards Bardonecchia to pick up the track to take us up to the Lake for the next night. Unfortunately we found the/a track but could not find our way onto the one we wanted that led to the lake. We ended up back tracking and taking a scenic road that met up with the track we needed. The track was really easy and fairly pleasant if busy. You could have done this section in a car. Apart from going to the actual camping spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1546.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125152.4119&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Valley of Lago di Rochemolles &#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;107&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The road continues on from where we camped to one of the highest glaciers you can drive to in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1702.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125163.2832&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Refreshing Bath&#34; width=&#34;341&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We stopped for the evening at the river that feeds Lago di Rochemolles, it was obviously icy cold, but was great for a very invigorating bath and cooling some Prosecco. The valley was very scenic and a great stop for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1704.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125195.692&#34; class=&#34;alignnone&#34; alt=&#34;Cutting Wood&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;263&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we had a proper fire in a pit made by some predecessors, we managed to find enough wood nearby and an old sauce pan to warm water for washing up. Dinner that night was slightly left field. We had failed to stop for more supplies since our last supermarket stop, we had some powdered soup from Croatia. This was very nice, I think it was called Dalmation soup.... We also had three military ration packs, which had been given to us by John in Cinque terra. Our plan was to enjoy these as pudding after we had the roast potatoes. Unfortunately being military ration novices what we cooked for pudding was awful. I feel for the boys who eat them, this looked off. So we ended up going to bed a bit hungry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Update: I have since learnt that the packs last for 10 years. Sorry John. If you are reading this John, we lost your email address, hope you had a cool trip. It was great having a BBQ with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-2043.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125179.4502&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Girls Washing up.&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;233&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping by a stream led to a lot of night time pees. In the morning we woke stinking of smoke. Had breakfast and headed for the road. It was here, well in Bardonecchia we would say bye for a few days to Carole and Daniel. Obviously we did this over coffee and pastries. They were heading to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-17021.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125165.5713&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our Spot&#34; width=&#34;363&#34; height=&#34;272&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We from hear ambled our way via a few one night stops home, as usual once we got half way up France the heavens opened and we just headed back to the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fort Pramand, Mount Pramand Overnight</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 08:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1825.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394770.2654&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Pramand&#34; width=&#34;388&#34; height=&#34;291&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since leaving the Plitvička national park, in Croatia where we visited the former top secret airbase of &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/&#34;&gt;Zeljava&lt;/a&gt; we made our way to Fort Pramand, which was the next area we planned to do some off-road exploring, near Oulx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394854.0425&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Drinking Prosecco&#34; width=&#34;306&#34; height=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt; On the way we stopped in Slovenia at the Bovec national park to chill out for a day or so, around the beautiful mountains and river Soča, we seem to like that area and always have a good time exploring. We also stopped in Revine, which is near Connegliano in Italy, the area famous for Prosecco sparkling wine. We obviously had to grab a box from a vineyard. The main reason for stopping here though was to use it as a gateway to Venice. There is an intercity train that will take you straight into Venice main station. That&amp;#039;s another story though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After this we travelled towards Oulx, barring another one night stop at Lago Maggiore. Oulx is one of the nearest towns to where we had planned to head up to the tracks I had researched. So the original plan was to stock up with and food, water and beer we needed then go. Oulx has a few official camp sites in the immediate vicinity, should you need a base to explore from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;But the Landy had other ideas. I had noticed that on occasion with increasing frequency, that the battery voltage was creeping up to the point of potentially over charging the batteries. This was concerning, as apart from potentially screwing up my expensive new batteries it was likely to mean we could not depend on them when we were off the beaten track. Luckily when we stopped in Oulx, we had a fiddle with the alternator which was fairly new as I uprated it a few months earlier and found that some of the terminals must have either worked loose or built up a resistance on the regulator sensing connection. This obviously led to the regulator over exciting the alternator giving a high output voltage. It was interesting because none of the connections were noticeably loose. It has been fine since. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1448.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394803.1416&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;On the up&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So now the beer could be kept cool we headed up to the mountain tracks, via the main road that runs parallel to the E70 motorway, I think it is the ss n 24 headed east we took the left that leads up past Fort Fenils. However the excitement was not over! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As we started to ascend we suddenly noticed a strong smell of smoke and soon came to some mountain fire trucks, police and lots of people. It was a forest fire approaching the road, we were lucky though they guided us past. The road is tarmac for a few kilometres on the way up before it turns to easy gravel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Next the Pajero which Carole and Daniel were driving started to overheat! So we had to stop shortly after hitting gravel for lunch. Luckily to get to Fort Pramand we did not have far to go so, time was on our side. You&amp;#039;d think that was the end of the drama though surely. Luckily the next incident started as we approached the fort. The Pajero decided that the automatic transmission oil indicator would light, suggesting it was overheating. We guessed it was because of the low range work and slow speed, not helped probably by the earlier overheat. Oh well it would get a chance to cool overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1629.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394765.179&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tracks up&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The tracks up to Fort Pramand are easy, until you get to the last bit leading up to the Fort, which is a turn off from the main track anyhow. The track narrows because of trees either side that lean towards the center of the track. The ground has a few large roots to climb. It is not to bad in a small or low 4x4, but with the root tent on the Landy it was a little tricky, we clipped a corner of the tent lightly. Just a scuff mark no damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The Fort itself is fairly big, but in a very poor state of repair it sits at 2162 meters, there are various warnings spray painted on the walls warning of Danger. The roof is in a poor state of repair. I suspect it has had a few vehicles on its roof. You can walk onto it by following the track up, the view is excellent from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1746.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394771.471&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner&#34; width=&#34;356&#34; height=&#34;475&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we settled up there and started to cook and set ourselves up for the night it started to feel a bit spooky. The girls were convinced it was haunted. Especially when something took exception to Wendy&amp;#039;s singing. For some reason after we all told her not to quit her day job, and that she did no justice to Black Betty, the radio in the car came on and started blaring!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We had a nice dinner which was made even better with the red wine we got from Connegliano to season it. Shortly after the clouds rolled in so we disappeared for what we thought would be a peaceful night. However with the girls convinced we were being watched by spooky ghosts, Wendy woke a few times to noises, saying she felt like someone was climbing the ladder to the roof tent. She then woke me up because she was too scared to go to the toilet! The conversation went along the lines of.... &#34;Do you need a pee. no. Can you come with me. Do I have too. Yes. Well I am not going twice get Cassie, we&amp;#039;ll have a family pee.&#34; Needless to say. There was no ghost waiting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1754.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394800.108&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Setup&#34; width=&#34;366&#34; height=&#34;275&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With hind sight I guess being parked with the ladder right against the Fort, between two very dark portals was probably adding to the girls apprehension. In the morning Carole got out of the tent having had no sleep, because she was also convinced ghost soldiers were marching across their tent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After breakfast we left a little tired and headed for Mount Jafferau, via a cool tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;If you want to download the GPS track from this post and the next you can download it here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiloc.com/wikiloc/view.do?id=3261982&#34;&gt;Wikiloc&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/view_trip.php?trip_id=1741579&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Everytrail&#34;&gt;Everytrail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Feel free to leave a comment if you want to know more. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Col Linaire, Col de Sanson, Pas de Colle Ardente - Mount Saccarel</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871723104_817a4bd793.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;The next track&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;282&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After finishing up on Col de Tende we headed back down to the town of Tende for supplies and to freshen up at the local piscine (swimming pool) (If only they had known!), before we departed for the second section of our little off road trip. Again we planned to stay at least one night up on the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The local chap at the fuel station we met the day before, had been correct about Col de la Boaïra being block from the Fort Central end, so we decided to heed his advice again and took his recommended entry point to the next pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With a plan in place, we kicked off by heading south from Tende fully refreshed and clean towards St Dalmas de Tende, where we turned left to head east on the D43 past La Brigue. This took us to the turning for the D143 on the right that allowed us to get to what would be the start of our next off road excursion at Notre-Dame des Fontaines. Apparently this is worth a stop to have a look, we did not take the opportunity unfortunately but will next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed straight up towards Col Linaire, which would take us up through the forest &#34;Bois Du Pinet&#34; along what seemed considerably more dusty gravel tracks than the day before. On the way up we passed an old Willis Jeep heading down, the driver, his dog and Family looked local and to be having a great time. I guess the old Williss is ideal for adhoc dog walking on your local mountain. What an awesome playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Given the time we left Tende after our swim and restock, it was not long, probably 8 km from the church until we decided we would stop for a light lunch. We stopped at a 5 point junction that offered to easily get us lost. Luckily it was easy to work out the exit we needed, after removing the closed piste and the exit we arrived from! The junction on the map is at &#34;Cime du Pinet&#34;, which is the Top of the Pinet hill. There were various logs lying around for us to sit on to enjoy lunch. There must be a certain amount of forestry undertaken, perhaps to control the fire risk? While we were there another car was parked up with a local who had just gone mountain biking, he did not seem so friendly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871721608_6d3de535d8.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Forest Roads&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After having lunch we continued up the fourth exit... Towards Col du Loup, this continued through the Forêt Communale de la Brigue it was great driving through the forests, they provided a welcome break from the heat. As we were driving up, I was conscious that although we had enough water to last us easily for at least two nights, we did not have a lot spare, so was keeping an eye open for a source that would allow is to fill the solar shower and water carrier. At this time of the year there did not seem to be many streams around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871715168_50ec94991d_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Topping up with water&#34; width=&#34;227&#34; height=&#34;302&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily we happened upon a water trough that was reasonably full. The water looked clean enough for the intended purposes and had a steady flow into it, which meant it was not stagnant. We filled up the shower and most of the carrier. But it was a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14236.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Border marker&#34; width=&#34;339&#34; height=&#34;254&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After getting water, our final re-supply item we continued up to the border area to Col de Sanson / Baisse de Sanson. The next section hugs what I think is the 1947 border of France and Italy, it was fairly spectacular along the ridge or the south east side of Mont de Colle Ardente for the first 5 km or so, then the track pops over the top for the next roughly 6 km along the north west side of Mont Saccarel, I think this is Pas de colle Ardente or part of. This leads into Pas du Tanarel which will have you emerge on the eastern side of Mont Tanarel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15323.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track to Mont Saccarel &#34; width=&#34;322&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It is about 2 km south of this point you have the option to proceed down towards San Bernardo and off the mountain or as we did proceed towards Mont Saccarel which is at 2200 meters. Mont Saccarels&amp;#039; summit overlooks a 12 meter statue of Jesus, that was placed there is 1901. The statue has a fantastic view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we stayed on Mont Saccarel, just below the summit which had the remains of some old fortifications. When we arrived at the summit there were some local Italians having a braai, that had driven up in there 4x4&amp;#039;s. We parked above them on the summit and decided to walk to have a look at the statue, it was about 1 km walk and would allow us time to see what the local chaps did. As it goes they disappeared shortly after we started our stroll. So after taking some photos of us and the Jesus statue we wondered back and pitch camp where they had been. Our camp straddled the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-17542.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from the summit&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-16451.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Jesus Statue&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1646.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Group shot&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we used some of the water we collected on the way up, to boil up some pasta and washing up water, no one had the trotts in the morning so needless to say the water was fine. We had a hearty vegetable pasta dish for dinner followed by beer! The rest of the evening was spent admiring the changing view in the evening light and listening to the distant cattle grazing it&amp;#039;s way across the slopes below. Once the sun had gone down we went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night I got up to look at the stars (have a pee) which were almost blinding due to the lack of light pollution, in the distance far below us there was the orange clusters of street lights in local towns and villages. I spent a few minutes admiring until the cold got to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the morning, we woke to a definite chill as you&amp;#039;d expect from a clear night at that height, the morning was glorious and I could not wait to see the view first from inside the warm shelter of the tent, then while I enjoyed the warmth of a warm fresh coffee. There was a problem though, I first had to go for a climb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night we had visitors... My flip flop had gone for a walk, only one. So armed with one of Wendy&amp;#039;s on my once bare foot, I dug out the binoculars and eventually far below I spotted the outline of my black flip flop in the rocks and shrubs. Off I trekked to get it, shortly after I put the kettle on. On recovery of my flop, I was suspicious, apart from some sizeable teeth marks, there was also a fairly stinky deposit of what I think was pee. I suspect a fox or something decided to mark it&amp;#039;s territory on my flop flip. I promptly returned to camp to deal with the situation, both proud and puzzled. By this time the kettle was boiling and with my now clean flop, we enjoyed our coffee and I pondered the curious event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My flip flops will live another summer by the looks of things, I guess the wife&amp;#039;s did not smell nice enough for our visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-3-aug-2012-0659.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Solar shower&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having fed ourselves and packed up, we freshened up under the solar shower, the moon had little effect on it&amp;#039;s temperature thou, so it was rather refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We then headed down the track we arrived on before turning off down the mountain towards San Bernardo for a coffee, before we headed for Cinque Terre our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFNXBiaFM5VFBnSmM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Gps track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1528.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The road down&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1755.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Panoramic from summit&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;165&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baisse d&#39;Ourne, Col de Tende - Fort de la Marguerie, Fort Central</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning we woke at our Campsite in Barolo in Italy early, the plan was to get to Tende in France, stock up on supplies at the super market, fill up with diesel, grab some petrol for the stove and head up to Col de Tende. We did fairly well and managed to have breakfast, coffee and pack up to be on the road by 0920 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-10201.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tunnel de Tende&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;296&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the minor back roads from Barolo to enter France via the Tunnel de Tende, on the SS20/N204. The tunnel was interesting in that it was only open one way at a time. We arrived at the back end of a line going our way, so decided to stop at the restaurant by the tunnel for a coffee and a pastry. That also gave us the opportunity to investigate the oil pressure light that was coming on in the in-laws car. We found nothing that would explain the light... Kicking the tyres did the trick thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tende is a picturesque town, that has houses perched on top of one another, we found a supermarket on the main drag, which was conveniently located next to a souvenir shop followed by a cafe. After getting supplies we made a pitch at the cafe for a light refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-12071.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Tende town centre&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to get diesel just south of Tende, while filling up we met a local driving an old Toyota Land Cruiser, 80 series I think, who we got chatting to about the tracks on the surrounding mountains. He gave us the low down and a few decent pointers including telling us about some closures due to land slides etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this new info we headed back towards Tende, where we planned to pick up the road Chemin Des Spegi towards Gite d&amp;#039;Etape which we entered through some sleepy back streets of the town, we then planned to continue up to eventually camp near or at Fort de la Marguerie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13361.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Colla Megiana&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assent to Gite d&amp;#039;Etape was slow it took about an hour to get to the top, most of the corners required at least a three point turn, in a 110 Defender. There seemed to be a never ending flow of hair pin bends. Chemin Des Spegi eventually turns into Chemin Muletier Des Spegi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roads up the mountain are gravel, which is a welcome change after about a thousand miles on Tarmac since leaving the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surroundings are initially sparse coniferous forest and dry grey rock. The forest eventually gives way to open rocky, green vast land scapes. Occasionally the roads are fringed by sections of granite wall, some with vast sheer drops. It is very easy to imagine military vehicles on the roads. Meeting one on the assent would certainly make for an interesting manuvoure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way up we noticed that the in-laws car was starting to over heat and loose a bit of coolant from the expansion tank. It appeared the low range work and slow speeds were not allowing the engine to keep cool, we noticed that the car was missing it&amp;#039;s thermostat. This it would seem, was a good time to have lunch, we managed to find a spot were we could put the cars into the wind, top up the coolant and have a nice shady lunch, near the turning for Colla Megiana. After the break we never did see the temperature of the Pajero rise again. Apart from the missing thermostat I wonder if there was an airlock or something in the system after the major service and the radiator flush we had just before departing on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13311.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Recovery Time&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;232&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued after lunch towards the fort along Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino. We had originally planned to do a longer route to the fort, but during the day we lost a fair amount of time. With time now cracking on and it being after three we decided to go for the shorter option, so at Baisse de Peyrafique we kept to the right. We had originally planned to go left and do a loop via Mount Paracouerta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16121.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping to the shorter route kept us on Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino, this took us along spectacular gravel road all the way to our camp at the Fort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the Fort to find another nice Landy from Germany pearched just where I had planned to camp, with the view you could hardly blame them. I had a look there was still room for us, so decided to ask if they would mind us joining them. They were fine with that, I guess they had no choice really, but I asked anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16331.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from Camp&#34; width=&#34;534&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17081.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Camping spot next to the Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually felt sorry for them, it was very pieceful before we arrived, at least we could not destroy there view!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We manoeuvred the vehicles in to position then, set our selves up for the night. It was still light enought to allow us to go and explore the fort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from the UK it was surprising that we were able to roam freely in the fort. It is clear that some do not respect the fort as much as we did, there was plenty of graphitti and rubbish inside the fort. We spent about an hour looking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17111.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Is it spooky?&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Proud of her self!&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17231.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Room 44&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-1733.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;On top of the fort&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17431.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;From the draw bridge to the court yard&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17391.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The draw bridge&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-18021.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our camp site&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from the camp was super. Stretching towards the Italian border and Fort Central, we could also see Tende far below and Fort Tabourde and Fort Pepin in the distance, giving an appetiser for what would be comming in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner we had a simple vegetable pasta, lots of beer and kept warm as the sun disappeared over the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-19131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Simple dinner&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the binoculars we were able to spy on the sheep and a lone hand gliding camper at Fort Central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to take an early night, but... At about 2300 we were woken by a load rusling and a bit of a commotion, we had made a &#34;school-boy&#34; error. We left the rubbish out in a black bag. This of course had been found by a fox who seemed a bit brave for the wild. Needless to say, our rubbish was everywhere and I was running round in my boxers chasing the rubbish and the fox! Half way down a mountain freezing in boxers is something I will always remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are on the subject of rubbish. I personally found it really appalling that the land scape was scarred  with toilet paper and other rubbish. If you take a dump, take the paper with you and be considerate where you dump. As they say take only photos and leave nothing but a foot print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow once we had delt with the rubbish and the fox, if was off to sleep for a pleasant but cold night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0956.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Central&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke to a spectacular view. After breakfast and coffee, we packed up and headed towards fort central. It was surprising again for us to be able to look around. We spent about an hour scouting around and then explored the track towards Fort Pepin. We found that the track was closed due to a land slide, apparently the local authorities do not have the budget to restore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coming to a dead end we headed down to Tende via another thousand hair pin bends, where we used the local pool for a shower and a very pleasant swim. We also got a few more supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0940.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Sentry Post&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0959.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#039;s here&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1009.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1029.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking back to The fort&#34; width=&#34;453&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1026.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Gun points&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1014.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Inner buildings&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1022.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking up from a lower floor&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1041.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Driving through&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFMk5wUW92VzhIaWs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;GPS Track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>