<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wild Camping on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/wild-camping/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wild Camping on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/wild-camping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 19 - Bunec to Beach Cove via Butrint</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 07:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140027.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a fairly ok nights sleep and woke early. We decided to avoid the breakfast spoken of last night as dinner was a little &#39;dodgy&#39;, for want of a better word. We opted for just a coffee instead. Outside our room we bumped into a lovely lady sitting with her grandson. She asked us where we were from and we told her, &#34;England, Brighton&#34;. She said she knew it and lived in Lewisham. She was on holiday with her family and investigating a business opportunity in Albania. I must add, she was Albanian. We chatted for a bit longer and then bid her farewell, we were off for that coffee.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being reinforced with a coffee, we headed out towards Butrint, we wanted to visit the Roman ruins there. After a long and hot drive, we arrived at the entrance car park to the ruins. Immediately we were accosted by a young urchin girl and her male companion. They demanded that we buy bracelets from them. Dan was in the firing line of their deluge and so we ended up buying a bracelet from the girl and one from the boy. By this time I had another little urchin at my window. She begged that I bought a bracelet from her too, I had to say no. The first young girl then came round to my window and asked if she could have my banana that I had sitting in the front. I laughed and had to admire her audacity. I gave her the banana. She immediately peeled it and ate it as she walked away, pleased at herself for getting another tourist in her trap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were now dripping and feeling a little hard done by, having been accosted by the urchins. We went for a cold drink at the restaurant before entering the sight. At the entrance to the ruins the prices were 700 LEK per foreign visitor, 500 LEK per foreign visitor in a group, 300 LEK for an Albanian visitor and 400 LEK for a child. So it was an entrance fee of 1,400 LEK and so we followed the cruise ship visitors that had just descended on the place by bus load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140030.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked around the remains. The signs at the entrance had said no smoking, walk on the path and beware the insects and snakes. The last bit made us hopeful we&#39;d see something other than roman ruins. We waited at the first part, an amphitheatre, for the hoards to disappear. Here Cassie discovered a turtle in the water around the ruins. From here we wondered around, skirting the crowds. It was extremely hot, and we were all dripping in sweat by the end. Afterwrds Dan and Cassie got themselves and ice cream and I got a can of cold Coca Cola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140071.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to head off and find a camp on the beach somewhere. Yesterday Dan had noticed that the radius arm bushes needed changing, especially if we wanted to tackle a few more gravel tracks during the holiday. We had seen plenty of &#39;Autoservis&#39; places along the road and so we went in search of one that could fit us in. We tried a few and they all pointed us to someone else as they were far to busy. Eventually on the way out of Butrint, we stopped at a small garage we had noticed on our way in. He was now quiet and Dan asked if he could do the work, it would only take 1 hour. The guy agreed. He spoke good english and so Dan changed into some shorts and negotiated the car above a pit. Cassie and I sat in the car trying not to expire, while Dan helped the guy change the bushes. All done for 2000 LEK. Luckily Dan had the spares in the car … Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were off now in search of a beach to stay on. They all looked packed and we could not find a turning to some. So, we decided to stop for lunch somewhere. We came across a little village and went to a restaurant. Here the owner spoke good english and we ordered lamb with a greek salad. The owner chafed to us about working on cruise ships and seeing the world, but how now he water to settle in Albania. We asked him about the ferries from Vlorë to Brindisi. He recommended going from Igoumenista instead and offered to let us use the internet to check fares.We thanked him and Dan did just that. The prices and info was not helpful as the ferry from Vlorë did not show up in the searches. We thanked the owner and hit the road once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0264.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we stopped at a little cove we had spotted on the way past yesterday. The water edge was lined with mobile homes, which we only assumed were stopping for the night. As we approached and stopped, a funny Albanian man came up to us and asked where we were from. We told him England and asked if it was ok to stay. He said sure no problem, just park. Dan asked if he wanted money, he said that wasn&#39;t necessary, we were his friends … we concluded he was a little strange and parked up anyway, changed into our kozzies, and went for a dip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130968.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0270.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0279.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie immediately spotted sea urchins in the water, so we tried to avoid these. Later on we spoke to a lady who had stood n one and was trying to get the poison out her toe. Cassie got the snorkel and mask out and did a little look see in the water. She stayed in for ages! All of a sudden there was a ruckus, some locals nearby had caught an octopus. They started throwing it onto the rocks whilst screaming and shouting. I found this really upsetting. Why not just kill it humanely and hopefully not as sport, but to take it back and eat it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we had been sitting on the beach, the wind had been building. We decided to set the tent up and head for the restaurant for dinner across the road from the bay. As we had eaten a big lunch, we decided to go for a snack type dinner … this didn&#39;t really happen. Dan ordered calamari and I the seafood spaghetti, Cas shared both. The wind was now quite strong. We wondered back to the tent and got ready for bed. Whilst we lay in the tent, we were whipped and bashed. Dan and I worried about it not being safe in the tent with the wind at this strength, so we gathered up our sleeping stuff, closed up the tent and bundled into the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a night of horror! I personally got NO sleep … Dan says he managed a wink or two and I think Cassie was the luckiest out of us all. She probably managed an hour or so. To say we woke early would be an understatement. We were up before 6, teeth brushed and outta there. We were the walking dead but we still headed for Vlorë to see how much it would be to catch the ferry to Brindisi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18 - Kepi i Kalas to Bunec via our Secret beach</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 07:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0254.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Being in a hotel last night meant getting away quickly was easy. We had a local style breakfast of feta, tomato, cucumber and bread. Washed down with a few coffees.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Our plan was to check out a beach I had found on Google earth that looked almost isolated due to the track you had to use to get to it. Due to the GPS problems I had circled it on the map. This meant it was another day heading to a circle. The drive to the beach took about an hour or so. We first had to negotiate some spectacular steep roads with tight hairpins over the surrounding mountains. The roads had various bits missing and loads of fallen rocks which claimed a few victims to punctures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130959.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The turning to the beach was immediately of the bottom of the steep decent. There had been a few attempts to grade it, but the track was pretty bad. On the was down we got held up by a truck rescuing an Italian mobile home who had been over ambitious. Both looked frustrated. The tow rope was in taters. The owner said something to me as we squeezed by. I promised to return with my tow strap and shackles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;By the time I had stopped 50 meters on and returned they appeared to on there way so I returned and we continued to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we got to the bottom we were delighted, we found an almost empty beach except for a couple of 4x4&#39;s and 2 or 3 like minded over landing campers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The beach was made up by sandy white pebbles. The top of the beach had a sand track which was easy to traverse. We headed most of the way along the track then turned down to the sea. Parking 10 meters from the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0253.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Here we swam in crystal clear water and lounged around for the morning. Cassie loved it. Spending most of the time checking out the fishies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on we decided to leave, I was a little apprehensive, as I had noted the sand and shingle made for horribly difficult driving. I had deflated the tyres a little and even in low diff lock, I struggled. I had to repeatedly reverse to get any momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My first attempt to get up the beach failed, I thought I had enough speed but could not get into low third without grinding to a halt and sinking. I stopped and let some more air out of the tyres and reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Foot to the floor I headed slightly back down towards the sea and managed to get some speed and into third. This allowed me to managed the engine speed and get enough velocity to get over the sand up to the slightly better surface to get off the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once I was back on the track at the top, I was hot! So we headed to a small makeshift bar a local had erected in the rock walls of the mountain that encapsulated the beach. I had a fanta and a beer to chill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had received we headed south to find a place to stay. We had again opted out of camping as we had no supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130983.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We eventually after some chaos ended up at a tiny restaurant at Bunec beach, which had rooms. The owning family lived in a tent. They were very nice and cooked us a traditional pasta dish and we drank loads of beer and swam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130990.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The rooms in these places are basic but functional and clean. We paid 30 euro with breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12- Sarajevo to Jablaničko Jezero via Lukomir</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/07/day-12-sarajevo-to-jablanicko-jezero-via-lukomir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 06:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/07/day-12-sarajevo-to-jablanicko-jezero-via-lukomir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So having spent the night in a hotel, which is fairly civilised for us, we got cracking early after a light breakfast. The plan for today was to find our way out of Sarajevo and head for the village of Lukomir. After which we would find some camping etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out of Sarajevo was easier said than done. The city has a one way system, we wanted to head out of the city to the southwest. For a start vaguely towards the airport and then end up on road 18. We only need to get out a few kilometers, to find the turn off to the roads in the mountains. But there was a surprising lack of signs indicating places and exits out of Sarajevo. You would expect for instance to see the airport sign posted or the next largest city. But there was nothing. Well nothing we could see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the city driving is fairly easy, there was a big circular oneway system around the centre, it takes about 10 minutes to go around. The previous day we did it several times, so by now we were experts. Once we got to the western end of the system we headed south over one of the bridges and eventually with a few missed turnings found our way out, with some amusement.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130773.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We needed a few supplies before we headed up to Lukomir, I was anticipating wild camping up on the mountains somewhere, as without decent scale maps or a working GPS I was a little vague on how exactly to get there or what to expect. The best map we had was a 1:200 Bosnia and Herzegovina map, which turned out to be totally inaccurate for the dirt roads. Anyway, conveniently there was a fuel station at the hotel and also conveniently at the turning off the main road was a tiny shop. Which meant we were now ready for anything ... sort of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we headed up off the main road towards Bjelašnica which is the local Ski resort, we climbed at first what seemed a fairly none descript dusty road past a load of industrial cement works (I think), beyond these as we continued up toward Bjelašnica, the road continued to become smaller and with occasionally broken tarmac. By comparison, with French and Swiss Ski resorts, Bjelašnica is tiny.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130801.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to follow the signs to the most easily accessible village of Umoljani. This is reasonably well sign posted and only involves a short section of dirt track to get to the village from Bjelašnica. What we found out was that if you approach from the other side, via Ozimine, is that you can do the whole route by tarmac, on very minor roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9916.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to get to Umoljani then try and find Lukomir. Which we thought would be a simple affair as the map shows a track to Lukomir and we also saw the occasional sign. But we where wrong, these just lead to Umoljani. After about 40 minutes or so, we decided to just follow a track we came across in the opposite direction to which we had been indicated. I think we had given up on the idea of Lukomir and just fancied doing a bit of exploring, I could see a zig-zag track going up what I think was Vlahinja, which looked like it could also turn out to be a good stop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130814.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after about 15 minutes we spotted a small sign indicating Lukomir so obediently turned as indicated by the sign. The track seemed to go on forever. But eventually after passing a few shepards and their flocks we could see houses in the distance. Just outside the village is a tourist sign, which tells the &#34;Story&#34; of the village, we parked there and went for a wander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9923.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that hits you is the smell of sheep manure, there were huge piles of it, setting the odour of the area, it was not unpleasant, just strong. As we passed the first houses on the track through the village, the old ladies of the houses shouted for us to buy some of there products, which they had hanging on the fence. The seemed to mainly be slippers made of wool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to wander along the track and we got to the water spring in the centre of the village, which in the heat, offered an opportunity to cool off. Here we saw there was a small wood sign indicating food, which lead us to a few tables outside a house. We sat down and tentatively asked for drink. Cassie had juice, I cheekily asked if they had beer ... I was in luck. The guy running the place stopped to have a drink too, he had been cutting wood. He was spending the summer up in the village with his mother, at his grandfather&#39;s house. He used to be a tram driver in Sarajevo, but having spent a year training he had been waiting for two years to get a new contract. This was an opportunity for him to earn some cash for the winter, in Sarajevo. He explained that not many people spend the winter on the mountains anymore, most opt to return to Sarajevo or lower towns for the cold months. We also learnt some of the villagers stories and how sometimes too many tourists can appear. Which seemed a shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later we purchased some slippers and grabbed some stuff out the car, so we could go for a short walk and have a picnic lunch. We found an excellent spot on a peak over looking the canyon beyond the village. During lunch we talked about what to do next, I had asked if we could camp nearby and the guy who gave us drinks said we could camp where we parked. Wendy was not comfortable with that, feeling like we were intruding. So we drove down from the mountain tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first we headed out the way we came, but spotted a sign to Vrdolje and opted to follow that a different was down. This would we hope lead us to a main road on which lies Konjic, which we thought would have camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tracks require a certain amount of faith. You&#39;ll pass loads of branches, and with no signs, we always opted to take what we fought was the continuation of the main route. Always what plays in you mind is mines, which are normally indicated and should not be a problem in the area we were in but, it just sits there. We were lucky we passed a man and he confirmed we were headed in the right direction and that we should just continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About an hour or so later we popped out on the main road, and looked for camping on Konjic. Which was fairly well sign posted. We had to pay a small 5 KM toll to take the road into the campsite, which considering it was 50m beyond the toll man was steep. We did not mind though. The campsite was basic, which we like, outdoor shower, lake to swim and a horrible toilet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked, grabbed a beer from the fridge and went to cool down in the lake. Later we popped into the restaurant in the site and had Ćevapi for dinner with several beers. All of these places have restaurants and being so cheap, we have been using them rather than cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Needed a lightweight stove</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 20:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, I needed to get a lightweight stove for a quick camping microadventure on Saturday night. I did not want to buy one and was considering self heating meals and no coffee in the morning. Until I found inspiration from a post on twitter to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/64726512&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Allen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to have a go at building my own also. I had some mentholated spirit for fuel, I just needed a drink can to make the stove. After a quick trip to the local shop, and with my thirst quenched I had my raw material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1013.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10131.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10132.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10133.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimmed the top and bottom sections. Bottom section is about 30mm high, the top is about 50mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2035.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20351.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creat flues in the side of the can with a knife. Small at the top. Large at the bottom. These form the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20352.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mate both sections&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20353.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ridges are critical. They are small at the top, large at the bottom. They form the fuel generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small hole using a pin just under the top lip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20354.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small amount of fuel, approx 5mm deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20355.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light, wait 10 seconds for fuel to heat in the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10134.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once hot the fuel vaporises in the side ridges, which is the generator the flames only burn on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10135.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about 5 minutes to boil two cups of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1012.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weights very little too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10121.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field test!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2007.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised by the stove, it had no trouble heating my dinner or boiling water in my coffee maker. Just keep it out of the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how these work. Check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beverage-can_stove&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 09:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastlane99.plus.com/&#34;&gt;Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just found this link via a reply to a &lt;a title=&#34;HUBB&#34; href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/europe/familly-friendly-4x4-tours-alps-70380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post on Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;. If your looking at exploring the tracks of the Alps. There some nice pictures on here from the early 2000&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit to the Map Shop - Stanfords</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 18:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/image.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves at a loose end this morning, the weather was iffy. So we took a pleasant ride into London for a wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are considering are plans for the summer so decided we&#39;d pop to the map shop in London. Those of you who don&#39;t know it. This is probably the best place to purchase maps and travel books in London. It has three floors of books and maps normally in the scale you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a Bradt Albania Guide, a 1:150k Kosovo map, 1:200k Albania map, 1:400 Bulgaria map and 1:500k Romania / Moldova map, the latter two are not ideal scales for what we need but they&#39;ll do. I&#39;ll probably get better scales if I can find them. Unfortunately I could not find a decent Macedonia map so had to resort to Amazon for that and a Kosovo and Macedonia guide book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance you should pop in, it is a pretty cool shop!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Stats - Summer 2012 Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In starting to consider this years plan, i thought i would post some recorded figures from last summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stats from our last trip from 27th July to the 26th August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We covered 3663.1 miles, about 5900 km.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used 606.42 litres of diesel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Averaged 27 miles per gallon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filled up 15 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid 26 tolls totalling 287.8 Euro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most expensive where for the Tunnel de Mont Blanc at 38.9 and tunnel de Frejus at 39.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used the channel tunnel for crossing the channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used a over night ferry from Bari to Dubrovnik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 night in a hotel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 attempted nights at a hotel night resulting in six police officers attending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 nights free camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 none catastrophic car part failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which do you want to know more about!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myway Serengeti 1.6m Roof Tent &amp; Boab Roof Bars</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 15:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-aug-2012-2004.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been trying to find the right sleeping solution for the three of us since, pretty much the first trip we ever went on. The problem we have always had is that we would prefer to be able to wild camp or free camp, but having a family tent made this almost impossible. Not to mention the time it takes to put up and take down a larger tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years that followed we moved onto two small back packing tents one for Cassie and one for us. A two and three man. The plan being in camp sites we use both, in the bush we use one. What we often found though, was that it was hard to find a decent spot for the Landy and a three man tent. If we were walking it would have been fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used the family tent for two years, then the small tents for about two years. We eventually slimmed our arsenal of tents down to the family tent, which will be sold this year, it was only kept for the in-laws on this last trip; the three man backpacking tent we will keep for walking and biking; Cassie&amp;#039;s pop up tent and now the latest addition is a roof tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this trip we took the pop up tent and the new roof tent. The plan being that we would all sleep in the roof tent in the wild, then at campsites we would use both tents to allow us to get a good nights sleep, without being kicked and punched by Cassie all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enquiries about purchasing the roof tent started about 6 or 7 weeks before we left. We were hoping to go and check one out, then get one shortly after. What ended up happening actually, was that we got really busy and were not able to get to a place to see one, it was quite a way. What also happened was that we had to wait for a delivery from Cape Town, South Africa by sea. Luckily we were able to secure one of the items which had already departed in the next batch to be delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-21-jul-2012-1525.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up paying a deposit and hoping the tents would not be delayed in customs. They were supposed to clear by the first week of July. We thought that would be perfect as we could get a couple of nights camping in to make sure everything was ok. Inevitably that did not happen as you would expect, nothing is that simple. We managed to get the tent the Friday before we left. Paul from Myway came down from Doncaster to fit it and train us! Which was a nice touch. Needless to say the tent is superb. One thing led to another and we were not able to get out camping that weekend, so would have to just wait till the actual trip. Fingers crossed everything would be ok! In the end we did manage to find time on the Southdowns to practice putting it up and down including the shower curtain. We also managed to get a few pictures of the process. The pictures below were taken in France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 1 - Position Car&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1716.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 2 - Remove Cover and Insert Ladder&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1718.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 3 - Close the Door and reach for the ladder!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17181.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 4 - Rotate about the hinge and open&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17182.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 5 - Remember something you forgot.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17183.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 6 - Position ladder and fit stays for the flysheet&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1720.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      And Relax!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1719.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spoken at length with Paul, we ended up with a Serengeti 1.6m tent, we had originally wanted to get an Evolution because it was lighter and not canvas and we wanted a 1.8m as it was wider. Paul assured us that the Serengeti was a good choice and that a 1.6 was plenty wide enough for us and Cassie. He was so confident that he assured me if we were not happy we&amp;#039;d sort &#34;something&#34; out! The man proved to know his stuff. The other advantage of the Serengeti was that the canvas would keep the light out in the morning. We found it easy to sleep till nine at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing this so far, I&amp;#039;ve missed a beat, in between paying a deposit and getting the tent I had to find a platform to mount the tent to on top of the Landy. I spent quite a lot of time trying to work out if I wanted a roof rack or roof bars. Roof tents in general are heavy. Myway tents are lighter than most, the 1.6m we were waiting for weighed in at circa 50kg. Most are about 20kg more, with some hitting the 90kg mark for family models. A decent roof rack is about 40 to 50kg, with the Landy and a lot of other cars rated at about 100kg for roof loads, I&amp;#039;d want the lightest mounting system possible. Roof bars are about 5kg approximately each. It seemed an obvious choice considering we did not need a rack at the moment and could do with saving some money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1550.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found various bars around, I wanted something sturdy though. Really because of the off roading factor and mounting the awning. I toyed with getting some boab / mantec bars, I forget what they are called, but dismissed that because I was not convinced they were robust enough for us. Boab also, did some other bars called Boab bars in a 40mm x 40mm or 40mm x 20mm section. I opted for the 40mm square option. I ordered three of these as I needed to mount my awning using u-bolts. This offered a significant weight and cost saving over a rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Construction and Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of construction the tent is made on an aluminium base frame which uses stainless brackets and bolts with aluminium rivets in places, this has a marine ply base attached via captive nuts and bolts. The base frame has a bolted stainless hinge arrangement on either side of the frame, this is the point at which the aluminium hoop tubes attach which support the main tent canvas. The canvas hangs on the hoops, this allows the fly sheet to lay over the top of the whole arrangement. This leaves about a 40 or 50mm gap between the inner tent and flysheet, depending on how the two are adjusted. This gap allows plenty of airflow and is probably a contributing factor to the lack of condensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canvas inner tent is coated with a waterproofing agent, as is the flysheet. With this coating the canvas is free from the normal leaks you get on the first outing. This did not mean we escaped unscathed. We suffered a small amount of leaking on the first night due to the fly sheet being incorrectly adjusted and hanging on the inner canvas, it was a very minor leak and we did not see the issue again after we adjusted and experimented a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tent is delivered with about a 40mm sponge mattress and a fitted green sheet. The foam is covered in nylon so you need the sheet. The mattress cover is arranged such that it hindges in the middle and folds flat when the tent is packed away. We found the mattress fairly soft, so was easy to feel the base underneath, it took a little getting used to. We tended not to notice so much when we slept in sleeping bags in colder climates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to leave some bedding in the tent when it is packed away, but it must be folded flat before the tent is folded. It should be left on the fixed half of the tent. Failure to fold the bedding flat will result in it bunching when the tent is put away and putting extra strain on the hinge, which could lead to failure of the hinge if excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights we did discover one issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design. The cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically linked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in the two plywood base halves. In order to remedy this we will be installing some locating pegs, which will actually be formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the underside of the folding half of the tent a channel is mounted to the base. This allows the addition of a &#34;shower curtain&#34; which is essentially three sides of a walled room with no ground sheet and a small cut out for the ladder, the Landy forms the fourth wall. The ladder is outside the room. We tried this briefly on the Downs but never used this on the trip. The way we have the tent mounted means that it would provide shelter at the back of the Landy into the rear door during inclement weather, with the door open. The additional kit comes in a small bag, so is light enough to carry around. I just never want to have to use it. It takes 2 or 3 minutes to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appart from the minor niggle above, we had a great time with the Serengeti this holiday. We enjoyed the quick set up and pack away times. Wendy and I got quite a good routine established that meant we could put our feet up quicker and be on the road sooner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of the quick set up time means it gives more confidence for camping discreetly as it can be set up at dusk and packed away at dawn when no one is around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of quality, the construction is excellent and modular, so if something needs changing it can be and would be fairly simple, probably without having to go to Myway for spares. The only thing I would pick up Myway (the factory) on is the construction process. We found a lot of swarf in the tent and on the aluminium components. This was because the components are drilled during assembly, rather than drilled cleared and then assembled. It would not be hard to fix this process issue and would save some customer annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short I would not be able to compare against other roof tents as I have not had the chance to look at them, but I can say with confidence that the Myway Serengeti 1.6 meter is an excellent buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Jafferau and Lago Di Rochemolles</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1220.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125197.9639&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track Up To Fort Jafferau &#34; width=&#34;417&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After spending the night at &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/&#34;&gt;Fort Pramond&lt;/a&gt;, we had a plan today to driver up to Mount Jafferau then on to a nearby Lake that is now a reservoir, we were hoping to spend the night by the river there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to pack up fairly promptly and were on the way by the time the day was heating up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-0911.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125203.729&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Exit of the exciting tunnel&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was kind of excited about the day, because we were heading along a track that showed a cool tunnel on the map. I dunno how I came to that conclusion,  just by looking at the map. The tunnel on the track is circa 800 meters long, unlit, unpaved and leaks more than you would see in a normal road tunnel as it is not lined. This leak leads to a stream of water in the tunnel that is often a few inches deep. Oh and the end never seemed to appear, leading to a further sense of excitement under the dim light of the Landys head lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1213.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125156.5093&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Jafferau&#34; width=&#34;358&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The other thing about the day that excited me was the climb to the Fort on Mount Jafferau, this sits at circa 2800 meters and promises spectacular views. We were not let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Most of the track up to Jafferau is easy in a 4 x 4, I am not sure how far you&amp;#039;d want to go in a ordinary car. There are some fairly rocky sections, not hard but difficult in most cars. If the weather was bad, you would not consider it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the way up to Mount Jafferau, we were listening on the CB to other people that we could not see. We could hear that they were watching us, as they were mentioning the English vehicles. Even with the aid of the binoculars we could not see who was watching us and nor could we find them. It was rather creepy being in a valley, with all the ex military sites and the creepy night we had the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The track we were following stopped at Jafferau... Sort of. We had a plan to asses the situation at the end. This was because we had a map that showed a 500 meter foot path then the start of a new track down the other side of Mount Jafferau. Well when we got there we found that there was a track down, that was fairly steep and circa 1000m descent. Linking the track up and the track down was actually the easy bit. We did the whole descent in low range 1st gear, but had to occasionally slow the descent a little on top. It was great because we were following the Ski run literally, so naturally this led to us arriving at the top of the bubble lift and at the restaurant at the top of the lift. A convenient place to stop for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1311.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125181.358&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Nice Lunch Stop&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel had a double helping of home made Lasagne, made by the Owners Wife and Wendy and I had a local platter of meats and cheeses. After a good fill. We carried on our descent, we had about another thousand meters to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed down towards Bardonecchia to pick up the track to take us up to the Lake for the next night. Unfortunately we found the/a track but could not find our way onto the one we wanted that led to the lake. We ended up back tracking and taking a scenic road that met up with the track we needed. The track was really easy and fairly pleasant if busy. You could have done this section in a car. Apart from going to the actual camping spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1546.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125152.4119&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Valley of Lago di Rochemolles &#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;107&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The road continues on from where we camped to one of the highest glaciers you can drive to in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1702.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125163.2832&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Refreshing Bath&#34; width=&#34;341&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We stopped for the evening at the river that feeds Lago di Rochemolles, it was obviously icy cold, but was great for a very invigorating bath and cooling some Prosecco. The valley was very scenic and a great stop for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1704.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125195.692&#34; class=&#34;alignnone&#34; alt=&#34;Cutting Wood&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;263&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we had a proper fire in a pit made by some predecessors, we managed to find enough wood nearby and an old sauce pan to warm water for washing up. Dinner that night was slightly left field. We had failed to stop for more supplies since our last supermarket stop, we had some powdered soup from Croatia. This was very nice, I think it was called Dalmation soup.... We also had three military ration packs, which had been given to us by John in Cinque terra. Our plan was to enjoy these as pudding after we had the roast potatoes. Unfortunately being military ration novices what we cooked for pudding was awful. I feel for the boys who eat them, this looked off. So we ended up going to bed a bit hungry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Update: I have since learnt that the packs last for 10 years. Sorry John. If you are reading this John, we lost your email address, hope you had a cool trip. It was great having a BBQ with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-2043.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125179.4502&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Girls Washing up.&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;233&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping by a stream led to a lot of night time pees. In the morning we woke stinking of smoke. Had breakfast and headed for the road. It was here, well in Bardonecchia we would say bye for a few days to Carole and Daniel. Obviously we did this over coffee and pastries. They were heading to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-17021.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125165.5713&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our Spot&#34; width=&#34;363&#34; height=&#34;272&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We from hear ambled our way via a few one night stops home, as usual once we got half way up France the heavens opened and we just headed back to the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fort Pramand, Mount Pramand Overnight</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 08:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1825.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394770.2654&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Pramand&#34; width=&#34;388&#34; height=&#34;291&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since leaving the Plitvička national park, in Croatia where we visited the former top secret airbase of &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/&#34;&gt;Zeljava&lt;/a&gt; we made our way to Fort Pramand, which was the next area we planned to do some off-road exploring, near Oulx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394854.0425&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Drinking Prosecco&#34; width=&#34;306&#34; height=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt; On the way we stopped in Slovenia at the Bovec national park to chill out for a day or so, around the beautiful mountains and river Soča, we seem to like that area and always have a good time exploring. We also stopped in Revine, which is near Connegliano in Italy, the area famous for Prosecco sparkling wine. We obviously had to grab a box from a vineyard. The main reason for stopping here though was to use it as a gateway to Venice. There is an intercity train that will take you straight into Venice main station. That&amp;#039;s another story though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After this we travelled towards Oulx, barring another one night stop at Lago Maggiore. Oulx is one of the nearest towns to where we had planned to head up to the tracks I had researched. So the original plan was to stock up with and food, water and beer we needed then go. Oulx has a few official camp sites in the immediate vicinity, should you need a base to explore from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;But the Landy had other ideas. I had noticed that on occasion with increasing frequency, that the battery voltage was creeping up to the point of potentially over charging the batteries. This was concerning, as apart from potentially screwing up my expensive new batteries it was likely to mean we could not depend on them when we were off the beaten track. Luckily when we stopped in Oulx, we had a fiddle with the alternator which was fairly new as I uprated it a few months earlier and found that some of the terminals must have either worked loose or built up a resistance on the regulator sensing connection. This obviously led to the regulator over exciting the alternator giving a high output voltage. It was interesting because none of the connections were noticeably loose. It has been fine since. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1448.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394803.1416&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;On the up&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So now the beer could be kept cool we headed up to the mountain tracks, via the main road that runs parallel to the E70 motorway, I think it is the ss n 24 headed east we took the left that leads up past Fort Fenils. However the excitement was not over! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As we started to ascend we suddenly noticed a strong smell of smoke and soon came to some mountain fire trucks, police and lots of people. It was a forest fire approaching the road, we were lucky though they guided us past. The road is tarmac for a few kilometres on the way up before it turns to easy gravel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Next the Pajero which Carole and Daniel were driving started to overheat! So we had to stop shortly after hitting gravel for lunch. Luckily to get to Fort Pramand we did not have far to go so, time was on our side. You&amp;#039;d think that was the end of the drama though surely. Luckily the next incident started as we approached the fort. The Pajero decided that the automatic transmission oil indicator would light, suggesting it was overheating. We guessed it was because of the low range work and slow speed, not helped probably by the earlier overheat. Oh well it would get a chance to cool overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1629.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394765.179&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tracks up&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The tracks up to Fort Pramand are easy, until you get to the last bit leading up to the Fort, which is a turn off from the main track anyhow. The track narrows because of trees either side that lean towards the center of the track. The ground has a few large roots to climb. It is not to bad in a small or low 4x4, but with the root tent on the Landy it was a little tricky, we clipped a corner of the tent lightly. Just a scuff mark no damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The Fort itself is fairly big, but in a very poor state of repair it sits at 2162 meters, there are various warnings spray painted on the walls warning of Danger. The roof is in a poor state of repair. I suspect it has had a few vehicles on its roof. You can walk onto it by following the track up, the view is excellent from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1746.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394771.471&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner&#34; width=&#34;356&#34; height=&#34;475&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we settled up there and started to cook and set ourselves up for the night it started to feel a bit spooky. The girls were convinced it was haunted. Especially when something took exception to Wendy&amp;#039;s singing. For some reason after we all told her not to quit her day job, and that she did no justice to Black Betty, the radio in the car came on and started blaring!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We had a nice dinner which was made even better with the red wine we got from Connegliano to season it. Shortly after the clouds rolled in so we disappeared for what we thought would be a peaceful night. However with the girls convinced we were being watched by spooky ghosts, Wendy woke a few times to noises, saying she felt like someone was climbing the ladder to the roof tent. She then woke me up because she was too scared to go to the toilet! The conversation went along the lines of.... &#34;Do you need a pee. no. Can you come with me. Do I have too. Yes. Well I am not going twice get Cassie, we&amp;#039;ll have a family pee.&#34; Needless to say. There was no ghost waiting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1754.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394800.108&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Setup&#34; width=&#34;366&#34; height=&#34;275&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With hind sight I guess being parked with the ladder right against the Fort, between two very dark portals was probably adding to the girls apprehension. In the morning Carole got out of the tent having had no sleep, because she was also convinced ghost soldiers were marching across their tent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After breakfast we left a little tired and headed for Mount Jafferau, via a cool tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;If you want to download the GPS track from this post and the next you can download it here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiloc.com/wikiloc/view.do?id=3261982&#34;&gt;Wikiloc&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/view_trip.php?trip_id=1741579&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Everytrail&#34;&gt;Everytrail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Feel free to leave a comment if you want to know more. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Col Linaire, Col de Sanson, Pas de Colle Ardente - Mount Saccarel</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871723104_817a4bd793.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;The next track&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;282&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After finishing up on Col de Tende we headed back down to the town of Tende for supplies and to freshen up at the local piscine (swimming pool) (If only they had known!), before we departed for the second section of our little off road trip. Again we planned to stay at least one night up on the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The local chap at the fuel station we met the day before, had been correct about Col de la Boaïra being block from the Fort Central end, so we decided to heed his advice again and took his recommended entry point to the next pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With a plan in place, we kicked off by heading south from Tende fully refreshed and clean towards St Dalmas de Tende, where we turned left to head east on the D43 past La Brigue. This took us to the turning for the D143 on the right that allowed us to get to what would be the start of our next off road excursion at Notre-Dame des Fontaines. Apparently this is worth a stop to have a look, we did not take the opportunity unfortunately but will next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed straight up towards Col Linaire, which would take us up through the forest &#34;Bois Du Pinet&#34; along what seemed considerably more dusty gravel tracks than the day before. On the way up we passed an old Willis Jeep heading down, the driver, his dog and Family looked local and to be having a great time. I guess the old Williss is ideal for adhoc dog walking on your local mountain. What an awesome playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Given the time we left Tende after our swim and restock, it was not long, probably 8 km from the church until we decided we would stop for a light lunch. We stopped at a 5 point junction that offered to easily get us lost. Luckily it was easy to work out the exit we needed, after removing the closed piste and the exit we arrived from! The junction on the map is at &#34;Cime du Pinet&#34;, which is the Top of the Pinet hill. There were various logs lying around for us to sit on to enjoy lunch. There must be a certain amount of forestry undertaken, perhaps to control the fire risk? While we were there another car was parked up with a local who had just gone mountain biking, he did not seem so friendly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871721608_6d3de535d8.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Forest Roads&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After having lunch we continued up the fourth exit... Towards Col du Loup, this continued through the Forêt Communale de la Brigue it was great driving through the forests, they provided a welcome break from the heat. As we were driving up, I was conscious that although we had enough water to last us easily for at least two nights, we did not have a lot spare, so was keeping an eye open for a source that would allow is to fill the solar shower and water carrier. At this time of the year there did not seem to be many streams around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/7871715168_50ec94991d_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Topping up with water&#34; width=&#34;227&#34; height=&#34;302&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily we happened upon a water trough that was reasonably full. The water looked clean enough for the intended purposes and had a steady flow into it, which meant it was not stagnant. We filled up the shower and most of the carrier. But it was a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14236.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Border marker&#34; width=&#34;339&#34; height=&#34;254&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After getting water, our final re-supply item we continued up to the border area to Col de Sanson / Baisse de Sanson. The next section hugs what I think is the 1947 border of France and Italy, it was fairly spectacular along the ridge or the south east side of Mont de Colle Ardente for the first 5 km or so, then the track pops over the top for the next roughly 6 km along the north west side of Mont Saccarel, I think this is Pas de colle Ardente or part of. This leads into Pas du Tanarel which will have you emerge on the eastern side of Mont Tanarel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15323.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track to Mont Saccarel &#34; width=&#34;322&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It is about 2 km south of this point you have the option to proceed down towards San Bernardo and off the mountain or as we did proceed towards Mont Saccarel which is at 2200 meters. Mont Saccarels&amp;#039; summit overlooks a 12 meter statue of Jesus, that was placed there is 1901. The statue has a fantastic view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we stayed on Mont Saccarel, just below the summit which had the remains of some old fortifications. When we arrived at the summit there were some local Italians having a braai, that had driven up in there 4x4&amp;#039;s. We parked above them on the summit and decided to walk to have a look at the statue, it was about 1 km walk and would allow us time to see what the local chaps did. As it goes they disappeared shortly after we started our stroll. So after taking some photos of us and the Jesus statue we wondered back and pitch camp where they had been. Our camp straddled the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-17542.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from the summit&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-16451.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Jesus Statue&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1646.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Group shot&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we used some of the water we collected on the way up, to boil up some pasta and washing up water, no one had the trotts in the morning so needless to say the water was fine. We had a hearty vegetable pasta dish for dinner followed by beer! The rest of the evening was spent admiring the changing view in the evening light and listening to the distant cattle grazing it&amp;#039;s way across the slopes below. Once the sun had gone down we went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night I got up to look at the stars (have a pee) which were almost blinding due to the lack of light pollution, in the distance far below us there was the orange clusters of street lights in local towns and villages. I spent a few minutes admiring until the cold got to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the morning, we woke to a definite chill as you&amp;#039;d expect from a clear night at that height, the morning was glorious and I could not wait to see the view first from inside the warm shelter of the tent, then while I enjoyed the warmth of a warm fresh coffee. There was a problem though, I first had to go for a climb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night we had visitors... My flip flop had gone for a walk, only one. So armed with one of Wendy&amp;#039;s on my once bare foot, I dug out the binoculars and eventually far below I spotted the outline of my black flip flop in the rocks and shrubs. Off I trekked to get it, shortly after I put the kettle on. On recovery of my flop, I was suspicious, apart from some sizeable teeth marks, there was also a fairly stinky deposit of what I think was pee. I suspect a fox or something decided to mark it&amp;#039;s territory on my flop flip. I promptly returned to camp to deal with the situation, both proud and puzzled. By this time the kettle was boiling and with my now clean flop, we enjoyed our coffee and I pondered the curious event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My flip flops will live another summer by the looks of things, I guess the wife&amp;#039;s did not smell nice enough for our visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-3-aug-2012-0659.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Solar shower&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having fed ourselves and packed up, we freshened up under the solar shower, the moon had little effect on it&amp;#039;s temperature thou, so it was rather refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We then headed down the track we arrived on before turning off down the mountain towards San Bernardo for a coffee, before we headed for Cinque Terre our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFNXBiaFM5VFBnSmM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Gps track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1528.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The road down&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1755.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Panoramic from summit&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;165&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baisse d&#39;Ourne, Col de Tende - Fort de la Marguerie, Fort Central</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning we woke at our Campsite in Barolo in Italy early, the plan was to get to Tende in France, stock up on supplies at the super market, fill up with diesel, grab some petrol for the stove and head up to Col de Tende. We did fairly well and managed to have breakfast, coffee and pack up to be on the road by 0920 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-10201.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tunnel de Tende&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;296&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the minor back roads from Barolo to enter France via the Tunnel de Tende, on the SS20/N204. The tunnel was interesting in that it was only open one way at a time. We arrived at the back end of a line going our way, so decided to stop at the restaurant by the tunnel for a coffee and a pastry. That also gave us the opportunity to investigate the oil pressure light that was coming on in the in-laws car. We found nothing that would explain the light... Kicking the tyres did the trick thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tende is a picturesque town, that has houses perched on top of one another, we found a supermarket on the main drag, which was conveniently located next to a souvenir shop followed by a cafe. After getting supplies we made a pitch at the cafe for a light refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-12071.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Tende town centre&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to get diesel just south of Tende, while filling up we met a local driving an old Toyota Land Cruiser, 80 series I think, who we got chatting to about the tracks on the surrounding mountains. He gave us the low down and a few decent pointers including telling us about some closures due to land slides etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this new info we headed back towards Tende, where we planned to pick up the road Chemin Des Spegi towards Gite d&amp;#039;Etape which we entered through some sleepy back streets of the town, we then planned to continue up to eventually camp near or at Fort de la Marguerie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13361.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Colla Megiana&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assent to Gite d&amp;#039;Etape was slow it took about an hour to get to the top, most of the corners required at least a three point turn, in a 110 Defender. There seemed to be a never ending flow of hair pin bends. Chemin Des Spegi eventually turns into Chemin Muletier Des Spegi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roads up the mountain are gravel, which is a welcome change after about a thousand miles on Tarmac since leaving the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surroundings are initially sparse coniferous forest and dry grey rock. The forest eventually gives way to open rocky, green vast land scapes. Occasionally the roads are fringed by sections of granite wall, some with vast sheer drops. It is very easy to imagine military vehicles on the roads. Meeting one on the assent would certainly make for an interesting manuvoure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way up we noticed that the in-laws car was starting to over heat and loose a bit of coolant from the expansion tank. It appeared the low range work and slow speeds were not allowing the engine to keep cool, we noticed that the car was missing it&amp;#039;s thermostat. This it would seem, was a good time to have lunch, we managed to find a spot were we could put the cars into the wind, top up the coolant and have a nice shady lunch, near the turning for Colla Megiana. After the break we never did see the temperature of the Pajero rise again. Apart from the missing thermostat I wonder if there was an airlock or something in the system after the major service and the radiator flush we had just before departing on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13311.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Recovery Time&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;232&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued after lunch towards the fort along Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino. We had originally planned to do a longer route to the fort, but during the day we lost a fair amount of time. With time now cracking on and it being after three we decided to go for the shorter option, so at Baisse de Peyrafique we kept to the right. We had originally planned to go left and do a loop via Mount Paracouerta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16121.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping to the shorter route kept us on Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino, this took us along spectacular gravel road all the way to our camp at the Fort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the Fort to find another nice Landy from Germany pearched just where I had planned to camp, with the view you could hardly blame them. I had a look there was still room for us, so decided to ask if they would mind us joining them. They were fine with that, I guess they had no choice really, but I asked anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16331.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from Camp&#34; width=&#34;534&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17081.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Camping spot next to the Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually felt sorry for them, it was very pieceful before we arrived, at least we could not destroy there view!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We manoeuvred the vehicles in to position then, set our selves up for the night. It was still light enought to allow us to go and explore the fort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from the UK it was surprising that we were able to roam freely in the fort. It is clear that some do not respect the fort as much as we did, there was plenty of graphitti and rubbish inside the fort. We spent about an hour looking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17111.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Is it spooky?&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Proud of her self!&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17231.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Room 44&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-1733.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;On top of the fort&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17431.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;From the draw bridge to the court yard&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17391.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The draw bridge&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-18021.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our camp site&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from the camp was super. Stretching towards the Italian border and Fort Central, we could also see Tende far below and Fort Tabourde and Fort Pepin in the distance, giving an appetiser for what would be comming in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner we had a simple vegetable pasta, lots of beer and kept warm as the sun disappeared over the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-19131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Simple dinner&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the binoculars we were able to spy on the sheep and a lone hand gliding camper at Fort Central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to take an early night, but... At about 2300 we were woken by a load rusling and a bit of a commotion, we had made a &#34;school-boy&#34; error. We left the rubbish out in a black bag. This of course had been found by a fox who seemed a bit brave for the wild. Needless to say, our rubbish was everywhere and I was running round in my boxers chasing the rubbish and the fox! Half way down a mountain freezing in boxers is something I will always remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are on the subject of rubbish. I personally found it really appalling that the land scape was scarred  with toilet paper and other rubbish. If you take a dump, take the paper with you and be considerate where you dump. As they say take only photos and leave nothing but a foot print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow once we had delt with the rubbish and the fox, if was off to sleep for a pleasant but cold night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0956.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Central&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke to a spectacular view. After breakfast and coffee, we packed up and headed towards fort central. It was surprising again for us to be able to look around. We spent about an hour scouting around and then explored the track towards Fort Pepin. We found that the track was closed due to a land slide, apparently the local authorities do not have the budget to restore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coming to a dead end we headed down to Tende via another thousand hair pin bends, where we used the local pool for a shower and a very pleasant swim. We also got a few more supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0940.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Sentry Post&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0959.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#039;s here&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1009.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1029.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking back to The fort&#34; width=&#34;453&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1026.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Gun points&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1014.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Inner buildings&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1022.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking up from a lower floor&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1041.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Driving through&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFMk5wUW92VzhIaWs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;GPS Track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>