<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Summer 2010 on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/categories/summer-2010/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Summer 2010 on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/categories/summer-2010/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Teplice nad Metuji to Adrspach - Czech Republic</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/19/teplice-nad-metuji-to-adrspach-czech-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 20:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/19/teplice-nad-metuji-to-adrspach-czech-republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;While we where in the Czech Republic in August 2010, during our summer holidays we stayed in Teplice Nad Metuji, this is part of a National Park around the Adrspach area, and is a very nice place to visit and walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The park its self is home to sandstone formations that have been paired with famous monuments and people in name, it covers 17 km square in the Bohemia area of the Northern Czech Republic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;All the trails are really well marked out and walking maps are easily available we had a 1:16000 map which was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-171&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/teplice-walk.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;426&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;You can see the route overview by clicking this link &lt;a title=&#34;The route on Everytrail&#34; href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/view_trip.php?trip_id=783942&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Teplice to Adrspach walk at EveryTrail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080861.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080869.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080883.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080886.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080891.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080894.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080893.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080898.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080903.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080913.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080914.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080916.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080922.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080937.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080941.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080945.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080958.JPG&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more info &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adr%C5%A1pach-Teplice_Rocks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 17 - 19: 23 - 25 AUGUST, Ĉeský Krumlov – Home....</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/26/day-17-19-23-25-august-cesky-krumlov-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/26/day-17-19-23-25-august-cesky-krumlov-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Ĉeský Krumlov – Regensburg (Pielenhofen, Germany)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: €20.70 – 1 night. 50c for shower.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today was the earliest and quickest we have broken camp so far! We were up, packed and on the road by 8.30am! We parked in one of the tourist car parks and walked into town. We thought it was a very pretty place but it must get extremely busy because as we sat down for coffee and cakes, troops of tourists were already walking past us. We were off and on the road by 10am. We will try and make it into Germany today for another 1 nighter. The car has developed a strange noise that is worrying Dan. He investigated the noise last night, but found nothing. What could it be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decide to stop at Penny Markt to do some shopping, something that we have been a bit lax about. Perhaps this time it’s because we’ve had Pete around for the majority of the trip?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We finally, after a long search, found a camp site. Dan immediately set about searching for the source of the noise. He thinks it’s the drive shaft pinion bearing, broken perhaps when he changed it back at home? We texted a friend back in the U.K to see if they could look up a Land Rover garage near where we were staying. The camp site didn’t have wifi so we couldn’t do it ourselves. Dan set about removing the rear prop shaft, putting the car into diff lock to see if that stopped the noise. To top the night off, Wendy ended up pouring boiling water over her hand and sitting with it in iced water for the rest of the evening. Going to bed with burn gel all over her hand. What a way to end a wonderful holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;There isn’t a garage near us either, what do we do? Limp home on the diff or go to a garage and risk getting stranded for days?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After a discussion, we decided a limp home it would be. Constant speed. not up and down or fast. Just try cover good distance and then stop. Maybe do as much as possible distance wise today, heading for Belguim. To make it even worse, for Wendy, her hair dryer blew up too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Lets hope things get better…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090081.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 18: 24 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Pielenhofen (Germany) – Niederbreitbach (Germany)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: €15.00 – 1 night. €1 for a shower&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What a day! We have made it to Koblem, then we couldn’t find a camp site! It was a LONG day in the car, we drove right up till 6.30pm. Finally, we found a camp site past Koblem in Niederbreitbach. A small town in the Westerwald Nature reserve. We decided to stay for 1 night as there was nothing to see in the town. We set up camp and went to find a restaurant for dinner. We found a restaurant owned by a married couple. We happened to be their only customers apart from a private party in the ‘smoking room’. Another early night. We decided that we deserved a lie in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 19: 25 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Niederbreitbach (Germany) – Hove (U.K)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We tried to find our way onto the A61 to navigate ourselves into Belguim. We ended up crossing the Rhein at Linz on a lovely little car ferry. It cost €3 and took about 5 minutes to cross. Was a lovely little detour. We decided to go as far as possible again today and catch the ferry home tomorrow. That way, Dan can get the car sorted before we go back to school and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Change of plan!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We are now making it all the way to Calais to catch the ferry and try to make it home today. The unfortunate thing about this, is technically, we have now lost a week of our holiday by making our way home early. Oh well, Germany will still be there next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the way home from Dover, the heavens opened. Dan had to stop and “hot wire” the headlight wires so we had light to drive home in. It was yet another interesting journey in Tusky. The sunroof leaked so much, that Wendy had to don her rain jacket to stop getting soaked. Finally home and back to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090085.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090087.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;If you are interested in the route we took, you can download a gps track file &lt;a title=&#34;2010 GPS GPX File&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFeUkwM1F5bUZTUnVBNlFZRFhLa0tnZw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 16: 22 AUGUST,Teplice nad Metuji – Ĉeský Krumlov</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/23/day-16-22-augustteplice-nad-metuji-cesky-krumlov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 16:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/23/day-16-22-augustteplice-nad-metuji-cesky-krumlov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We woke early today. Breaking camp and packing up was easier with our wonderful new tents. Today we are off to Ĉeský Krumlov, stopping along the way at the Church of Bones in Kostince near Kutná Hora. We were traffic lucky today and made it to Kostnice in good time. The church is the outcome of an estimated 40 000 to 70 000 peoples bones used to decorate the church. The church is said to be a reminder of our humanity, that without redemption we cannot enter heaven. It was an extremely interesting place. We bought some souvenirs and headed out looking for lunch. We set off after lunch for Ĉeský Krumlov. It turns out that Cassie has gained a wobbly tooth..oh the woes of being a child. We went through Ĉeský Budějove, home of Budweiser, on our way to Ĉeský Krumlov. Not much to write home about really. The outskirts of Ĉeský Krumlov looked a bit like a building site. We drove through and found a campsite on the outskirts of Ĉeský Krumlov. The camp we found was in a solar farm, very bizarre. We paid for only 1 night as we were unsure if we wanted to stay or not. What we ended up deciding on was having dinner in the camp restaurant, breaking cmp early and heady off into Ĉeský Krumlov for breakfast so that we could beat the tourists and still see the town. We sat outside and ate our dinner under candle light..romantic? Not really, we couldn’t see what it was we were eating! Another early night, this time with an alarm wake up for 7am so we could make town for breakfast and head off in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080995.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090024.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090038.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090044.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1090045.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 14/15: 20/21 AUGUST  Martin (Slovakia) – Teplice nad Metuji (Czech Republic)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/22/day-1415-2021-august-martin-slovakia-teplice-nad-metuji-czech-republic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 16:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/22/day-1415-2021-august-martin-slovakia-teplice-nad-metuji-czech-republic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: 560 Crowns – 2 nights = €23.00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After an initial hiccup of taking the wrong exit and having to do a big loop, we finally made our way to the Czech. Unfortunately for us the road was VERY slow going. Not a motorway, still a major road, but FULL of trucks and slow moving vehicles making it a long journey. We stopped at 12pm for lunch and a drink, but we were still stuck at about 2pm in a traffic jam with still roughly 90km to go till we get to Adršpach. The traffic was driving us crazy, so we deviated off onto smaller roads. Turned out to be a wise decision and we finally made it to a camp site in Teplice nad Metuji. It was a lovely, quiet camp site. We found a nice quiet spot and set about putting up the new tents. They went up in no time! A HUGE difference from the other tent.We had managed to find a supermarket and cash machine along the way. More ‘funny money’ to get used to. We bought pasta for dinner tonight as we already had bits and bobs to turn it into a feast. We had our pasta with some toast made from the bread that needed to be finished. Wasn’t the best meal, but it wasn’t the worst either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080861.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080862.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080865.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 15: 21 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan discovered some maps for the area. The guy at the office said that we could catch the train to Adršpach. We decided to catch the train there and walk back. When we got to the station we discovered that Dan got the times wrong. We changed our plan and instead walked to Adršpach and caught the train back. It was a magnificent walk. You had to pay to get into the National Reserve – 150 Crowns for 2 adults and 1 child. The walk took us through forest, over peat bogs, up steps over the rocks and down steps into the rocks. Overall, we walked for 3 &amp;amp; half hours. Casie did amazingly well considering in some places the steps were so steep and precarious Dan had to carry her! After a good 12mile walk, we finally reached the end. Here we treated ourselves to some chips. We got some souvenirs for Cassie’s friends. We found the train station and awaited our train back to town. Once back at the camp site, we washed and headed out to find some dinner. We had some local food and drank some Czech white wine. We headed back to camp for an early night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080894.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080903.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080925.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080941.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080952.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 13: 19 AUGUST, Vodńa Nádž (Voklav, Slovakia) – Martin (Slovakia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/20/day-13-19-august-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia-martin-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 16:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/20/day-13-19-august-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia-martin-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Hotel cost: €80 double room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Up at the normal time, packed up and made tracks for Martin. Not too much of a journey today thankfully. We reached Martin at about 2pm and parked up to look for a hotel/B&amp;amp;B. We managed to find a B&amp;amp;B, but it happened to be a 4* hotel. A decision was made to stay for the night. For a 4* hotel, the room were pretty undistinguishable and there was no air conditioning. At this point Cassie had decided to go up to the rooms with Pete and did not tell us where she had gone. I had been at the car getting clothes and Dan had been sorting out the payment and did not see her go with Pete. We were both in an absolute panic! The receptionist saw this and simply stood there looking at us! I mean, she did absolutely nothing and when we asked her to call Pete’s room she simply said “I already have, there’s no answer”, Dan was starting to loose his temper and asked her to try again. That was it for me, the hotel dropped all it’s 4* in my eyes thanks to their receptionists disgusting behaviour. I decided to go up to the rooms to look for her whilst Dan stayed downstairs. I managed to find her with Pete. Phew! Panic over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We dumped our stuff in the room and went off out into town for a beer and snack. The beers in Slovakia are strong, 12%, needless to say this loosened Dan up and he declared “Lets go buy a tent!”. Martin seemed to have many camping and outdoor extreme sports stores. He had been saying for ages that he wanted us to have 2 smaller tents for these trips and the big tent for camping back home. So what happened? We ended up buying 2 new tents! After this we had to go back to the hotel so Dan could erect the new tents. We all had a bath, shaves etc. and then went down to the bar for a beer. We wondered around looking for a restaurant. We managed to find a restaurant tucked away inside a mall. Lucky for us the menu was in English/Slovak. Our phrasebook was turning out to be damn useless at deciphering menus and road signs. This meal was expensive compared to all the others we have had, city prices I guess. Back to the hotel and a farewell to Pete as he was getting up early to leave in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Breakfast was nothing exciting. Once again the hotel showed its rubbish customer service. We showed up in the dining room with no staff there to tell us where to sit, so we sat at any table. Got food, sat down only to be told very gruffly to move to another table. We weren’t even offered any help to carry our food to the other table, at the other end of the room too! We ate and left, nice to see the back of that place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080838.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080839.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080844.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 11/12: 17/18 AUGUST,  Nová Sedlica – Vodńa Nádž (Voklav, Slovakia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/19/day-1112-1718-august-nova-sedlica-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2010 16:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/19/day-1112-1718-august-nova-sedlica-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: €22 – 2 nights for 3 adults, 1 child, 2 tents &amp;amp; 2 cars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to stop at the pension we had wanted to stay at for a drink before setting off again. What a pity it had been full, it looked like a lovely place to stay. Perhaps if we are back in that neck of the woods again we might book into it. Out of interest we asked when they would have a free room, they said they were fully booked for the next week. There were plums and apples growing on the side of the roads next to the pension, Cassie picked some and ate them. Not quite ripe enough, but she seemed to enjoy them all the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today’s camp site search was a long and interesting one. So, the map showed a camp site, we headed there. Only to find that it was just day camping, for swimming. We decided that it was a good enough spot to have lunch and look at the map to see where the other camp sites were plotted. We saw that there were 3 on the other side of the lake and decided to head for those. The first one was full of travellers, scary, so we moved on. The next we just could not find. The 3rd, again was a site for travellers. There were these camp sites on the map, but they just didn’t exist. It was now getting late. Pete decided to consult his GPS to find B&amp;amp;Bs listed in the area or camp sites. He finds a camp site, hotel and B&amp;amp;B listed on the opposite side of the lake. We decide to head there. When we get there, there is a toll to pay to access the road down to the camp site. We paid €2.50, Pete paid €2…why Pete paid a different price, we just don’t know. We finally stumbled across the camp site and decided to stay. The lake was warm, there were toilets and showers so we decided to stay for 2 nights. The tents got put up and off we went for a beer up at the bar. We made the decision to braai tonight and go out for dinner tomorrow, so off we trudged back down to the tents to cook dinner. At the Tesco in Snina we had picked up some meat, ready made Slovakian salads and vegetables. The salads were not very tasty, what was in them I still have no clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Our tents were under a street lamp type light, it was very bright. Poor Pete ended up moving his tent and Dan and I decided to put up with the light. Wendy had an awful nights sleep, but that could have also been due to a VERY loud party happening next to the camp site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080760.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080763.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 12: 18 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to treat ourselves to a breakfast of french toast and coffee, to make up for the terrible nights sleep. We spent the day lazing in the sun and Cassie got a day swimming in the lake. A nice lazy day. We also determined the next leg of our journey, where Pete would be leaving us. We decided to head for Martin in Slovakia where Pete would go his way and we’d head off into Czech. We showered and walked to find the local eatery. The menu was small. Dan ordered what he was told to be a typical Slovak dish: Bryndzové halušky (potato dumplings with sheep’s-milk cheese). Pete and I were unadventurous and had burgers, Cassie had chicken in a mushroom sauce with chips. We paid up after Dan and Pete devoured a chocolate tart slice each. The night turned chilly and we walked back for a cold nights sleep, big contrast to the scorcher of a day we had had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080764.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080774.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080795.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 10: 16 AUGUST,  Poroszlo (Hungary) – Nová Sedlica (Slovakia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/17/day-10-16-august-poroszlo-hungary-nova-sedlica-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 16:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/17/day-10-16-august-poroszlo-hungary-nova-sedlica-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Pension: €10.00 pppn €5.00 for a child&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Up bright and early, packed up and ready to leave at our best time yet! Off into Slovakia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Tokaj (pronounced Tokay), is a lovely little town with lovely cheap wine. We bought 3 bottles and a grape juice or non alcoholic wine. The bottles were 1.5ℓ as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Ready to head off out into Slovakia. The roads were awful. HUGE potholes, making you drive in the centre of the road so as to avoid them. We made our way to Nova Sedlica to find a pension Dan and I had read about in the internet. Unfortunately, when we got there the pension was full, so we had to go back to the previous town to find another pension. When we finally found a pension, it happened to be brand new. The building hadn’t yet been rendered or fully painted. It was clean and cheap.We had dinner in the restaurant – 3 beers each, drinks for Cassie and paid for the rooms and it came to only €58.00! Comfortable nights sleep with clean shower in the morning. We had breakfast in the restaurant – 5 coffees, 3 orange juices, toast, scrambled eggs and a toasted sandwich only came to €15.00. Slovakia so far has proven to be cheap. We decided to go back to Nova Sedlica for a walk as that was the reason we wanted to stay there in the first place. The walk took us roughly 1 &amp;amp; half hours. Butterflies, insects, blackberries were but a few of the things we found along the way. We decided to go to Snina and stop at a Tesco, just to see what they are like here. We also need diesel and food before the next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080673.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080688.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080726.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 9: 15 AUGUST, Keszthely (Hungary) – Lake Tisza (Poroszlo, Hungary)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/16/day-9-15-august-keszthely-hungary-lake-tisza-poroszlo-hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2010 16:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/16/day-9-15-august-keszthely-hungary-lake-tisza-poroszlo-hungary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Not a long journey today distance wise, but a long journey due to road conditions and traffic. A very muggy day today. Cassie and Dan both sat in the car topless. We managed to successfully navigate our way through Budapest, but only after getting lost trying to find the M3 exit. Oh well…you can’t have it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since Bovec, we have experienced 4 thunderstorms. This time we drove straight into one. Trees were blown into the road, turning it into a slalom course. A branch was blown onto the landy at one point too! It was such a heavy storm, we had to stop and wait for it to pass. Then…it started to hail! What an experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed for our planned destination, only to get there and find that the camp site no longer existed. We had to continue onto the next town. We finally found a small camp site and changed our plan of 2 nights, to 1 night and a stay in a B&amp;amp;B at the next stop. We braaied for dinner. Over the cooking meat, we got chatting to a young couple about Hungary and places to visit. He recommended going to Tokaj, a Unesco World Heritage site for it’s wine making. We happened to already have it on our list, so decided to stop there for breakfast/lunch. An early night for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080639.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080640.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 7/8: 13/14 AUGUST, Bovec (Slovenia) – Lake Balaton (Keszthely, Hungary)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/15/day-78-1314-august-bovec-slovenia-lake-balaton-keszthely-hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2010 16:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/15/day-78-1314-august-bovec-slovenia-lake-balaton-keszthely-hungary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Camping costs: 13,264.70 Fontir = €47.20 (281 Fontir = €1) – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The journey this morning took us up a mountain pass, over and down again. Half way up the pass, Cas’ tummy couldn’t take the windy road and she emptied her breakfast all over the back seat. We had to pull over and clean up. Just as we started to clean up, the heavens opened and Dan and I got soaked! Not a good start to the day’s journey. It continued to rain as the journey continued. I do hope the sun shines soon! After a long days drive, we finally arrived at Lake Balaton. It was late in the day, so we picked the first campsite we came across. We chose a pitch down by the lake, it was big enough to pitch both tents and take both cars. Tents were erected and we went off in search of some dinner. Out the camp site and down the road were some restaurants, we decided to try there for dinner. We had Hungarian goulash for starters, and for our main we shared a pork platter. It consisted of breaded pork, sausages, meatballs, chips and a salad. There was a lot of meat, not even the 3 of us could finish it all. The meal for the 4 of us came to 9500 Fontir = £35.00.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Unfortunately, another thunderstorm rolled in as we walked home. There were some spectacular fork lightening rods. The other spectacular thing were these huge, green mosquito looking insects. They were around in the thousands, in fact millions. They seemed to be attracted to green. It didn’t help that our tent was covered with a green tarp (to stop the packing up of a wet tent), green landy, green chairs etc. We were plagued!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080577.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080579.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DAY 8: 14 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The next day we simply lazed around. Cassie playing in the shallows of the lake, Wendy sunbathed and Dan read. Loads of washing was done and we washed all of Cassie’s seat covers thanks to yesterday’s sick fiasco. We went for a wonder into town: Keszthely. We tried to find a supermarket, but soon found that they were all closed. Another meal out. As we were walking back we saw a sign for Tesco! When we got back from town, we were so hot and sticky, we had to go for a swim again. The lake was nice but it was muddy water and a gross silty bottom. Neither of us particularly enjoyed standing on the bottom of the lake, so we walked across the camp site to the swimming pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to go for dinner at the camp site restaurant. After our meal we headed back to the tent for an early night. Time to move on tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/IMG_1009.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;133&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080606.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 5/6: 11/12 AUGUST, Altenmarkt (Austria) – Bovec (Slovenia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/13/day-56-1112-august-altenmarkt-austria-bovec-slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 16:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/13/day-56-1112-august-altenmarkt-austria-bovec-slovenia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Camping costs: €38.04 – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Another wet start to the day and packing up a wet tent. Last night we had discussed a few nights stop at Bovec and then deciding where to go from there. We were now sick of rain and thunderstorms as that is all we had had every evening. We were wondering about changing direction and going South to Bosnia and Croatia. We were still undecided as to which direction to go and decided to make our decision in Bovec. We paid another toll today, not doing bad on the tolls actually but this one was a whopping €9.50. Today’s drive shouldn’t be too long as we only have 180km to Bovec. The scenery going into Slovenia was wonderful. Especially as we came into the mountains of Bovec. Great driving with the twists and turns of the mountain roads. We made excellent time and arrived at 13.00 hrs. We found the camp and set up the tents. We needed to do shopping again and decided to go for a wonder to find a shop. We were quite lucky, there was one 5 minutes up the road. We got some wonderful local bread, a cake (very strudel like) and a few other bits and bobs. We then had a beer next door, 3 beers came to €6.00. After lunch we were very hot and decided to go off looking for a swim. We were advised by the camp site reception that there was an outside swimming pool down the road, or alternatively you could swim in the river Soċa (pronounced Socha). After a good 20 minute walk, we made it to the river. We decided to carry on walking to see if we could find the pool. When we got there, the pool was closed! We walked back again to the river and had a paddle in that. It was very cold! Cassie and Wendy went in pretty much straight away but it took Dan a little longer to get wet. After the swim we walked back up the hill again for dinner. Tonight we braaied the meat we should have braaied last night in Austria. Unfortunately we had a late dinner and a rather late night to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080438.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080421.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080470.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080490.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080475.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080493.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DAY 6: 12 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Day 2 in Bovec and we decided to have an explore around today. After breakfast we took a walk into Bovec town. It was only 5 minutes from the camp site. Here we stopped and had a coffee and cake. Cassie had her usual ice cream. There was a supermarket across the road from the café and we decided to explore and get a few items for lunch. Pete had pointed out the pizza place shown in the Narnia movie extras dvd, the place where the crew spent a lot of their time and even ate the place out of fresh produce. We decided to have dinner there that evening. We had gone into the tourist office to ask them what sights there were to see. A waterfall nearby was suggested. It was a little too far to walk, so back at the tent Pete cleared his back seat so that we could take a drive in his car to the car park. The landy was stationary because it had the awning up. After lunch we drove to the waterfall. It was a short 20 minute walk to the viewing place. The waterfall was low on water, so there was no rush of water in the river below it. The walk wasn’t bad but a little steep on occasion. Once at the top you couldn’t go any further and so it was back down again. We then took Pete to the river where we had had a dip yesterday and sat with our feet in the water for a cool down. After we treated ourselves to an ice cream. A thunderstorm had been predicted by the tourist information, so Dan and I decided to suspend the extra tarp up over the tent to stop the nasty job of having to pack up a wet tent in the morning. We hoped that it wouldn’t rain because we had put all the effort into putting the tarp up. We set off into town for our pizza. The restaurant was booked up and we had a little 15 minute wait till a table was free. The pizzas are humongous! A small pizza on their menu (which we ordered for Cassie), is actually sufficient enough for an adult. The normal pizzas were too much and we couldn’t finish them. We asked to take them away in a bag so we could have them for lunch the next day. The service was very slow, but despite that, the restaurant was very busy. We had a rather early night this time, which was probably good because we were woken in the early hours of the morning by an enormously loud thunderstorm that was immediately above us. The thunder and lightening rolled in first and then really hard rain. Poor Cassie was frightened and ended up coming into our room. We thanked our stars that we had strung up the tarp. None of us got much sleep after that as the storm lasted for hours. A semi dry tent was packed up when the storm did break. It was off into Hungary today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080498.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080504.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080511.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 4: 10 AUGUST, Tübingen (Germany) – Altenmarkt (Austria)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/11/day-4-10-august-tubingen-germany-altenmarkt-austria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 16:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/11/day-4-10-august-tubingen-germany-altenmarkt-austria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Camping&lt;strong&gt; costs: €21.00 – 1 night&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We set off for Austria and a camp that Pete had seen on the net and added to his GPS. We saw a Lidl on the way and decided to stop for food for that evening. We got snacks, beer, lunch, chocolate, fruit and dinner all for a mere €26.83. Much better price! The German motorways all signal their exits with a sign saying AUSFARHT. This completely threw us to start with because we didn’t look it up in our phrase book and we couldn’t find the town on the map. We thought “This Ausfahrt is very popular!”. Until Wendy finally found the word in the phrase book. Suddenly it was a very big joke and all roads led to Ausfahrt. It gave us a jolly good giggle. Along the way Cassie made good progress in her school work. Wendy brought some reading books with us so that we could try and get Cassie to start trying to recognise and sound out words. She picked up the book and started reading. We were shocked and very proud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After a long drive we arrived at the camp site. According to the sign, the site was a 4 star camp site. The toilets were very clean and you were given a fob key to enter the toilets area. This also had the washing up area and a dining room to sit in. There was a computer with internet access on it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We set about setting up camp. Pete had given us an awning that he had from his Tomb Raider Land Rover. Cassie desperately wanted to go swimming and a thunderstorm was rolling in, so we quickly took her for a swim. It was freezing! Suddenly thunder rolled in. A quick departure from the pool and to the tents. It rained and my gosh did it rain! After being drenched, even under the awning, we retreated to the area by the toilets. We had forgotten our fobs, so we had to sit outside. At least we were dry. This meant that the braai we had planned for dinner was not going to happen, so we decided to don our raincoats and walk into town to try and find a restaurant. We managed to find a hotel that served food. The owner was very kind and put our coats in a dry room on the heaters to dry. There wasn’t a large choice on the menu, but nice food. We ordered 3 beers, a hot chocolate, ghoulash soup, bratwurst, mixed platter and a house pizza. It all came to €42.00. We headed back to our tents for a sleep, ready to head into Slovenia tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080384.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080401.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080405.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 2 &amp; 3: 8/9 AUGUST 2010, Neufchâteau (Belgium) – Tübingen (Germany)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/09/day-2-8-august-2010-neufchateau-belgium-tubingen-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 00:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/09/day-2-8-august-2010-neufchateau-belgium-tubingen-germany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: €53.00 – 2 nights&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As soon as we had packed up and hit the road, the wet set in and continued to stay wet right the way across into Germany. A day for border crossings, wonder what it would have been like if we had had to go through the customs as we went into France, Luxembourg, Germany, France again and back into Germany to reach Tübingen. We are meeting up with Pete in Tübingen at the camp site there on the River Nekar. Just before we got to Tübingen we stopped at a services for lunch…big mistake as it cost us €17.30 for 2 sandwiches, wurst, 3 drinks, biscuits and a chocolate. Seems a lot, but it really wasn’t for that price! We decided to go on the toll road between Saarbrucken and Strasbourg to cover some ground, this however meant a toll of €6.10. The day finally brightened up as we reached Tübingen. Perhaps it was the paying of a toll that brightened up the day..our fee for the sunshine. We finally managed to find the camp site and Pete was waiting for us at reception when we drove in. Pete had managed to bag himself a campervan/motorhome plot however the camp refused to let us have the one next to him and we had to go to the tent area. What was annoying was that you couldn’t take your car into the tent area. We managed to find a spot right next to the hedge and park the landy there so we didn’t end up having a walk whenever we needed something.We put the tent up and went to the bar for a well earned beer. After having a refuel at the bar, we took Cassie for a walk along the river to a small park where she could have a play and burn off some energy. We had all decided to have dinner at the camp restaurant as we had not managed to stop at a shop to get supplies. We had Swabian Dishes, meaning local. They consisted of a ravioli filled pasta with a potato and sauerkraut accompaniment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080341.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080350.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080378.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080322.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;DAY 3: 9 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today was our 2nd Wedding Anniversary. We had ordered bread at the camp store for the morning, and when this was delivered the next day, we had breakfast and went for a walk into the Old Town along the river. Once in town we found a café and had a coffee. Pretty pricey town as 3 coffees and a juice cost €13.00. Guess you are paying for the architecture you are seeing whilst drinking your coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                      &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080353.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080364.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080373.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080380.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We wondered around trying to find a supermarket to get things for lunch and dinner. After asking in very broken German, we managed to decipher that there was no supermarket in town and had to go out of town to find one. Well that wasn’t on the agenda, so back we trudged to find smaller stores to get individual items. We got bread from a baker and spotted a store with lovely salamis etc. in the window. Well! €41.74 later we had lunch! I think the sausages were made from pigs that ate gold. A beer was needed after that to wash away the shock. Poor Cas got attacked by wasps because she was drinking Fanta. We ended up trapping them in the ashtrays whilst she drank her drink. Back to camp to eat our expensive lunch. It was a bit of a hot day and there happened to be an outside swimming pool across the river from where the camp was. We decided to take Cassie and go cool off. The slight down side was that the bridge to cross the river was a good 10 minute walk down the river and then back up the other side to the pool. The pools were great. There were 3 different pools and they had slides, which Cassie loved. After a cool off, we wondered back to camp for dinner. After seeing the prices in the town, we decided to eat at the camp restaurant again. This time for dinner, we had pork with Swabian noodles and a salad. It was very nice, but there were far to many noodles on the plate and to be honest, they were very bland. Whilst having dinner we discussed the route we were taking. We couldn’t make it all the way to Bovec, Slovakia in one day, so a stop overnight was required. Austria was settled on for this stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080375.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 1: 7 AUGUST 2010, Calais (France) - Neufchâteau (Belgium)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/08/day-1-7-august-2010-calais-france-neufchateau-belgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 00:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/08/day-1-7-august-2010-calais-france-neufchateau-belgium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 style=&#34;text-align:-webkit-auto;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: €17.30 - 1 night&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34;  alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080253.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;-webkit-text-size-adjust:auto;background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);&#34;&gt;Early start, we set out at 02.45 hrs for Dover to catch our 05.55 hrs ferry to Calais. Pretty uneventful crossing with no major hiccups and actually remembering to drive on the other side of the road. We headed out on the A16 to Dunkerque and then down into Belgium. We had hardly realised that we had come into Belgium until we suddenly saw the border crossing sign...if we hadn&#39;t looked in that direction I don&#39;t think we would have truly noticed until the road signs were different. By now we were truly tired, having had such an early start. We decided to stop and find a camp site. We turned off just outside Namur into a small town called Neufchateau. We found a very small, quiet camp site and set about setting up camp.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:-webkit-auto;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;-webkit-text-size-adjust:auto;background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);&#34;&gt;Next on the list was tea, juice and nesquick (the diversity of us 3), and a snack.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1367225468953.287&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080258.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;-webkit-text-size-adjust:auto;background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#34;blogsy-1367225468965.01&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080265.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img id=&#34;blogsy-1367225468921.7761&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080287.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1367225468928.6074&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080305.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;-webkit-text-size-adjust:auto;background-color:rgba(255,255,255,0);&#34;&gt;The camp site had a small porta-pool, trampoline and some swings. After getting the tent up, we went up for a swim, on the insistence of Cassie. We had a camp cooked meal that night of Thai yellow curry that we had brought with us. That night is poured! Thankfully the rain had ceased when we woke in the morning. We now had the horrible job of packing away a wet tent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning the Summer Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/07/29/planning-the-summer-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 15:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/07/29/planning-the-summer-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We sat down one Sunday afternoon in July 2010 with just 4 weeks to go and a rough idea of where we wanted to go. Wendy had done some basic research on the internet about the different countries we had decided to visit and the suggested highlights to see. Dan had plotted these on a map for us to see where they lay and which ones would be possible and which would not. What we had decided was that we were doing Eastern Europe this year for a change.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan dragged out an old Europe map we had from back in 2007 (a little out of date, but useful for planning purposes). We decided to plot our route on this. Thankfully, Cassie had had a friend over to play with and that gave us the opportunity to spend the day plotting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-19-jul-2010-2215.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=374&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;337&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We then added the destinations to good old Google maps to find out distances between stops and travel time. From last years travel we decided to aim for 300 miles a day travelling. Going across Czech, Slovakia and Hungary, we guessed that 300 miles would not be possible due to no major roads. We decided to make up the needed distance back up through Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;The initial plan&#34; alt=&#34;2010 Overview&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/2010-overview.jpg?w=1280&amp;amp;h=420&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;209&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan contacted Pete, his friend we visited in Spain back in 2008, to show him our planned route. We had hoped to meet up with Pete again last year, but he was unable to get time off work to meet us. Pete informed Dan that it was a great route, but would we like to flip it, change one destination to Bovec, Slovenia and then he would be able to join us for some of the journey. Dan created a new map, emailed Wendy with the question and she decided that it would be no difference going one way as to the other. Wendy brought up the issue of our 2nd wedding anniversary and that if we flipped the route, we would be spending it in Stuttgart, not somewhere she wanted to spend our anniversary. After some investigation from Wendy she decided to change Stuttgart to Tübingen, a town on the banks of the river Necka. It is also close to Naturpark Schönbuch. Pete was happy with this and so we are going to meet a good old friend again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2010 Overview Plan B&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/2010-overview-plan-b.jpg?w=1280&amp;amp;h=440&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;220&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-19-jul-2010-22151.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=374&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;374&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-18-apr-2012-2145.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=200&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So this year we have made some more purchases. We have bought another box (as seen above) for food storage. We have bought a laundry bag, the clothes got a little bit out of hand last year being stuffed into nooks and crannies till they were washed. We have also bought a new braai…the amazing Boab braai. It’s very impressive. Unfortunately the English weather has not allowed us to test it at home before we set off on our journey. Dan has fitted a working light to Tusky as well as done some maintenance bits to the car which you can read about on the pages about Tusky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Because we are travelling to Eastern Europe we have also had to have vaccinations. Originally it started out as 6 vaccinations for Dan and Wendy and 2 for Cassie. We ended up just having 3 for Dan and Wendy and 1 for Cassie. Dan and Wendy had Typhoid, Diphtheria and Hepatitis A. It was suggested that we go to a travel clinic to get a vaccination for Tick Encephalitis but we did not have enough time left and you require 4 weeks and a minimum of 2 doses. Instead we have had to stock up on Deet insect repellent and some tick removing tweezers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Continuing on the health, we have also purchased a Life Systems first aid kit this year and stocked it with a few extra items. We decided on the mountaineer first aid kit because of the items it has. We have then added Imodium, burn patches, anti histamine cream, blister stick and blister plasters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>