<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>300tdi on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/300tdi/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 300tdi on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/300tdi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Antignano, Livorno - Italy</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/06/antignano-livorno-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 19:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/06/antignano-livorno-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9256.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-818 alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Poor Tusky&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel have decided that they would like to look for a small camping fridge. We looked for a Decathlon and used the GPS find our way. It was along the way and we were heading towards Bari now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We found a Decathlon, but were not in luck, they did not stock any fridges what-so-ever! As we were near the shops, we decided to stop off and get our food shopping done for the next few days. As we were packing the cars and fridge with our food shop, Dan and Daniel noticed an oil leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It turns out that the vacuum pump is seriously leaking. We need to get to a garage and get the right part to fix this situation. Dan used the GPS to locate the nearest Land Rover garage, and off we set on a search for this garage and a way to get the part we would require.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The first garage we find is no longer open to business. This is a set back that we did not expect or want. The day is wearing on and time is ticking. We managed to locate another Land Rover garage, and so the search continues. This time we are in luck! The garage is still in business, but we have now hit Siesta time and so we have to wait for 14.00hrs till we can find out if they have a part or can order one for us. We decide to go to a truck café we saw just down the road to have a snack and drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we get back to the garage, the guy is extremely helpful. He says that he can order the part, but it may take as long as 48hrs to be delivered. Give him an hour or so and he will see what he can do for us. It turns out that he is able to get the part delivered for the next day, we just have to collect it after 14.00hrs. We thank him profusely and set off to find a campsite that isn&amp;#039;t too far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The campsite we found was just up the road. It had a swimming pool, points for Cassie, and it had bungalows, points for Carole. Carole and Daniel rented a bungalow and we took a pitch. We decided to stay for 2 nights so that Dan had time to fit the pump and not worry. As we pulled up to our pitch, Dan got worried about being able to work on the Landy. It wasn&amp;#039;t a secluded spot. We went and had a look at a pitch that we would be able to &amp;#039;upgrade&amp;#039; to if we wanted. It was more expensive and came with it&amp;#039;s own sea view terrace. Dan was happier with the privacy this pitch provided, and so we moved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9240.jpg?w=225&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-817&#34; alt=&#34;The terrace adjoined to our pitch&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The time at he campsite was spent relaxing. The next day Wendy and Cassie spent the day at the pool whilst Dan worked on the Landy and Carole and Daniel did things they wanted to catch up on. It was a nice lazy stop despite the reason for stopping. We explored the beach, went for a swim in the sea and had a lovely braai on the terrace on the last evening. Ready to leave in the morning and do one mammoth drive. We were going to try and cover the whole distance to Bari tomorrow, making up for lost time.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1110456.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-820&#34; alt=&#34;Cassie &amp;amp; Wendy enjoying the sun &amp;amp; pool&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safari Snorkel Fitted</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/21/safari-snorkel-fitted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 18:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/21/safari-snorkel-fitted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-10431.jpg?w=180&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;239&#34; alt=&#34;Safari Snorkel&#34; /&gt;Thanks to being the lucky recipient of a Safari Snorkel for my Birthday and many Christmases to come, I managed to get a Safari Snorkel fitted to the Landy last week.
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;It was all fairly straight forward and I forgot to take many photos.&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most intimidating bit for me was drilling the holes in the body work, making sure I had the template spot on etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-10-jul-2012-0538.jpg?w=201&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; alt=&#34;Mounting holes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the existing induction pipe work, I sealed up the drain valve in the tee piece, for this I used Sika flex to seal the flap shut, then completely filled in the drain appeture with more of the stuff. I tested this when I finished by blocking the top of the Snorkel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the holes were drilled, I fitted the neoprene gasket for the Snorkel to the body of the Snorkel using some Sika flex sealant, I also did the same with the windscreen mount gasket. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-1044.jpg?w=195&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;195&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; alt=&#34;Water drain&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once these were dry, I test fitted the lot with plain nuts rather than nylocs, so that I could find the location to drill the windscreen frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lick of paint on the holes and then some more sealant around all the holes will keep the water out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The windscreen mount is secured with self tappers, five in total. I left the bolts for the snorkel body on the windscreen mount loose, until I tightened up the wing securing bolts using nylocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wing gasket had copious amounts of sealant around it, this is not really to keep water out of the snorkel though, more just to keep the holes sealed. The design of the Safari Snorkel is such that it does not depend on the wing seal. The whole upright section is continuos unit until the hose fits to it for the induction system, meaning that there are fewer potential failure failure points, that other designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-1043.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; alt=&#34;Windscreen bracket&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-10441.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; alt=&#34;Back of the wing panel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-13441.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Job Done&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter cooler Leak Testing - FTP8030 300TDI</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/04/inter-cooler-leak-testing-ftp8030-300tdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 19:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/04/inter-cooler-leak-testing-ftp8030-300tdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Defender has had what I think is a typical inter cooler leak for quite some time, which leads to some power loss often notable on hills. I attempted to sort it out last summer prior to our departure for our summer trip. I purchased a second hand item and found that it was also leaking. Luckily I tested it before I fitted it to the vehicle. I ended up leaving the original in place and living with the loss of power for the trip and manage to get my money back. The seller was very apologetic!
&lt;div&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120404-00134.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-285&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; alt=&#34;300 TDI Intercooler Leak - Back&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture above is typical of the leaks I have seen on these items. If you look on ebay a lot of the second hand inter coolers have the oil stain you see above, in the lower corner of the inter cooler, some have other oil stains which may be a sign of a leak, so please buy with care. This tel-tale sign of oil is what prompted me to test the leaking one I had last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fairly easy to set up a fairly crude off vehicle test. I used an old inner tube, which was cut so the valve was in the middle of a length of inner tube long enough to fit between the two hose connections on the inter cooler, the inner tube was secured with some jubilee clips. I then pumped up the inner tube to about 20 psi and stuck the whole lot in a tub of water. What I found was a constant stream of bubbles from the corner of the inter cooler, indicating a leak. Below you can see my inter cooler test equipment. Impressed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120404-00148.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-289&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Intercooler Test Equipment - Bike Inner Tube&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I managed to purchase a new replacement inter cooler from Motor &amp;amp; Diesel Engineering Ltd, they supply the LGV 2.8 Diesel engine over here which is a development of the 300TDI engine. The item they sent looked to me to be a re-core, but it had comforting stickers on it which suggest it was tested. The price was also very reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fairly easy to change the inter cooler, so I will not get into the detail, you can see that below. I think with my faffing around it took me two leisurely hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/300tdi-intercooler-change-lr.jpg&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-283&#34; width=&#34;516&#34; height=&#34;554&#34; alt=&#34;Defender 300TDI Intercooler Change&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this is of use to someone, has anyone else had the experience, I had with purchasing a bad second hand item?
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Charge Auxiliary Battery Installation - Version 1</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/17/split-charge-auxiliary-battery-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 19:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/17/split-charge-auxiliary-battery-installation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The battery in a Defender is under the passenger seat. It is a large compartment which you can actually fit two batteries in. This is perfect if you want to use there vehicle for winching, camping or over landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/IMG00119.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; alt=&#34;You should see a picture of the Defender battery compartment&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The main driver for fitting a second battery in our vehicle was to run the fridge. We have a Weaco CF-18 cool box style fridge this is an excellent fridge, which is sufficent for us on holidays camping, it has an 18 litre capacity. If we where going on longer trips I think I would push to get a large capacity fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I wanted to keep the control and wiring simple when I installed the second battery. In order to do this I decided against control electronics, there are loads on the market made by people such as National Luna. I decided to use the method shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The two batteries are simply linked by a contactor with a large rating. I chose a 120 Amp contactor in the end. The control of the contactor is by the charge indicator in the dash. I picked this up of the back of the alternator wiring to save me running wires upto the dash board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/1Qev0Mv3TaSUzn93-ekcuK3e04M5rZserP4Yo33wpwb0.png&amp;amp;w=499&amp;amp;h=335&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;499&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; alt=&#34;You should see the circuit diagram of the split charge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Attached to the auxilary battery is a small six way fuse panel this allows me to fuse any additional items I attach to the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/IMG00116.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; alt=&#34;You should see a picture of the Auxiliary Fuse Panel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Here are a few pics of the layout, before additional connections where made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/IMG00118.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of Contactor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/IMG00117.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; alt=&#34;The contactor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Around the vehicle I fitted surface mounted 12 volt sockets, such as below the second row seats and above the rear light cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img00124.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-563&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img00126.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-564&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img00127.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-565&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1080802.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;The fridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;There is some more info in these threads. &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.landrovernet.com/showthread.php/161991-Split-charge-Alternator-size&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.landrovernet.com/showthread.php?t=151988&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Sorry about the crappy pictures I took them on my blackberry...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>