<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albania on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/categories/albania/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albania on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/categories/albania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 20 - Secret Beach to Italian B&amp;B</title>
      <link>/2013/08/15/day-20-secret-beach-to-italian-bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 07:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/15/day-20-secret-beach-to-italian-bb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were up very early thanks to having had no sleep. Dan started the day with a 5am swim!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a departure of 6am for us after we brushed our teeth and dressed. We decided to find a café along the way and get some breakfast and a coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1140108.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made our way back up the winding road that you take to get down to the Southern part of Albania. At the top there is a restaurant, it looked open and was serving a few travellers, so we decided to stop. We ordered coffee and asked for the menu for breakfast. We got the impression that breakfast wasn&#39;t a big meal in Albania and ordered toast with butter and honey and toast with butter and jam. What we got was warmed up slices of bread with a side plate that had a lump of butter and a dollop of honey or jam. The butter was rancid and the Jam was a little different. We ate the bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0296.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had decided to head for Vlorë and enquire about the ferry, see if it did take cars and how much it was. When we got into Vlorë, we could see the port with a ferry anchored, but we couldn&#39;t see how to get to the port. Eventually we came across a sign and turned down a road … well, we ended up stuck as we found ourselves surrounded by bollards. There was a gap in the bollards where someone had obviously tried to drive over them and knocked one off. We are a high vehicle, so we just drove over it, down the incredibly high kerb and out into the traffic going onto the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img_0228.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually found the port and parked the land, grabbed our passports and documentation and went in search of tickets. Not a hard thing as the street was lined with ticket shops. The fair, including the car and 2 adults and 1 child came to €206 one way. We were informed it departed at 1pm and to check in at 12.30pm the latest. We bought the ticket, but now had a few hours to kill before we embarked. We decided to wonder around Vlorë, find a supermarket and exchange our LEK. The supermarket part was easier said than done, but we did manage to exchange our left over LEK. With that done we headed for an air conditioned café to have a drink and wait out our remaining time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 12.30 we got in the car and headed towards the ferry. We came across a mishmash of higgledy piggledy park cars and young boys shouting at us to buy cigarettes. One of the young boys pointed to an office and said, &#34;You go give ticket there.&#34;. Dan thanked him and hopped out with the tickets and passports. A gentleman at the office helped Dan with the odd check in procedure and then we were off and boarding the ferry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked, gathered our bits and bobs for the journey and went up to find a table. We were all tired from last night and were hoping to be able to get some shut eye on the journey. The gentleman that had helped Dan appeared, along with his wife and son. He is married to an English lady and every year they journey to Italy and Albania to visit his family. They warned us that even though we were told a 1pm departure, it would be more like 3pm departure. With this knowledge we settled ourselves for a long day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1140126.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally at 2.28pm the ferry started moving. We were off! Only another 5 hours to go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey was long and very boring. We were also warned not to eat the food on the ferry, so we settled for pre packaged crisps and biscuits. After disembarking, it was now 7.30pm and we decided to head a little south from Brindisi. We have no Italy maps and our GPS is still dead, so we looked for a services so we could buy a map of the area. After a few failed attempts, Dan pulls into one and manages to get a map. He asked a gentleman in the services if there was camping, the guy was apparently rather rat arsed, but very helpful and pointed Dan in the direction of a few campsites. Now we just had to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a little lost, and as the time ticked on, we could not find a campsite. We looked for the obligatory signs, but found none. After 2 hours we finally see a sign, and we follow it … and we follow it … and we follow it. We are now desperate to sleep and eat and decide to just check into a hotel. The first hotel we see, that is easy to park in, we pull into to ask if they have a room. Unfortunatley for us, they are completely full! We are informed that all the hotels are completely full and that we will struggle to find a room as it is Italy&#39;s 2 week holiday period. He kindly calls around and finds a B&amp;amp;B that have a free room, but it will cost us €100 for the night including breakfast. Bggars can&#39;t be chooses, so we thank the guy and take the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The owner of the B&amp;amp;B came to meet us at the hotel and show us the way back to the B&amp;amp;B. We followed him, pulled into the B&amp;amp;B, took the room key, had a shower and collapsed .. sparko till the next morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke not to early, but not to late and had showers. We then went to have breakfast. We were all starving as we never did get to eat dinner the night before. Breakfast consisted of a buffet style arrangement with fresh fruits, fruit juice, bread, butter, jam and some poached fruit and a lemon compot thing. We were simply enjoying eating when a plate of cakes is put down onto our table … a very sweet breakfast, Cassie certainly wasn&#39;t complaining.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 19 - Bunec to Beach Cove via Butrint</title>
      <link>/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 07:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1140027.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a fairly ok nights sleep and woke early. We decided to avoid the breakfast spoken of last night as dinner was a little &#39;dodgy&#39;, for want of a better word. We opted for just a coffee instead. Outside our room we bumped into a lovely lady sitting with her grandson. She asked us where we were from and we told her, &#34;England, Brighton&#34;. She said she knew it and lived in Lewisham. She was on holiday with her family and investigating a business opportunity in Albania. I must add, she was Albanian. We chatted for a bit longer and then bid her farewell, we were off for that coffee.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being reinforced with a coffee, we headed out towards Butrint, we wanted to visit the Roman ruins there. After a long and hot drive, we arrived at the entrance car park to the ruins. Immediately we were accosted by a young urchin girl and her male companion. They demanded that we buy bracelets from them. Dan was in the firing line of their deluge and so we ended up buying a bracelet from the girl and one from the boy. By this time I had another little urchin at my window. She begged that I bought a bracelet from her too, I had to say no. The first young girl then came round to my window and asked if she could have my banana that I had sitting in the front. I laughed and had to admire her audacity. I gave her the banana. She immediately peeled it and ate it as she walked away, pleased at herself for getting another tourist in her trap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were now dripping and feeling a little hard done by, having been accosted by the urchins. We went for a cold drink at the restaurant before entering the sight. At the entrance to the ruins the prices were 700 LEK per foreign visitor, 500 LEK per foreign visitor in a group, 300 LEK for an Albanian visitor and 400 LEK for a child. So it was an entrance fee of 1,400 LEK and so we followed the cruise ship visitors that had just descended on the place by bus load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1140030.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked around the remains. The signs at the entrance had said no smoking, walk on the path and beware the insects and snakes. The last bit made us hopeful we&#39;d see something other than roman ruins. We waited at the first part, an amphitheatre, for the hoards to disappear. Here Cassie discovered a turtle in the water around the ruins. From here we wondered around, skirting the crowds. It was extremely hot, and we were all dripping in sweat by the end. Afterwrds Dan and Cassie got themselves and ice cream and I got a can of cold Coca Cola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1140071.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to head off and find a camp on the beach somewhere. Yesterday Dan had noticed that the radius arm bushes needed changing, especially if we wanted to tackle a few more gravel tracks during the holiday. We had seen plenty of &#39;Autoservis&#39; places along the road and so we went in search of one that could fit us in. We tried a few and they all pointed us to someone else as they were far to busy. Eventually on the way out of Butrint, we stopped at a small garage we had noticed on our way in. He was now quiet and Dan asked if he could do the work, it would only take 1 hour. The guy agreed. He spoke good english and so Dan changed into some shorts and negotiated the car above a pit. Cassie and I sat in the car trying not to expire, while Dan helped the guy change the bushes. All done for 2000 LEK. Luckily Dan had the spares in the car … Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were off now in search of a beach to stay on. They all looked packed and we could not find a turning to some. So, we decided to stop for lunch somewhere. We came across a little village and went to a restaurant. Here the owner spoke good english and we ordered lamb with a greek salad. The owner chafed to us about working on cruise ships and seeing the world, but how now he water to settle in Albania. We asked him about the ferries from Vlorë to Brindisi. He recommended going from Igoumenista instead and offered to let us use the internet to check fares.We thanked him and Dan did just that. The prices and info was not helpful as the ferry from Vlorë did not show up in the searches. We thanked the owner and hit the road once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0264.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we stopped at a little cove we had spotted on the way past yesterday. The water edge was lined with mobile homes, which we only assumed were stopping for the night. As we approached and stopped, a funny Albanian man came up to us and asked where we were from. We told him England and asked if it was ok to stay. He said sure no problem, just park. Dan asked if he wanted money, he said that wasn&#39;t necessary, we were his friends … we concluded he was a little strange and parked up anyway, changed into our kozzies, and went for a dip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130968.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0270.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0279.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie immediately spotted sea urchins in the water, so we tried to avoid these. Later on we spoke to a lady who had stood n one and was trying to get the poison out her toe. Cassie got the snorkel and mask out and did a little look see in the water. She stayed in for ages! All of a sudden there was a ruckus, some locals nearby had caught an octopus. They started throwing it onto the rocks whilst screaming and shouting. I found this really upsetting. Why not just kill it humanely and hopefully not as sport, but to take it back and eat it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we had been sitting on the beach, the wind had been building. We decided to set the tent up and head for the restaurant for dinner across the road from the bay. As we had eaten a big lunch, we decided to go for a snack type dinner … this didn&#39;t really happen. Dan ordered calamari and I the seafood spaghetti, Cas shared both. The wind was now quite strong. We wondered back to the tent and got ready for bed. Whilst we lay in the tent, we were whipped and bashed. Dan and I worried about it not being safe in the tent with the wind at this strength, so we gathered up our sleeping stuff, closed up the tent and bundled into the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a night of horror! I personally got NO sleep … Dan says he managed a wink or two and I think Cassie was the luckiest out of us all. She probably managed an hour or so. To say we woke early would be an understatement. We were up before 6, teeth brushed and outta there. We were the walking dead but we still headed for Vlorë to see how much it would be to catch the ferry to Brindisi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18 - Kepi i Kalas to Bunec via our Secret beach</title>
      <link>/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 07:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0254.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Being in a hotel last night meant getting away quickly was easy. We had a local style breakfast of feta, tomato, cucumber and bread. Washed down with a few coffees.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Our plan was to check out a beach I had found on Google earth that looked almost isolated due to the track you had to use to get to it. Due to the GPS problems I had circled it on the map. This meant it was another day heading to a circle. The drive to the beach took about an hour or so. We first had to negotiate some spectacular steep roads with tight hairpins over the surrounding mountains. The roads had various bits missing and loads of fallen rocks which claimed a few victims to punctures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130959.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The turning to the beach was immediately of the bottom of the steep decent. There had been a few attempts to grade it, but the track was pretty bad. On the was down we got held up by a truck rescuing an Italian mobile home who had been over ambitious. Both looked frustrated. The tow rope was in taters. The owner said something to me as we squeezed by. I promised to return with my tow strap and shackles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;By the time I had stopped 50 meters on and returned they appeared to on there way so I returned and we continued to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we got to the bottom we were delighted, we found an almost empty beach except for a couple of 4x4&#39;s and 2 or 3 like minded over landing campers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The beach was made up by sandy white pebbles. The top of the beach had a sand track which was easy to traverse. We headed most of the way along the track then turned down to the sea. Parking 10 meters from the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0253.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Here we swam in crystal clear water and lounged around for the morning. Cassie loved it. Spending most of the time checking out the fishies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on we decided to leave, I was a little apprehensive, as I had noted the sand and shingle made for horribly difficult driving. I had deflated the tyres a little and even in low diff lock, I struggled. I had to repeatedly reverse to get any momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My first attempt to get up the beach failed, I thought I had enough speed but could not get into low third without grinding to a halt and sinking. I stopped and let some more air out of the tyres and reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Foot to the floor I headed slightly back down towards the sea and managed to get some speed and into third. This allowed me to managed the engine speed and get enough velocity to get over the sand up to the slightly better surface to get off the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once I was back on the track at the top, I was hot! So we headed to a small makeshift bar a local had erected in the rock walls of the mountain that encapsulated the beach. I had a fanta and a beer to chill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had received we headed south to find a place to stay. We had again opted out of camping as we had no supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130983.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We eventually after some chaos ended up at a tiny restaurant at Bunec beach, which had rooms. The owning family lived in a tent. They were very nice and cooked us a traditional pasta dish and we drank loads of beer and swam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130990.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The rooms in these places are basic but functional and clean. We paid 30 euro with breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17 - Koplic to Kepi i Kalas via the Karavasta Lagoon.</title>
      <link>/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 18:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130905.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the heat we did quite well this morning and managed to get packed up and on the road by 0945, after we had a slow coffee and showers all round. Our original plan was to head up to Thethi, which is said to be beautiful, but have a difficult road, especially after rain. Given that the last two days there had been storms in the area, we decided we would not attempt that, but perhaps try on the return route. Instead today we would head for the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gus and Helen who we met at the campsite had lent us a map which they had been given, by another traveller in Albania on a bike. Many of the circles were on the places we had read about, some were alien to us. Anyhow I copied the circles to our map. Todays plan was based on circles. We would head to the circle at Karavasta Lagoon. We had no idea what was there so Wendy read up in the guide book on the way between navigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary was that it is a wet land with many birds and lots of wild life. At night it is apparently a mosquito hell hole. Cool, sounds like an ideal place to visit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130908.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we left we found the roads in the area where we stayed all seemed ok, well sign posted and smooth. Petrol stations everywhere. It was not long before we were in chaos though, Sckoder was manic and it was every man for himself. The roads had occasional road markings, round abouts and traffic signals. Pedestrian crossings never mind those. We encountered various types of traffic, bikes, people, horse and cart, three wheel trucks and even motor bikes which had a tray arrangement welded to the from that formed a kind of three wheel truck thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic involved people and cyclists moving the wrong way and or on the wrong side of the road. Putting themselves in danger. The drivers used their horn to say either hello, we are over taking or we are coming through regardless. Undertaking was the norm. This was probably because the fast lane was used to avoid the chaos at the side of the road with the triple parked vehicles and other oddities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At roundabouts most people don&#39;t bother indicating, if they do it means nothing because they forget to change it as the filter off with the opposite indication. The roundabouts work a bit like a drain hole. In that no one stops, they just continue being sucked into the vortex and some break free when they need to leave. Occasionally you&#39;ll get some one a little bit more crazy who will just fly across the round about breaking the vortex. You&#39;ll have warning if you are lucky by way of continuous multiple beeping of the horn. Beep Beep beep beep beep beep beep beep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually made it out of Sckoder, shocked but unharmed! It was exciting. The only negative for me was the begging on the out skirts at the traffic lights which meant we locked the doors and put the windows up. Sorry. I felt really bad about that, but did not want to encourage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the main road overtaking is an art, you&#39;ll often be confronted by a speeding car in your lane flashing lights at you. They are overtaking. They expect you to assist be moving out of the way. Several occasions having held my ground, I took evasive action, either by braking, making use of the dirt hard shoulder or swerving. These guys are good at Chicken. I think I saved us a few times from accidents by braking to allow people to hop from behind and avoid the front of busses by feet, not meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We endured this for several hours, even trying the motor way, which although wider had limited road markings and was just a bigger play ground.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0156.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually arrived at Karavasta. Here we headed along dirt tracks, paid a toll and continued to the beach, we were able to drive all the way up the beach until we found a quiet spot. You can&#39;t do that in many places. Here we relaxed for an hour or so had a swim and lunch. Previously we had tried about 4 km up the beach, but being near a river outlet there was a lot of plan debris on the beach making it look undesirable amongst all the rubbish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having refreshed ourselves and having convinced ourselves it was not an ideal place to camp, we headed back out on the dirt road which we entered, this then lead us to take a turning to follow one of the waterways of the lagoon. We came across some locals fishing and checked with them we were headed in the right direction. They basically as usual said keep going!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0182.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were not headed basically down a raised section of the lagoon that had a track on it. The track continued for about 5 km, it was wet but ok. I was obviously concerned as it may have got very boggy. It was just wide enough for a car.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0190.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we saw loads of small birds, which appeared not to have the ability to fly, but to merely run around scatter brained. There were also lots of herons. The star of the afternoon was a tortoise we came across just wandering the track. We jumped out to get photos quickly, before it disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0198.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time we got out of there it was getting late, so we headed just south of Vlora to hunt down a room to stay in. We found a nice hotel perched on a cliff top with a private beach for 35 Euro a night with breakfast. We had a swim, then freshened up for the evening opting to eat at the hotel and drink a few beers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 - Koplic, Lake Shkrodër</title>
      <link>/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to stay two nights at Lake Shkodër. Today we woke slowly, having been woken by Cassie in the middle of the night again. After we finally dragged her sleeping items into the tent, thunder rolled in. There had been a little rain too, but not a significant amount. Needless to say, it was a little bit of a restless night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was warming up already by mid morning, and I had decided that the sheets, towels and pillow cases needed to be washed. We also needed to get some food. We asked the owner of the campsite if here was a shop close by and he said yes, just walk up to the main road, over the bridge and there is a shop there. So we handed over our washing, as he had a machine, and set off for the shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130897.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked we were shocked by the rubbish we saw on the side of the road and dumped in ditches, We passed two young boys by the overpass burning their rubbish. It was a reminder that Albania still had ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were perspiring by the time we got to the shop and had to stop for a cold drink at one of the bars. Afterwards we went to the shop and bought essentials .. water, beer, biscuits and other food items. Now for the walk back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the campsite, Cassie made friends with a young girl from a German family staying a few pitches down. She played all afternoon with Lea and her brother Nic. It was nice for her to have company, and Lea wanted to practice her English as she had recently started learning it at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day Thunder had been rumbling in the background but despite this, it had been warm and sunny.. with a slight cloudy haze. But by afternoon, the lightening started making an appearance and we decided to pack up Cassie&#39;s tent and head for the restaurant/bar. And a good thing we did, as the heavens opened with an almighty bang and gush of wind and it did not let up for hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had grabbed a table inside and here we stayed for the most of the evening. Eventually to be joined by Frank and Anjita, Cassie&#39;s new found friends&#39; parents. The evening was great. We swopped travelling stories, places to visit and even swopped blog addresses. It&#39;s always nice to make friends along the way, so thanks Fank and Anjita for a great evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a second Land Rover at the camp, owned by a Scottish couple that were travelling. We had spoken to them the day before about their set up and swopped maps for tips on places to travel. Anyway, Gus and Helen also ended up at the bar/restaurant and as our table was already full, they sat with a trio of Austrian guys next door to us. As the evening progressed, they ended up joining our table too. We all had a wonderful time drinking wine and beer and swopping stories. Thanks Gus and Helen for your tips and your extending fork!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/dscf0134.jpeg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 15 - Kostanijica to Kopliku</title>
      <link>/2013/08/10/day-15-kostanijica-to-kopliku/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 17:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/10/day-15-kostanijica-to-kopliku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is our 5th Wedding Anniversary, so we hoped to make it somewhere nice. Lake Shkodra had been recommended to us by our Dutch neighbours, so that&#39;s where we decided to head as it would also be an ideal place to stop just inside Albania. It has also been recommended to us to cross at the border by Podgorica as the other crossing was obscenely busy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130861.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey around the Kotor Bay and up and out towards Cetinje was magnificent. We managed to navigate ourselves to Cetinje, but once there, there happened to be absolutely no signs telling you how to get out of the town. We had seen a Policeman standing on a corner, so decided to head for him and ask for directions. We had already passed him and when we pulled up alongside him he humourously exclaimed, &#34;I know why you are here! I&#39;ve seen you already, you are lost!&#34;. He very kindly gave us good directions to find the road out and towards Podgorica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we neared Podgorica, we experienced the no road sign phenomonon again. With great &#34;Navigation by Wendy&#34;, we managed to stay on the road out Podgorica and towards the border at Hani Hotit in Albania. Although heading in the correct general direction, we had somehow managed o drive straight through the shanty part of Podgorica, giving us a real insight into the developing world of both Montenegro and Albania. We drove into a town, and as we stopped to consult our map, an old man came towards us, I can only assume asking us if we were ok. In my best pigeon Montenegrin I asked for Shkodër. The man said in many words I did not understand to keep going straight and not turn right! This we followed and eventually made it to the border crossing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130859.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time it was HOT and the sweat was simply dripping from us. Leaving Montenegro was fairly straight forward. The border guard looked at Dan sitting in just his board shorts and advised him that driving shirtless in Albania would receive him a fine from the Police. We thanked him and headed for the Albanian border control. Here I pulled out the Albanian phrase book and was flabbergastered at the huge change in language that we would have to master. Hello was not simply Ciao and thank you was no longer Hvala. We were going to be stumped. The border crossing was amazingly simple and we got insurance then and there from a man that was talking to the border guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in Albania! Yee Hah!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albania Off Road Guide</title>
      <link>/2013/07/17/albania-off-road-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/17/albania-off-road-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/20130717-140602.jpg&#34;&gt;
I have been in touch by chance via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/&#34;&gt;Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; with a chap called Matthew over the last few months. He is planning on travelling to Albania at a similar time to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway via Matthew I have found this book which I thought I would recommend, about routes in Albania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I like the book is that it not only takes off road, but also cover sites to see on route. One nice feature of the book is that the Author attempts to give you an idea of difficulty and what vehicles the route was covered in.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition there is a decent section on cuisine and the differences between regions and a small section on language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bebaweb.cz/albania-offroad-guide.php&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It was about 19 euro delivered to the UK and took a couple of days to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the back of the book so you can see it and the isbn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/20130717-140758.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirations for 2013&#39;s Trip</title>
      <link>/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 19:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2013-1900.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as I mentioned earlier in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, we have been thinking about what we might do this summer. Actually we have been thinking since last summer. I guess we are probably not alone on this, we tend to think from trip to trip, from day to day, even during a trip. I guess most people who enjoy travelling have this problem. Is it wrong? I don&amp;#039;t want to wish my life away, but I love thinking about possibilities, getting the map out while drinking wine or beer in camp. Is that dreamin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us we have been to lots of places in Europe, we still have much of Northern Europe to go and places on our own door step such as Scotland and Ireland, but the weather makes life tricky in those places. We don&amp;#039;t want to be confined, confined to a hotel. We want the option to camp, we like camping. No we are not poor, we just like to get away from it. I camp in hotels all year for work, I really don&amp;#039;t like it. So I guess sooner or later we need to take the plunge and face the weather, before we loose the opportunity to see the places we take for granted on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we have been thinking about travel this August. Unfortunately during tourist season, we are bound to this because of school holidays, we tend to get away lightly due to the places we visit, not always. Our plans have been a little hampered this year, domestics are getting in the way! We had to have the kitchen done... I guess you are wondering what the hell I am on. Well it is all about economics. The kitchen cost a fortune (it is still not finished). This has hampered our trip money saving ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this has meant that, although we have &amp;#039;planned&amp;#039;, the plan is more of an &amp;#039;aspiration&amp;#039;. Let me explain. I guess what we are saying is that, we refuse to give up the opportunity of our annual trip. Regardless of how far we have saved, we&amp;#039;ll see how far we can go on what we&amp;#039;ve got! So if we don&amp;#039;t know what we will be able to do we should plan for what we&amp;#039;d like to do. So I guess you&amp;#039;d say plan for your aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that explained. We&amp;#039;d like this year to explore some more dirt roads in the Alps, there is a warren up there and plenty of places to wild camp without having to part with Euros. After that we&amp;#039;d also like to explore Kosovo, Albania and Macedonia. These are completely new to us and potentially very exciting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-28-may-2013-2022.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we get from the Alps to Albania and the surrounding areas, would either be by road or by sea. We used a ferry last year from Bari to Croatia which made life very easy, but expensive. The easiest ferry option for Albania is from Ancona to Durrës. This costs circa €400 but saves probably about three days in raw driving, that is really more because we stop and take a non direct route. The ferry crossing is around 20 hours. The saving is definitely not in fuel, even in a Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of getting to Albania from Ancona, is that we can use the days saved to spend more time exploring before heading back, it is probably about 1500 miles (2600 km) to Brighton from there. Which would be about 7 days driving, we&amp;#039;d need to allow about 10 so we could chill a bit. This would leave us about 2 weeks in the area we want to be. In reality I&amp;#039;d hope to be able to build some of the return days into the route to allow us to look at possibly Kosovo, Montenegro and Bosnia and Herzegovina a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks we&amp;#039;ll be looking at every country we aspire to visit this year and posting a bit about sites and areas that have caught our attention. This will hopefully culminate with a rough route plan. Hopefully we&amp;#039;ll be able to research some more Alps routes too. So stay tuned if you want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>