<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Equipment on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/tags/equipment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Equipment on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/africanuhambo.github.io/tags/equipment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Needed a lightweight stove</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 20:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/23/needed-a-lightweight-stove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, I needed to get a lightweight stove for a quick camping microadventure on Saturday night. I did not want to buy one and was considering self heating meals and no coffee in the morning. Until I found inspiration from a post on twitter to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/64726512&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by Tom Allen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to have a go at building my own also. I had some mentholated spirit for fuel, I just needed a drink can to make the stove. After a quick trip to the local shop, and with my thirst quenched I had my raw material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1013.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10131.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10132.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10133.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimmed the top and bottom sections. Bottom section is about 30mm high, the top is about 50mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2035.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20351.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creat flues in the side of the can with a knife. Small at the top. Large at the bottom. These form the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20352.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mate both sections&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20353.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ridges are critical. They are small at the top, large at the bottom. They form the fuel generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small hole using a pin just under the top lip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20354.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a small amount of fuel, approx 5mm deep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-20355.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light, wait 10 seconds for fuel to heat in the generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10134.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once hot the fuel vaporises in the side ridges, which is the generator the flames only burn on the outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10135.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about 5 minutes to boil two cups of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-1012.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weights very little too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-jun-2013-10121.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field test!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-jun-2013-2007.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised by the stove, it had no trouble heating my dinner or boiling water in my coffee maker. Just keep it out of the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know how these work. Check out this &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beverage-can_stove&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyWay Serengeti Modifications</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, we had some issues with the MyWay Serengeti tent, we loved it. But we need to get the niggles sorted. Luckily Paul was on hand with advice and apologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights in the tent we did discover the first issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top half cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base board, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically locked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in hight between the two plywood base halves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-1841.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to remedy this we installed some locating pegs, which are actually formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-18411.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second issue we found when we removed the tent from the Landy. This was that the lower half of the cover was holding a small amount of water. We had come back from France is some serious rain, I guess that must have made it through the overlap seal in the cover. I guess this would have been exacerbated by the fact we had to pack the tent away wet on the way back. Had we used the tent after the rain this would have had the chance to dry out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remedy this issue we cut some crosses into the lower cover about 20 mm in length, these are just two slices or lines that form a flap arrangement. We located these in three places. The first was central and the others were about 30 cm from each side in each corner on the hinge end of the tent. Hopefully any water collecting will have a route out now. I was originally planning to put five slots into the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess time will tell how these modifications work. We&amp;#039;ll let you know if we have an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myway Serengeti 1.6m Roof Tent &amp; Boab Roof Bars</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 15:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-aug-2012-2004.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been trying to find the right sleeping solution for the three of us since, pretty much the first trip we ever went on. The problem we have always had is that we would prefer to be able to wild camp or free camp, but having a family tent made this almost impossible. Not to mention the time it takes to put up and take down a larger tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years that followed we moved onto two small back packing tents one for Cassie and one for us. A two and three man. The plan being in camp sites we use both, in the bush we use one. What we often found though, was that it was hard to find a decent spot for the Landy and a three man tent. If we were walking it would have been fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used the family tent for two years, then the small tents for about two years. We eventually slimmed our arsenal of tents down to the family tent, which will be sold this year, it was only kept for the in-laws on this last trip; the three man backpacking tent we will keep for walking and biking; Cassie&amp;#039;s pop up tent and now the latest addition is a roof tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this trip we took the pop up tent and the new roof tent. The plan being that we would all sleep in the roof tent in the wild, then at campsites we would use both tents to allow us to get a good nights sleep, without being kicked and punched by Cassie all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enquiries about purchasing the roof tent started about 6 or 7 weeks before we left. We were hoping to go and check one out, then get one shortly after. What ended up happening actually, was that we got really busy and were not able to get to a place to see one, it was quite a way. What also happened was that we had to wait for a delivery from Cape Town, South Africa by sea. Luckily we were able to secure one of the items which had already departed in the next batch to be delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-21-jul-2012-1525.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up paying a deposit and hoping the tents would not be delayed in customs. They were supposed to clear by the first week of July. We thought that would be perfect as we could get a couple of nights camping in to make sure everything was ok. Inevitably that did not happen as you would expect, nothing is that simple. We managed to get the tent the Friday before we left. Paul from Myway came down from Doncaster to fit it and train us! Which was a nice touch. Needless to say the tent is superb. One thing led to another and we were not able to get out camping that weekend, so would have to just wait till the actual trip. Fingers crossed everything would be ok! In the end we did manage to find time on the Southdowns to practice putting it up and down including the shower curtain. We also managed to get a few pictures of the process. The pictures below were taken in France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 1 - Position Car&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1716.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 2 - Remove Cover and Insert Ladder&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1718.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 3 - Close the Door and reach for the ladder!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17181.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 4 - Rotate about the hinge and open&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17182.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 5 - Remember something you forgot.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17183.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 6 - Position ladder and fit stays for the flysheet&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1720.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      And Relax!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1719.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spoken at length with Paul, we ended up with a Serengeti 1.6m tent, we had originally wanted to get an Evolution because it was lighter and not canvas and we wanted a 1.8m as it was wider. Paul assured us that the Serengeti was a good choice and that a 1.6 was plenty wide enough for us and Cassie. He was so confident that he assured me if we were not happy we&amp;#039;d sort &#34;something&#34; out! The man proved to know his stuff. The other advantage of the Serengeti was that the canvas would keep the light out in the morning. We found it easy to sleep till nine at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing this so far, I&amp;#039;ve missed a beat, in between paying a deposit and getting the tent I had to find a platform to mount the tent to on top of the Landy. I spent quite a lot of time trying to work out if I wanted a roof rack or roof bars. Roof tents in general are heavy. Myway tents are lighter than most, the 1.6m we were waiting for weighed in at circa 50kg. Most are about 20kg more, with some hitting the 90kg mark for family models. A decent roof rack is about 40 to 50kg, with the Landy and a lot of other cars rated at about 100kg for roof loads, I&amp;#039;d want the lightest mounting system possible. Roof bars are about 5kg approximately each. It seemed an obvious choice considering we did not need a rack at the moment and could do with saving some money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1550.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found various bars around, I wanted something sturdy though. Really because of the off roading factor and mounting the awning. I toyed with getting some boab / mantec bars, I forget what they are called, but dismissed that because I was not convinced they were robust enough for us. Boab also, did some other bars called Boab bars in a 40mm x 40mm or 40mm x 20mm section. I opted for the 40mm square option. I ordered three of these as I needed to mount my awning using u-bolts. This offered a significant weight and cost saving over a rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Construction and Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of construction the tent is made on an aluminium base frame which uses stainless brackets and bolts with aluminium rivets in places, this has a marine ply base attached via captive nuts and bolts. The base frame has a bolted stainless hinge arrangement on either side of the frame, this is the point at which the aluminium hoop tubes attach which support the main tent canvas. The canvas hangs on the hoops, this allows the fly sheet to lay over the top of the whole arrangement. This leaves about a 40 or 50mm gap between the inner tent and flysheet, depending on how the two are adjusted. This gap allows plenty of airflow and is probably a contributing factor to the lack of condensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canvas inner tent is coated with a waterproofing agent, as is the flysheet. With this coating the canvas is free from the normal leaks you get on the first outing. This did not mean we escaped unscathed. We suffered a small amount of leaking on the first night due to the fly sheet being incorrectly adjusted and hanging on the inner canvas, it was a very minor leak and we did not see the issue again after we adjusted and experimented a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tent is delivered with about a 40mm sponge mattress and a fitted green sheet. The foam is covered in nylon so you need the sheet. The mattress cover is arranged such that it hindges in the middle and folds flat when the tent is packed away. We found the mattress fairly soft, so was easy to feel the base underneath, it took a little getting used to. We tended not to notice so much when we slept in sleeping bags in colder climates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to leave some bedding in the tent when it is packed away, but it must be folded flat before the tent is folded. It should be left on the fixed half of the tent. Failure to fold the bedding flat will result in it bunching when the tent is put away and putting extra strain on the hinge, which could lead to failure of the hinge if excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights we did discover one issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design. The cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically linked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in the two plywood base halves. In order to remedy this we will be installing some locating pegs, which will actually be formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the underside of the folding half of the tent a channel is mounted to the base. This allows the addition of a &#34;shower curtain&#34; which is essentially three sides of a walled room with no ground sheet and a small cut out for the ladder, the Landy forms the fourth wall. The ladder is outside the room. We tried this briefly on the Downs but never used this on the trip. The way we have the tent mounted means that it would provide shelter at the back of the Landy into the rear door during inclement weather, with the door open. The additional kit comes in a small bag, so is light enough to carry around. I just never want to have to use it. It takes 2 or 3 minutes to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appart from the minor niggle above, we had a great time with the Serengeti this holiday. We enjoyed the quick set up and pack away times. Wendy and I got quite a good routine established that meant we could put our feet up quicker and be on the road sooner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of the quick set up time means it gives more confidence for camping discreetly as it can be set up at dusk and packed away at dawn when no one is around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of quality, the construction is excellent and modular, so if something needs changing it can be and would be fairly simple, probably without having to go to Myway for spares. The only thing I would pick up Myway (the factory) on is the construction process. We found a lot of swarf in the tent and on the aluminium components. This was because the components are drilled during assembly, rather than drilled cleared and then assembled. It would not be hard to fix this process issue and would save some customer annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short I would not be able to compare against other roof tents as I have not had the chance to look at them, but I can say with confidence that the Myway Serengeti 1.6 meter is an excellent buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defender Split Charge - Version 2</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/08/defender-split-charge-version-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 19:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/08/defender-split-charge-version-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; During the trip last year into the Balkan states, we had a slight issue that the split charge contactor started failing to close. At first this was intermittent, then it became permanent in the heat. I was sometimes able to get it to close by tapping the contactor with a fair force. Eventually that did not even work. This of course was a serious issue for keeping our drinks cold!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120413-00172.jpg?w=351&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; alt=&#34;Albright Contactor&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got back to the UK, the fault disappeared completely. It appeared to be a heat related fault. Probably the coil or a mechanical failure. While we were on the road we tried to get a new contactor, but failed. There were plenty of relays around at about 30 amps, but I needed a 100 amp contactor. A 30 amp relay would have been fried in no time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that I would seek a decent quality replacement in the UK. I actually already knew that I would replace it with a sealed Albright contactor when we were back. This provided the ideal opportunity to refine the whole split charge, being one not to miss out on an opportunity. I did some other work also. The Albright is a sealed unit which means that if it should get wet in the battery box it is not an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This other work was really because. Having been installed for three years the deep cycle battery I had was starting to show symptoms of loosing capacity, which I suspected was caused by the low output of the 65 amp alternator being at around 13 volts. To rectify this, I decided to install a 100 amp alternator, to give me extra head room and also charge the batteries quicker. At a later stage I will need to improve the alternator output cable to something slightly thicker, at the moment it is the standard 16 mm cable. I will probably stick in some 25 mm cable. This runs from the alternator to the starter motor. You may ask yourself why I changed the alternator rather than overhaul it, which would have been far cheaper. The reason was purely because I needed the extra capacity in the 100 amp unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the alternator improvement and my output now at 14.4 volts again, I also fitted some decent Odessey deep cycle batteries. I did not want to fit decent batteries with a crap alternator, this would have just shortened their life. In the end I went for PC1500&amp;#039;s with the side terminals. These batteries are sealed units so they do not give off gas or fluid if they get hot. This has the benefit that my now clean battery box should stay corrosion free. Typically batteries gas, on a defender it means that you get that horrible white powder in the box and also excessive corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20119.jpg?w=302&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;302&#34; height=&#34;226&#34; alt=&#34;Jump cable socket&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the batteries I wanted to use the side terminals of the start battery for an Anderson connector. Connected via 35 mm cable. This would provide a convenient way to jump start people or for me to be jump started. I had some 4 meter jump leads made for the purpose. Access to the batteries is otherwise a real pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-24-may-2011-1234.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;247&#34; alt=&#34;4 meter jump leads&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the battery box itself, I re-treated the box with Hammerite to protect against corrosion, then mounted a Devon 4x4 twin battery tray. This was actually the second battery tray. I first tried to order a Flatdog tray, but that did not fit my Odessey batteries height wise. The reason was because the threaded bars were too short. I sold that one. Luckily the Devon 4x4 version was included in the battery package I wanted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08277.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original fuse panel I had fitted was also at capacity, I needed a bigger one. I decided to fit a 12 way fuse box with a positive and negative power bus. This makes connecting new loads really easy. While I was at the rewiring, I also connected the stereo to the Auxilary battery, the CB also and put a new power socket in the lockable cubby box. This would be for charging the laptop and iPad on the go. Whilst I was in there I moved the stereo USB connector into the cubby box. This mean the iPod or USB stick will be safe under lock and key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20113.jpg?w=390&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;390&#34; height=&#34;292&#34; alt=&#34;Odyssey Batteries &#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was in the under seat box, I also decided to remove the old immobiliser enclosure in the battery compartment. I stowed the wiring for now thou. I&amp;#039;ll deal with that later, but am fairly confident I could just cut the wiring!... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immobiliser housing took up a fair amount of space, which I felt I would at some stage need. Why you ask? I have a plan / idea that I would like to fit an 80 or 100 watt solar panel to the roof somehow. This would more than cover the fridge running in the day. If I do this I will probably use a CTEK DC-DC charger (DS250s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20116.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; alt=&#34;Fuse panel 12-way&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08274.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;12-way fuse panel in place&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the Albright contactor was mounted such that it was tucked into the corner out the way. I had planned to connect the contactor in such a way that it would be powered when the charge indicator extinguished. I also wanted a way for the contactor to be forced to close before the charge indicator extinguished, this would allow for easy self jump starting, if necessary. In order to facilitate this I have a switch on the dash with an LED indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20115.jpg?w=317&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;317&#34; height=&#34;423&#34; alt=&#34;Albright mounted&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-15-apr-2012-21101.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Split charge control switch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boab Braai</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/25/boab-braai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 09:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/25/boab-braai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have been going thru cheap portable braai&amp;#039;s (aka bbq&amp;#039;s) like cheap toilet paper. They are generally made of very thin pressed sheet steel and don&amp;#039;t last. The cost of these and the disposibles we occasionally resort to has begun to add up. So we have resorted to buying a decent portable... The Boab Braai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1100423.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-232&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We purchased the braai from Boab.biz in 2010, they import stuff from South Africa and have a nice expanding product range. The first impression you get when it turns up is the sheer weight of the thing. This is not a Braai you walk far with. We live about 600 meters from the beach and it is hard work carrying it down just that far! It is perfect in the back of the Landy thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As you will no doubt know this braai is fairly well travelled, it has been used in over 12 countries with us and is now about to be used on the third summer trek. It is now obviously fairly dirty, but a good clean now and again brings it back to life. The surprising thing is how well the paint work has held out. We have actually been fairly rubbish at cleaning it etc, left it in the rain and there is little sign of corrosion. This is obviously a desirable feature in a braai. I keep thinking I will need to touch the paint up, but have so far put it off as it is no where near bad yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1100424.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-231&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Boab Braai - Hard at work on the South Downs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of the nice things about the Boab Braai, is the grill is of a decent size. Meaning you can easily cook for about 5 people depending on what you are cooking. The grill is also a heavy duty mesh and frame so does not buckle or get damaged with repeated cleaning or time. You will also fail to loose sausages through the grill due to the grill having a square pattern!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of the nice features of the Boab Braai is that the lid also has legs and becomes a handy cooking table for beer and utensils. One feature of the lid we have not tried is the griddle. Perhaps soon. Thou. The braai also comes with a handy pot holding arm, we use this for utensils, as we generally use out petrol Coleman stove for pots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The only downside with the Braai, is that due to the dimensions and design it can be tricky to get started if you are complacent in setting up the coals. This is because there is no vents for air to get in at the base of the fire. Since I purchased the Boab Braai they have added a log burner base to the accessories which would adress this. In reality if you are an experience fire starter (twisted fire started, sorry...) this will not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The great thing about the Boab Braai is that the grade of material allows for a decnt camp fire after dinner. Just don&amp;#039;t get done by a forest ranger like we did, who promptly doused the Boab Braai with water!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Verdict: Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;Boab Braai Datasheet PDF&#34; href=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/boab-ultimate-braai-factsheet.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the data sheet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Leave a comment let us know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/boab-braai-complete-large.jpg?w=512&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-230&#34; width=&#34;410&#34; height=&#34;819&#34; alt=&#34;Boab Braai Complete&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weaco CF-18 Portable 12 Volt Fridge</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/21/weaco-cf-18-portable-12-volt-fridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 19:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/21/weaco-cf-18-portable-12-volt-fridge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/waeco-cf-18.jpg&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-212 alignleft&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;185&#34; alt=&#34;Waeco CF-18&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After two years of road trips into Europe and the prospect of more lengthy and exotic trips in the future, the struggle with not having enough cold beer got too much. We decided to look at our options for a portable car fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the land of 12 volt fridges all is not equal. The cheap ones you generally see in places like Halfords (local automotive accessory store) tend to work by making use of the Peltier Junction effect. Basically it is an electrical junction. You stick the fridge on one side of the junction and a heat sink and fan on the other. Electrically charge the junction blow the heat of the top and the other side gets cold. Simples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The downfall of these fridges is that they are generally quite power intensive and have a limited cooling differential from ambient. This is not ideal in warmer European countries, but may well be sufficient in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The better option is to get a fridge such as the Waeco CF-18, it has a Danfoss compressor, similar to that which is used in a standard fridge or air conditioner. The whole unit is fairly efficient and works on a refrigerant circuit the same as your fridge at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We got this fridge for Summer 2009, on the advice of a friend, who tends to buy decent stuff. We have now used it for three years in countries from Portugal to Montenegro. It is superb and will run for up to three days on our split charging system, depending on the temperature in the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/waeco-cf-18-diamentions.jpg?w=244&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-213 alignright&#34; width=&#34;244&#34; height=&#34;148&#34; alt=&#34;Waeco Dimensions&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One word of advice. This fridge has worked well for us. It would be nice to have a larger one thou, so buy bigger if you can afford to and can store it between trips. This fridge is big enough for two two litre bottles some small items of meat, yoghurt and butter and milk. Oh and the odd chocolate bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Secondly watch out for the insulation level. If the manufacturer offers an insulating sleeve or blanket buy it. It will help in the hottest environments. Remember you car parked in the sun with windows closed could easily reach over 45 degrees Celsius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120323-00107.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-240 alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Insulating Cover&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cover for the CF-18 seems to be of a reasonable quality, a decent fit , with lashing eyes and additional pockets. It will cost about an extra £35 delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom is removable, by using the zipper provided. The foil lining should make for easy cleaning. The only downside is the black top material, a light grey would have been better. Having said that thou the material is certainly tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120323-00120.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-239 alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Insulating Cover Removable Bottom&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120323-001141.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-242&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Insulating Cover Vent&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Verdict: If you are after a smaller Fridge. We would definitely recommend this fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Others to consider are National Luna and Engel. For an in depth review of bigger 12 volt fridges check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.expeditionportal.com/resources/equipment-review-and-testing/556-overland-journal-portable-12v-fridge-review.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post on Expedition Portal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What fridge do you use on Overland journeys? Leave a comment and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>