<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Camping on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/camping/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Camping on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/camping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 - Koplic, Lake Shkrodër</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to stay two nights at Lake Shkodër. Today we woke slowly, having been woken by Cassie in the middle of the night again. After we finally dragged her sleeping items into the tent, thunder rolled in. There had been a little rain too, but not a significant amount. Needless to say, it was a little bit of a restless night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was warming up already by mid morning, and I had decided that the sheets, towels and pillow cases needed to be washed. We also needed to get some food. We asked the owner of the campsite if here was a shop close by and he said yes, just walk up to the main road, over the bridge and there is a shop there. So we handed over our washing, as he had a machine, and set off for the shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1130897.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked we were shocked by the rubbish we saw on the side of the road and dumped in ditches, We passed two young boys by the overpass burning their rubbish. It was a reminder that Albania still had ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were perspiring by the time we got to the shop and had to stop for a cold drink at one of the bars. Afterwards we went to the shop and bought essentials .. water, beer, biscuits and other food items. Now for the walk back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the campsite, Cassie made friends with a young girl from a German family staying a few pitches down. She played all afternoon with Lea and her brother Nic. It was nice for her to have company, and Lea wanted to practice her English as she had recently started learning it at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day Thunder had been rumbling in the background but despite this, it had been warm and sunny.. with a slight cloudy haze. But by afternoon, the lightening started making an appearance and we decided to pack up Cassie&#39;s tent and head for the restaurant/bar. And a good thing we did, as the heavens opened with an almighty bang and gush of wind and it did not let up for hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had grabbed a table inside and here we stayed for the most of the evening. Eventually to be joined by Frank and Anjita, Cassie&#39;s new found friends&#39; parents. The evening was great. We swopped travelling stories, places to visit and even swopped blog addresses. It&#39;s always nice to make friends along the way, so thanks Fank and Anjita for a great evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a second Land Rover at the camp, owned by a Scottish couple that were travelling. We had spoken to them the day before about their set up and swopped maps for tips on places to travel. Anyway, Gus and Helen also ended up at the bar/restaurant and as our table was already full, they sat with a trio of Austrian guys next door to us. As the evening progressed, they ended up joining our table too. We all had a wonderful time drinking wine and beer and swopping stories. Thanks Gus and Helen for your tips and your extending fork!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0134.jpeg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyWay Serengeti Modifications</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;, we had some issues with the MyWay Serengeti tent, we loved it. But we need to get the niggles sorted. Luckily Paul was on hand with advice and apologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights in the tent we did discover the first issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top half cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base board, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically locked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in hight between the two plywood base halves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-1841.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to remedy this we installed some locating pegs, which are actually formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-oct-2012-18411.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second issue we found when we removed the tent from the Landy. This was that the lower half of the cover was holding a small amount of water. We had come back from France is some serious rain, I guess that must have made it through the overlap seal in the cover. I guess this would have been exacerbated by the fact we had to pack the tent away wet on the way back. Had we used the tent after the rain this would have had the chance to dry out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remedy this issue we cut some crosses into the lower cover about 20 mm in length, these are just two slices or lines that form a flap arrangement. We located these in three places. The first was central and the others were about 30 cm from each side in each corner on the hinge end of the tent. Hopefully any water collecting will have a route out now. I was originally planning to put five slots into the cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess time will tell how these modifications work. We&amp;#039;ll let you know if we have an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Jafferau and Lago Di Rochemolles</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1220.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125197.9639&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track Up To Fort Jafferau &#34; width=&#34;417&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After spending the night at &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/&#34;&gt;Fort Pramond&lt;/a&gt;, we had a plan today to driver up to Mount Jafferau then on to a nearby Lake that is now a reservoir, we were hoping to spend the night by the river there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to pack up fairly promptly and were on the way by the time the day was heating up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-0911.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125203.729&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Exit of the exciting tunnel&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was kind of excited about the day, because we were heading along a track that showed a cool tunnel on the map. I dunno how I came to that conclusion,  just by looking at the map. The tunnel on the track is circa 800 meters long, unlit, unpaved and leaks more than you would see in a normal road tunnel as it is not lined. This leak leads to a stream of water in the tunnel that is often a few inches deep. Oh and the end never seemed to appear, leading to a further sense of excitement under the dim light of the Landys head lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1213.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125156.5093&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Jafferau&#34; width=&#34;358&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The other thing about the day that excited me was the climb to the Fort on Mount Jafferau, this sits at circa 2800 meters and promises spectacular views. We were not let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Most of the track up to Jafferau is easy in a 4 x 4, I am not sure how far you&amp;#039;d want to go in a ordinary car. There are some fairly rocky sections, not hard but difficult in most cars. If the weather was bad, you would not consider it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the way up to Mount Jafferau, we were listening on the CB to other people that we could not see. We could hear that they were watching us, as they were mentioning the English vehicles. Even with the aid of the binoculars we could not see who was watching us and nor could we find them. It was rather creepy being in a valley, with all the ex military sites and the creepy night we had the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The track we were following stopped at Jafferau... Sort of. We had a plan to asses the situation at the end. This was because we had a map that showed a 500 meter foot path then the start of a new track down the other side of Mount Jafferau. Well when we got there we found that there was a track down, that was fairly steep and circa 1000m descent. Linking the track up and the track down was actually the easy bit. We did the whole descent in low range 1st gear, but had to occasionally slow the descent a little on top. It was great because we were following the Ski run literally, so naturally this led to us arriving at the top of the bubble lift and at the restaurant at the top of the lift. A convenient place to stop for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1311.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125181.358&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Nice Lunch Stop&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel had a double helping of home made Lasagne, made by the Owners Wife and Wendy and I had a local platter of meats and cheeses. After a good fill. We carried on our descent, we had about another thousand meters to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed down towards Bardonecchia to pick up the track to take us up to the Lake for the next night. Unfortunately we found the/a track but could not find our way onto the one we wanted that led to the lake. We ended up back tracking and taking a scenic road that met up with the track we needed. The track was really easy and fairly pleasant if busy. You could have done this section in a car. Apart from going to the actual camping spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1546.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125152.4119&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Valley of Lago di Rochemolles &#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;107&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The road continues on from where we camped to one of the highest glaciers you can drive to in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1702.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125163.2832&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Refreshing Bath&#34; width=&#34;341&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We stopped for the evening at the river that feeds Lago di Rochemolles, it was obviously icy cold, but was great for a very invigorating bath and cooling some Prosecco. The valley was very scenic and a great stop for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1704.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125195.692&#34; class=&#34;alignnone&#34; alt=&#34;Cutting Wood&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;263&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we had a proper fire in a pit made by some predecessors, we managed to find enough wood nearby and an old sauce pan to warm water for washing up. Dinner that night was slightly left field. We had failed to stop for more supplies since our last supermarket stop, we had some powdered soup from Croatia. This was very nice, I think it was called Dalmation soup.... We also had three military ration packs, which had been given to us by John in Cinque terra. Our plan was to enjoy these as pudding after we had the roast potatoes. Unfortunately being military ration novices what we cooked for pudding was awful. I feel for the boys who eat them, this looked off. So we ended up going to bed a bit hungry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Update: I have since learnt that the packs last for 10 years. Sorry John. If you are reading this John, we lost your email address, hope you had a cool trip. It was great having a BBQ with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-2043.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125179.4502&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Girls Washing up.&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;233&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping by a stream led to a lot of night time pees. In the morning we woke stinking of smoke. Had breakfast and headed for the road. It was here, well in Bardonecchia we would say bye for a few days to Carole and Daniel. Obviously we did this over coffee and pastries. They were heading to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-17021.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125165.5713&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our Spot&#34; width=&#34;363&#34; height=&#34;272&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We from hear ambled our way via a few one night stops home, as usual once we got half way up France the heavens opened and we just headed back to the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>