<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preparation on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/preparation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preparation on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/preparation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair done</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 17:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130724-184907.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The landy is now back to normal the whole repair is done, seats are in soundproofing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have the fun of packing for the trip. Sorry I did not take a picture of the finished article! But the picture above shows the first of three seats fitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must dash need to iron my pants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upriser/Upstand in</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 16:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not quite as far as I would have liked today. Missed the nut and bolt store. They close at 1400 on a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to get the Upstand and floor fitted and the two central seat brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130720-173701.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow when my drill is charged again, I&#39;ll get ready for the last two seat brackets, when I get the bolts on Monday they&#39;ll be fitted. I should also be able to refit the sound proofing tomorrow, that is the rubber chequer plate stuff from write off road. As sold to the MOD. I had not finished fitting it due to this repair, needing to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am going for a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There Upstand Assembly</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0109.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much of an update tonight, with the ongoing repair apart from to show some pictures of the panel now it has been fully tweaked and drilled to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished of the drilling tonight and deburred everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final job for the night was to give another coat of etch primer and paint the seat brackets and new panels with stone chip paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are now drying, so tomorrow I&#39;ll start fitting it for real. The only thing I need to do is drill the seat brackets in location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful with a push, I should have it done tomorrow or Sunday at the latest. Not wishing to tempt fate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0111.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Upstand/Upriser Re-Assembly</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0091.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now at the stage of re-assembly. It has been a slow road even to strip the back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mid-crossmember is galvanised and from YRM metal solutions. One of the nice features of the new one, is that the top brackets are loose rather than welded on this makes it easier to get the cross member under the fuel pipes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have had with the crossmember is that the holes, for mounting to the chassis rails where about 3mm out across the vehicle. I am not entirely sure why, but I eventually managed to get the bolts in. I suspect it may have been partially due to the camber of the road. I&#39;ve used stainless bolts so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0095.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note on the cross member is that the cut out for the fuel hoses on my vehicle is in the wrong location. This probably varies from vehicle to vehicle. One was YRM could improve this is to have a wider cut out. I have added additional protection and will tywrap the hoses out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the crossmember was in it was time to start fitting the upstand/upriser. The new item is a different size to the old one. In a good way. The lips are about another 10mm deep. This means that around the top a certain amount of fitting is required, this is around the spars under the floor and the doubler between the separate sections of floor near the doors. I only cut out these areas, I like the idea of the extra depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new item seemed longer also, I did not have to cut it down. The reason is that the old panel was tapered making the top shorter than the bottom edge. I spaced it evenly each side and it seems ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0102.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fitting done, I have now dry fitted it, drilled the holes for the top rivets and will tomorrow drill the sides pieces and seat brackets. At the moment the rivets are all loose. I will strip it out and paint it once I have dry assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The floor is in with a couple of screws at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair continues</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130717-141934.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll need to forgive the posts at the moment, they are short and sweet. This is because I am under pressure and because I am feeling guilty about not posting, all I would like to on what has happened and what I want to happen. I am doing them on the run with the Wordpress app.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow an update on the floor repair of the landy. The second row floor is out. This was a bit of hassle as all the screws were seized. I have no power at the vehicle so a grinder was not an option. The up stand/ upriser is out and the mid cross member is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also cleaned up around the mid cross member mountings and put stone chip paint on it to give it some protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0086.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand Corrosion Repair</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130715-194202.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promised to do some posts about our planned trip, which we are due to depart on in 11 days. As of now we have not even booked the channel tunnel crossing or got our international driving permits. We are cutting it fine this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo shows some horrible corrosion I needed to get fixed before we go. It is in the area of the second row seat brackets on the upstand. Fairly typical of what happens when you combine steel and aluminium. Electrolytic corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I am in the throws of stripping the floor and getting the panel out. The end caps were particularly hard due to a hidden solid rivet under the c post bracket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New panels are from YRM, I got the upstanding and end brackets from them. I also have a galvanised crossmember I am not sure if I will fit that yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to post more pictures as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130715-195412.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Warm Up and Last Minute Fuel Pump Change</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 08:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-30-may-2013-1644.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend we got lucky with the weather, mostly. We spent a couple of nights camping in Wales. On the way we decided we&amp;#039;d break the journey, by stopping the night at a pub that allows camping in their garden. So we stopped in Wiltshire at The Parish Lantern, highly recommended. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole journey avoided the motorways and took us through many little interesting towns and funny back roads, on the way back we managed to include a couple of green lanes near Salisbury and the Stone Henge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1518.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1536.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to departure, I thought I&amp;#039;d change the fuel filter, the Landy will get it&amp;#039;s service any day, but in the mean time I though that I&amp;#039;d do the filter because I felt it had been a bit sluggish when I had occasionally driven it over the winter. As you&amp;#039;d expect the filter was quick and easy to change. But.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems occurred during priming, I was not able to prime the filter with the lift pump handle. I though it may have been the position of the pump lever on the cam, flicking the engine over a few times did not improve that. I managed to get the engine started though after several attempts without the lift pump for assistance, then just to confirm my suspicion cracking the bleed screw on the filter housing did not give a stream of diesel. This in my eyes proved the lift pump was failed and that it was not pressurising the filter, etc. It was getting late on the night before we left at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I had a new genuine lift pump in my spares box complete with olives, nuts and gasket. I would have to make a decision. Live with it and fit a new one on return or fit the spare in the morning before we left. The problem is that I did not want to have a sluggish vehicle on a long journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the task seemed mostly simple I took the gamble to fit it in the morning. In the pouring rain. My only apprehension was that the bolts to the block interface plate could be seized. They were not, so after establishing that, I spent an hour and the problem was fixed. Pump on and decent pressure restored at the pump bleed screw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside of it all was that we got off earlier on our weekend trip and managed to have an early pint at the pub we stayed at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the annual trip approaching over the next couple of weeks, I have to get a service done on the Landy and fix the second row seat up riser corrosion which is a big job. For that I managed to get a galvanised mid cross member from YRM metal solutions together with the aluminium panels I need. I just hope I can get it all apart! I&amp;#039;ll keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirations for 2013&#39;s Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 19:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2013-1900.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as I mentioned earlier in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, we have been thinking about what we might do this summer. Actually we have been thinking since last summer. I guess we are probably not alone on this, we tend to think from trip to trip, from day to day, even during a trip. I guess most people who enjoy travelling have this problem. Is it wrong? I don&amp;#039;t want to wish my life away, but I love thinking about possibilities, getting the map out while drinking wine or beer in camp. Is that dreamin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us we have been to lots of places in Europe, we still have much of Northern Europe to go and places on our own door step such as Scotland and Ireland, but the weather makes life tricky in those places. We don&amp;#039;t want to be confined, confined to a hotel. We want the option to camp, we like camping. No we are not poor, we just like to get away from it. I camp in hotels all year for work, I really don&amp;#039;t like it. So I guess sooner or later we need to take the plunge and face the weather, before we loose the opportunity to see the places we take for granted on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we have been thinking about travel this August. Unfortunately during tourist season, we are bound to this because of school holidays, we tend to get away lightly due to the places we visit, not always. Our plans have been a little hampered this year, domestics are getting in the way! We had to have the kitchen done... I guess you are wondering what the hell I am on. Well it is all about economics. The kitchen cost a fortune (it is still not finished). This has hampered our trip money saving ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this has meant that, although we have &amp;#039;planned&amp;#039;, the plan is more of an &amp;#039;aspiration&amp;#039;. Let me explain. I guess what we are saying is that, we refuse to give up the opportunity of our annual trip. Regardless of how far we have saved, we&amp;#039;ll see how far we can go on what we&amp;#039;ve got! So if we don&amp;#039;t know what we will be able to do we should plan for what we&amp;#039;d like to do. So I guess you&amp;#039;d say plan for your aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that explained. We&amp;#039;d like this year to explore some more dirt roads in the Alps, there is a warren up there and plenty of places to wild camp without having to part with Euros. After that we&amp;#039;d also like to explore Kosovo, Albania and Macedonia. These are completely new to us and potentially very exciting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-may-2013-2022.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we get from the Alps to Albania and the surrounding areas, would either be by road or by sea. We used a ferry last year from Bari to Croatia which made life very easy, but expensive. The easiest ferry option for Albania is from Ancona to Durrës. This costs circa €400 but saves probably about three days in raw driving, that is really more because we stop and take a non direct route. The ferry crossing is around 20 hours. The saving is definitely not in fuel, even in a Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of getting to Albania from Ancona, is that we can use the days saved to spend more time exploring before heading back, it is probably about 1500 miles (2600 km) to Brighton from there. Which would be about 7 days driving, we&amp;#039;d need to allow about 10 so we could chill a bit. This would leave us about 2 weeks in the area we want to be. In reality I&amp;#039;d hope to be able to build some of the return days into the route to allow us to look at possibly Kosovo, Montenegro and Bosnia and Herzegovina a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks we&amp;#039;ll be looking at every country we aspire to visit this year and posting a bit about sites and areas that have caught our attention. This will hopefully culminate with a rough route plan. Hopefully we&amp;#039;ll be able to research some more Alps routes too. So stay tuned if you want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready for the Summer</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 17:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-26-may-2013-1303.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the weather getting better and a short camping trip planned for next weekend, we decided this weekend was probably the most sensible time to get the tent on the Landy and the awning set up, ready for opportunities to go camping and the summer trip. The other good thing given that this weekend is a bank holiday is that next weekend should be quieter! The roads and transport systems in the UK just can&amp;#039;t cope when we all decide to move in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a friend giving me a lift getting the roof tent on was a breeze. This year, I have made some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first. The tent is mounted about 6 or 8 inches further forward. This I am hoping will make the car feel a little more stable, while still allowing the rear door to open easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second tweak, was to fit some locating pegs to the back of the tent to remedy the problem I mentioned in this blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that caused the base to sag and create an uncomfortable step. I&amp;#039;ll write about that further &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/&#34;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually we also made a third tweak. That was to create some drain holes in the lower side of the tent cover. We noticed when we removed the tent last year that we had some water sitting in the bottom of the cover. These holes should allow moisture to be dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to another thing I should mention. We have been working on ideas for the summer, we intend this year to again go on a &amp;#039;Big&amp;#039; trip. Note that I say ideas and not planning or plans. Why? Well we are not sure if our aspirations will match our plans. We had to have some house work done this year that cost a small fortune. We&amp;#039;ll reveal more in the near future on the trip though. So stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit to the Map Shop - Stanfords</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 18:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/image.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves at a loose end this morning, the weather was iffy. So we took a pleasant ride into London for a wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are considering are plans for the summer so decided we&#39;d pop to the map shop in London. Those of you who don&#39;t know it. This is probably the best place to purchase maps and travel books in London. It has three floors of books and maps normally in the scale you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a Bradt Albania Guide, a 1:150k Kosovo map, 1:200k Albania map, 1:400 Bulgaria map and 1:500k Romania / Moldova map, the latter two are not ideal scales for what we need but they&#39;ll do. I&#39;ll probably get better scales if I can find them. Unfortunately I could not find a decent Macedonia map so had to resort to Amazon for that and a Kosovo and Macedonia guide book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance you should pop in, it is a pretty cool shop!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myway Serengeti 1.6m Roof Tent &amp; Boab Roof Bars</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 15:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-aug-2012-2004.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been trying to find the right sleeping solution for the three of us since, pretty much the first trip we ever went on. The problem we have always had is that we would prefer to be able to wild camp or free camp, but having a family tent made this almost impossible. Not to mention the time it takes to put up and take down a larger tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years that followed we moved onto two small back packing tents one for Cassie and one for us. A two and three man. The plan being in camp sites we use both, in the bush we use one. What we often found though, was that it was hard to find a decent spot for the Landy and a three man tent. If we were walking it would have been fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used the family tent for two years, then the small tents for about two years. We eventually slimmed our arsenal of tents down to the family tent, which will be sold this year, it was only kept for the in-laws on this last trip; the three man backpacking tent we will keep for walking and biking; Cassie&amp;#039;s pop up tent and now the latest addition is a roof tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this trip we took the pop up tent and the new roof tent. The plan being that we would all sleep in the roof tent in the wild, then at campsites we would use both tents to allow us to get a good nights sleep, without being kicked and punched by Cassie all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enquiries about purchasing the roof tent started about 6 or 7 weeks before we left. We were hoping to go and check one out, then get one shortly after. What ended up happening actually, was that we got really busy and were not able to get to a place to see one, it was quite a way. What also happened was that we had to wait for a delivery from Cape Town, South Africa by sea. Luckily we were able to secure one of the items which had already departed in the next batch to be delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-21-jul-2012-1525.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up paying a deposit and hoping the tents would not be delayed in customs. They were supposed to clear by the first week of July. We thought that would be perfect as we could get a couple of nights camping in to make sure everything was ok. Inevitably that did not happen as you would expect, nothing is that simple. We managed to get the tent the Friday before we left. Paul from Myway came down from Doncaster to fit it and train us! Which was a nice touch. Needless to say the tent is superb. One thing led to another and we were not able to get out camping that weekend, so would have to just wait till the actual trip. Fingers crossed everything would be ok! In the end we did manage to find time on the Southdowns to practice putting it up and down including the shower curtain. We also managed to get a few pictures of the process. The pictures below were taken in France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 1 - Position Car&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1716.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 2 - Remove Cover and Insert Ladder&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1718.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 3 - Close the Door and reach for the ladder!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17181.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 4 - Rotate about the hinge and open&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17182.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 5 - Remember something you forgot.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-17183.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Step 6 - Position ladder and fit stays for the flysheet&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1720.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      And Relax!&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-29-jul-2012-1719.jpg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spoken at length with Paul, we ended up with a Serengeti 1.6m tent, we had originally wanted to get an Evolution because it was lighter and not canvas and we wanted a 1.8m as it was wider. Paul assured us that the Serengeti was a good choice and that a 1.6 was plenty wide enough for us and Cassie. He was so confident that he assured me if we were not happy we&amp;#039;d sort &#34;something&#34; out! The man proved to know his stuff. The other advantage of the Serengeti was that the canvas would keep the light out in the morning. We found it easy to sleep till nine at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In writing this so far, I&amp;#039;ve missed a beat, in between paying a deposit and getting the tent I had to find a platform to mount the tent to on top of the Landy. I spent quite a lot of time trying to work out if I wanted a roof rack or roof bars. Roof tents in general are heavy. Myway tents are lighter than most, the 1.6m we were waiting for weighed in at circa 50kg. Most are about 20kg more, with some hitting the 90kg mark for family models. A decent roof rack is about 40 to 50kg, with the Landy and a lot of other cars rated at about 100kg for roof loads, I&amp;#039;d want the lightest mounting system possible. Roof bars are about 5kg approximately each. It seemed an obvious choice considering we did not need a rack at the moment and could do with saving some money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1550.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found various bars around, I wanted something sturdy though. Really because of the off roading factor and mounting the awning. I toyed with getting some boab / mantec bars, I forget what they are called, but dismissed that because I was not convinced they were robust enough for us. Boab also, did some other bars called Boab bars in a 40mm x 40mm or 40mm x 20mm section. I opted for the 40mm square option. I ordered three of these as I needed to mount my awning using u-bolts. This offered a significant weight and cost saving over a rack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Construction and Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of construction the tent is made on an aluminium base frame which uses stainless brackets and bolts with aluminium rivets in places, this has a marine ply base attached via captive nuts and bolts. The base frame has a bolted stainless hinge arrangement on either side of the frame, this is the point at which the aluminium hoop tubes attach which support the main tent canvas. The canvas hangs on the hoops, this allows the fly sheet to lay over the top of the whole arrangement. This leaves about a 40 or 50mm gap between the inner tent and flysheet, depending on how the two are adjusted. This gap allows plenty of airflow and is probably a contributing factor to the lack of condensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canvas inner tent is coated with a waterproofing agent, as is the flysheet. With this coating the canvas is free from the normal leaks you get on the first outing. This did not mean we escaped unscathed. We suffered a small amount of leaking on the first night due to the fly sheet being incorrectly adjusted and hanging on the inner canvas, it was a very minor leak and we did not see the issue again after we adjusted and experimented a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tent is delivered with about a 40mm sponge mattress and a fitted green sheet. The foam is covered in nylon so you need the sheet. The mattress cover is arranged such that it hindges in the middle and folds flat when the tent is packed away. We found the mattress fairly soft, so was easy to feel the base underneath, it took a little getting used to. We tended not to notice so much when we slept in sleeping bags in colder climates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to leave some bedding in the tent when it is packed away, but it must be folded flat before the tent is folded. It should be left on the fixed half of the tent. Failure to fold the bedding flat will result in it bunching when the tent is put away and putting extra strain on the hinge, which could lead to failure of the hinge if excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few nights we did discover one issue with the tent, which we now have a solution for. This came about due to a design change, apparently ours is one of the first of a new design. The cross member behind the hinge tended to sag by approx 10mm, this put a noticeable step in the middle of the base, between the two halves of the tent. Unfortunately we could feel this through the mattress. Tents before the design change had some locating pegs to ensure the cross members of the two halves were mechanically linked, so any sag was minimised and mutual, this most importantly avoided a difference in the two plywood base halves. In order to remedy this we will be installing some locating pegs, which will actually be formed by the cap heads of some stainless steel bolts. These will interface to locating holes on the second half cross member which folds down. The important thing about this issue was that it did not prevent us from enjoying the tent and when we got back, Paul offered some brilliant support for discussion to come up with a solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the underside of the folding half of the tent a channel is mounted to the base. This allows the addition of a &#34;shower curtain&#34; which is essentially three sides of a walled room with no ground sheet and a small cut out for the ladder, the Landy forms the fourth wall. The ladder is outside the room. We tried this briefly on the Downs but never used this on the trip. The way we have the tent mounted means that it would provide shelter at the back of the Landy into the rear door during inclement weather, with the door open. The additional kit comes in a small bag, so is light enough to carry around. I just never want to have to use it. It takes 2 or 3 minutes to install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appart from the minor niggle above, we had a great time with the Serengeti this holiday. We enjoyed the quick set up and pack away times. Wendy and I got quite a good routine established that meant we could put our feet up quicker and be on the road sooner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The benefit of the quick set up time means it gives more confidence for camping discreetly as it can be set up at dusk and packed away at dawn when no one is around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of quality, the construction is excellent and modular, so if something needs changing it can be and would be fairly simple, probably without having to go to Myway for spares. The only thing I would pick up Myway (the factory) on is the construction process. We found a lot of swarf in the tent and on the aluminium components. This was because the components are drilled during assembly, rather than drilled cleared and then assembled. It would not be hard to fix this process issue and would save some customer annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short I would not be able to compare against other roof tents as I have not had the chance to look at them, but I can say with confidence that the Myway Serengeti 1.6 meter is an excellent buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get one!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defender Split Charge - Version 2</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/defender-split-charge-version-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 19:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/defender-split-charge-version-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; During the trip last year into the Balkan states, we had a slight issue that the split charge contactor started failing to close. At first this was intermittent, then it became permanent in the heat. I was sometimes able to get it to close by tapping the contactor with a fair force. Eventually that did not even work. This of course was a serious issue for keeping our drinks cold!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img-20120413-00172.jpg?w=351&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; alt=&#34;Albright Contactor&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got back to the UK, the fault disappeared completely. It appeared to be a heat related fault. Probably the coil or a mechanical failure. While we were on the road we tried to get a new contactor, but failed. There were plenty of relays around at about 30 amps, but I needed a 100 amp contactor. A 30 amp relay would have been fried in no time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that I would seek a decent quality replacement in the UK. I actually already knew that I would replace it with a sealed Albright contactor when we were back. This provided the ideal opportunity to refine the whole split charge, being one not to miss out on an opportunity. I did some other work also. The Albright is a sealed unit which means that if it should get wet in the battery box it is not an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This other work was really because. Having been installed for three years the deep cycle battery I had was starting to show symptoms of loosing capacity, which I suspected was caused by the low output of the 65 amp alternator being at around 13 volts. To rectify this, I decided to install a 100 amp alternator, to give me extra head room and also charge the batteries quicker. At a later stage I will need to improve the alternator output cable to something slightly thicker, at the moment it is the standard 16 mm cable. I will probably stick in some 25 mm cable. This runs from the alternator to the starter motor. You may ask yourself why I changed the alternator rather than overhaul it, which would have been far cheaper. The reason was purely because I needed the extra capacity in the 100 amp unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the alternator improvement and my output now at 14.4 volts again, I also fitted some decent Odessey deep cycle batteries. I did not want to fit decent batteries with a crap alternator, this would have just shortened their life. In the end I went for PC1500&amp;#039;s with the side terminals. These batteries are sealed units so they do not give off gas or fluid if they get hot. This has the benefit that my now clean battery box should stay corrosion free. Typically batteries gas, on a defender it means that you get that horrible white powder in the box and also excessive corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20119.jpg?w=302&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;302&#34; height=&#34;226&#34; alt=&#34;Jump cable socket&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the batteries I wanted to use the side terminals of the start battery for an Anderson connector. Connected via 35 mm cable. This would provide a convenient way to jump start people or for me to be jump started. I had some 4 meter jump leads made for the purpose. Access to the batteries is otherwise a real pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-24-may-2011-1234.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;247&#34; alt=&#34;4 meter jump leads&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the battery box itself, I re-treated the box with Hammerite to protect against corrosion, then mounted a Devon 4x4 twin battery tray. This was actually the second battery tray. I first tried to order a Flatdog tray, but that did not fit my Odessey batteries height wise. The reason was because the threaded bars were too short. I sold that one. Luckily the Devon 4x4 version was included in the battery package I wanted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08277.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original fuse panel I had fitted was also at capacity, I needed a bigger one. I decided to fit a 12 way fuse box with a positive and negative power bus. This makes connecting new loads really easy. While I was at the rewiring, I also connected the stereo to the Auxilary battery, the CB also and put a new power socket in the lockable cubby box. This would be for charging the laptop and iPad on the go. Whilst I was in there I moved the stereo USB connector into the cubby box. This mean the iPod or USB stick will be safe under lock and key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20113.jpg?w=390&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;390&#34; height=&#34;292&#34; alt=&#34;Odyssey Batteries &#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was in the under seat box, I also decided to remove the old immobiliser enclosure in the battery compartment. I stowed the wiring for now thou. I&amp;#039;ll deal with that later, but am fairly confident I could just cut the wiring!... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immobiliser housing took up a fair amount of space, which I felt I would at some stage need. Why you ask? I have a plan / idea that I would like to fit an 80 or 100 watt solar panel to the roof somehow. This would more than cover the fridge running in the day. If I do this I will probably use a CTEK DC-DC charger (DS250s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20116.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; alt=&#34;Fuse panel 12-way&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08274.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;12-way fuse panel in place&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the Albright contactor was mounted such that it was tucked into the corner out the way. I had planned to connect the contactor in such a way that it would be powered when the charge indicator extinguished. I also wanted a way for the contactor to be forced to close before the charge indicator extinguished, this would allow for easy self jump starting, if necessary. In order to facilitate this I have a switch on the dash with an LED indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20115.jpg?w=317&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;317&#34; height=&#34;423&#34; alt=&#34;Albright mounted&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-15-apr-2012-21101.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Split charge control switch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lafayette Venus CB Radio Install</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/06/10/lafayette-venus-cb-radio-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 09:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/06/10/lafayette-venus-cb-radio-install/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-2011.jpg?w=225&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; alt=&#34;CB Antenna Mounting Location on the back of the Defender&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been meaning to install a CB radio for several years, I finally got round to it this year. On the last few trips, we have found that we could have done with a CB to communicate with others in the group at various stages. It is not always possible to depend on mobile phones for short range and duration communications. Apart from the issues and expense of roaming outside UK, the connection time is too long and the likelihood of a reliable signal is low when in a remote location.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been looking at various models of CB for a while, I wanted a euro compatible model as I would most likely use the CB abroad more than in the UK. This would allow me to switch the frequency range to suit which ever country we are visiting. The other important requirement was a unit that would take up little room in the Defender cab. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the suppliers had pretty much the same range of products, prices did vary slightly. All seemed to do various kits or packages. I was not after a sophisticated CB as long as it covered the Euro zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-6-jun-2012-2016.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;198&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much browsing and looking at reviews, I narrowed my choice down to two. These are the Intek M-100 Plus and the Lafayette Venus. Both are small units, the Intek is narrow at 100mm wide and about 37mm high, but has made up for its slender face by being slightly long at about 200mm including the rear plug and front knobs. The Intek has the a fairly conventional layout with a simple handset and the main unit housing the controls and display. The Venus CB unit is also slender at 108mm wide, 29mm high and 136mm deep. The big difference of the Venus from the Intek is that the layout is not that conventional. It has a plain base unit, with a fairly complex handset that houses the display and all the controls. This gives the Venus a fairly complex look. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20117.jpg?w=224&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;224&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20111.jpg?w=224&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;224&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage of the Venus layout is the base unit is discreet. This is the main attraction to me. In many countries CB is illegal or at least frowned upon. So in the case of the Venus, I can simple disconnect the handset and stow it out of sight and also unscrew the antenna from the rear of the vehicle. This will mean that it should not be noticed that we have a CB at any borders. I can go one step further also. The unit has a power connector so to completely remove the base unit it is simply a matter of disconnecting power and antenna plugs, these stow being the fuse panel in the Defender out of sight and the base unit can be hidden anywhere. In the picture on the right you can see how the cables would be stowed behind the cover to the left of the CB unit. I had considered mounting the module under the cubby box or inside the cubby box, but in the end I decided against it for amongst other reasons heat dissipation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-6-jun-2012-2024.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;269&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am in the strange situation this year, that I actually am travelling with people from the outset and needed to source a CB for them also. This gave rise to the opportunity to buy both the Intek and the Lafayette. The Intek should be good for their use as it is easy to stow and use in an adhoc manner thanks to the 12 volt plug that is fitted. This gives the opportunity to test both radios for a month on the road. If the Venus turns out to be a dog, then I&amp;#039;ll swap for the Intek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-6-jun-2012-2034.jpg?w=180&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that I would mount the antenna to the rear of the vehicle with a body mount. This position allows the antenna to be mounted high, which should aid the range of the CB, it also proved fairly easy to get a decent SWR reading, though out both the UK and Euro bands I get a maximum reading of Circa 1.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may have to review this antenna location once we fit the roof tent. I hope to mount the tent on the front half of the vehicle thou. Which should avoid issues with SWR changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For power I connected the CB positive and negative directly to the fuse panel linked to my secondary battery. This ensures I do not increase the risk on the start battery and also ensures I have a decent earth to the vehicle and hence the antenna ground plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once powered up the CB is surprisingly intuitive to use. Power, volume and channel selection are carried out via the top three buttons. Scanning and squelch via the buttons on the front. I have not had a chance to carry out and decent conversations yet, but have listened to a few, audio is very clear, thanks to two speakers. I am hopeful the Venus will be a decent performer. We&amp;#039;ll let you know once we have used it over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How To Install and Test a CB Radio Antenna&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When installing the antenna and CB it is important to do a few basic things to ensure success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am detailing this due to the amount of CB problem posts I see on forums. These should be done before you try and use the CB for communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When fixing the mount to the vehicle, ensure that it is positioned so that the antenna does not have a lot of metal body work running up the side of it, especially by the coil at the base of the antenna if you have one. See the first photo on this post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the mount earth has a good bond to the body panel you are fixing it to. It may be necessary to rub the paint away, then seal with silicone over the mount to prevent corrosion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that the earth and antenna feed are isolated from one another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The easiest way to check this is by testing at the CB antenna feed plug (the plug you put in the back of the CB). Check from the centre pin to the barrel (shield), using a multimeter set to the ohm range. This should be open circuit or at least many Mega ohms. Try not to touch the barrel or probes, you will cause a lower reading, depending on how conductive you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next check the barrel of the plug to earth this should be very low I would aim for less than 0.5 ohms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If these readings are good then you have the basis for a good SWR. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However. You must ensure you use decent quality cable, which is 50 ohm, ideally a decent RG58, with both foil and braided shield. Try to avoid routing via noisy electrical components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power wiring of your CB should be ideally straight from the battery positive and negative. Mine is linked to the second battery fuse panel on my split charge. Make sure it is fused properly!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally check that the negative wire of the power to the shield of the antenna feed also has a low resistance. If not you need to fix this and aim for less than an ohm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next connect up your SWR meter and ensure you are outside in a clear area. Follow the instructions that you have with the meter, you need to get this as low as possible. Personally I was happy with the reading I got over the whole range Which was less than 1.4. You should work to be at least below 1.5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps people, I wish I had a pound for each high SWR reading. If I missed anything or it is not clear let me know, I&amp;#039;ll clarify or update.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrument Binnacle (Cowl) - Raptor Engineering</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/05/30/instrument-binnacle-cowl-raptor-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 05:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/05/30/instrument-binnacle-cowl-raptor-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-0913.jpg?w=420&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;473&#34; alt=&#34;Dash Explosion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The binnacle on the Defender is the part that surrounds the instruments in front of the driver, it secures to the underside of the dashboard top surface. The binnacle is also known as the instrument cowl. Item 1 In the picture on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binnacle provides a frame to mount the instrument panel and heater controls onto. On older Defenders and I expect Series vehicles also, it is common to find them cracked and falling apart, this leads to the surrounding components being loose and fee to move. In my case leading to an annoying medley of squeaks and rattles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a simple job, apart from a couple of ackward screws, to replace the binnacle, a standard plastic replacement is available from various part suppliers at about £50. I believe the part number is MTC2808. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The problem with replacing like for like is that eventually the replacement will end up in the same state as the original, I suspect the combined effects of heat, vibration and UV on the exposed sections probably cause the failure. That together with heavy hands. I suppose you would hope that modern replacements are of a better specified plastic and more hardy. Not knowing for sure I wanted an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-0934.jpg?w=343&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;343&#34; height=&#34;343&#34; alt=&#34;Raptor Binnacle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily a powder coated steel equivalent is available from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raptor-engineering.co.uk/defender-s111-binnacle-mount&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Raptor Engineering Binnacle&#34;&gt;Raptor Engineering&lt;/a&gt;, at around the same price as the plastic replacement. I decided I would go for this when I replaced the binnacle on our Defender. I did not fancy doing the job again in the future. Picture on the right shows what it looks like. I forgot to take a before picture, so have pinched the one from Raptor&amp;#039;s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the good things about the Raptor replacement is that there are less of the fiddly screws to put back, once they are out. Also the lugs at the top of the mount, were the top of the instrument panel secures to are adjustable, allowing an element of fine tuning the final position of the instrument panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On thing that would have been nice as an option on purchase, would have been a kit of u-nuts and original spec screws. I found that I had various bits missing, probably lost with bits of dash before my time. I think I would have purchase the extras at the time if I had the option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08284.jpg?w=351&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; alt=&#34;Broken Defender Binnacle Instrument Cowl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually managed to get the old binnacle out and it was only then that I realised how bad it was. There were pieces from both sides and the back missing, there were also various cracks which prevented the captive nut things securing properly, which are supposed to hold the side panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have my suspicions that the rear section in the picture on the left was broken when the immobiliser was fitted for my insurance. I found the missing bit deep in the dash below the hazard relay etc. the other side of the binnacle looks similar to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-082710.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the old one is out the Raptor replacement dropped straight in. I loosely fitted it to start with to allow me to make sure everything lined up correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once happy, I secured the main fixings and then the heater controls to the binnacle. As I had screws and u-nuts missing, I decided to replace all of the side self tapping screws with round head hex M5 screws and nuts, that are black anodised. This matches the adjustable tab screws provided by Raptor and looks smart, it also gave me the spares to secure the front properly. The only self tappers are the four that secure the main instrument panel to the binnacle. Picture below if you are interested. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-0827.jpg?w=358&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;358&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;Overall, I am pleased with the Raptor product, it makes a very sturdy replacement, fits well and gives the dash a fresher look. I would highly recommend using this as a standard replacement.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>