<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Austria on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/austria/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Austria on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/austria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 - Ramsau am Dachstein to Bovec</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/31/day-5-ramsau-am-dachstein-to-bovec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/31/day-5-ramsau-am-dachstein-to-bovec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not a lot happened today. Today was a relatively short hop to one of our favourite areas, we have been to Bovec several times, normally because it is convenient to stop at on our journey to where ever we are going. The difference this time was that we wanted to stay at a campsite we had walked through near the river Koritnica, which is actually in Vodenca about 2 km from Bovec. Having left early from yesterdays campsite, stopped for breakfast and lunch we arrived relatively early at about 1330. Unfortunately the reception of the campsite was closed until 1600.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting here was interesting, we used the &lt;a title=&#34;Wurzen Pass&#34; href=&#34;http://www.dangerousroads.org/austria/259-wurzen-pass-austria.html&#34;&gt;Wurzen pass&lt;/a&gt; on the way out of Austria which features 18% inclines and a few hair pins, for this with the fully loaded Landy low range is fairly useful. This was followed by using the 206 road which goes from Kranjska Gora to Bovec. This road we had previously travel in the other direction several years ago and resulted in Cassie reliving her breakfast. This&lt;a title=&#34;Vrsic Pass&#34; href=&#34;http://www.dangerousroads.org/slovenia/619-vri-pass-slovenia.html&#34;&gt; road&lt;/a&gt;, has some pretty serious gradients and cobbled sections, the views are spectacular. There are 50 numbered hairpin turnings, but I would say at least a hundred turns in total, as they are only numbered if they are proper hairpins! I think both of these roads feature on the Dangerous roads website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Vodenca, as we knew the area, we just left the car on the side of the road and wandered down to the river, to have lunch on the other side. To cross the river you have to use one of the wire bridges, which Wendy does not like, Cassie and I bounced over it in joy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water was no warmer than usual, it must be about 10 degrees Celsius, cold enough to cause pain in your feet and hands. Cassie got dunked for soaking me having promised she would not and I eventually managed to get in and out in a very short second. Wendy took the option of looking pretty on the stoney beach. By the time this was done it was almost time for the reception to open so we killed the last few minutes, having a Radler at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan for tomorrow was to have a chilled day of walking and swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 - Westerheim to Ramsau am Dachstein</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/30/day-4-westerheim-to-ramsau-am-dachstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 19:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/30/day-4-westerheim-to-ramsau-am-dachstein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We woke to pouring rain again, the flavour of the trip so far. We decided to simply pack up and move on. Dan and Cassie went to get breakfast from the camp shop. Croissants and Coffee to go.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another day of driving it was to be. We headed out and decided to make it all the way to Austria. Again it was to be a day of clouds and rain. As we decided to stop, Cassie chose the camp off the GPS and we headed in that direction. Unfortunately two things happened…the camp was full and the GPS decided to fail on us. We could not get it to start again and so just drove until we saw a sign for camping and stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130436.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again they were full, but gave us a spot at the top in the car park of the Pension/House. Grey skies loomed and so we battened down the hatches, expecting the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camp/pension grill was where we decided to have dinner, but the old guy that ran the place decided that it wasn&#39;t good enough to open with just a few people and closed for the night. We made our own concoction for dinner of potatoes, bacon and onions alongside scrambled eggs. We fondly named this &#34;Bubble and Peep&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then headed off to bed in anticipation of another stormy night with interrupted sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY4: TUESDAY 2 AUGUST 2012 Stechelberg (Switzerland) – Bürserberg (Austria)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/03/day4-tuesday-2-august-2012-stechelberg-switzerland-burserberg-austria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 17:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/03/day4-tuesday-2-august-2012-stechelberg-switzerland-burserberg-austria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping costs: Camping Heidi €26.70 – 1 night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What a days driving! We left camp later than usual and drove all day but only managed to cover 180 – 200km! We managed to just get inside the Austrian border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to find a supermarket after searching for one for ages and decided to stop to buy as many supllies as we could. Walking around looking for ice tea for Cassie, she slips on the floor and bruised her cox-ix/bottom. Poor Cas, she had an enourmous bruise on her right bottom cheek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to stop as we entered into Austria, and immediately saw a campsite sign. When we got there, they were packed and wanted €40pn! We decided to move on. Eventually we found a camp run by a Dutch couple. We made the decision to camp only 1 night and start heading south into Slovenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The camp was amongst apple trees. As we sat cooking dinner, apples fell here and there, narrowly missing us. It was quite unnerving, waiting for an apple to land on our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8420.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8428.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8429.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8448.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>