<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Licques on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/licques/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Licques on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/licques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 - Licques to Nuefchateau</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/27/day-1-licques-to-nuefchateau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 23:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/27/day-1-licques-to-nuefchateau/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So after the shenanigans at the Eurotunnel we arrived at Calais at jut gone nine. Seemed a bit late to be looking for a campsite. We were off the train in little time, thanks to the efficient loading and unloading arrangement. We head straight for Reims. The plan at this stage was to just find a place to bed down for the night, so after ten minutes or so on the road, I managed to persuade the GPS to take us via a campsite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for us, it existed and was ok, the guy was busy socialising at the bar so just told us to take any pitch which did not bother us, it was late. We literally just parked opened the roof tent then headed to the bar for a beer. The night, with beer came to 20 euros, not bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie was first in bed, we decided we&#39;d drink the beer in the fridge, which led to Wendy and I being up until gone eleven. It also meant a night of pee breaks. I never seem to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning we woke to claps of thunder, it was just before eight. We did not fancy hanging around and used this as an excuse to get up and out of there, we packed up the tent, sleeping bags and had a wash by quarter past eight. Deciding to have breakfast at a cafe on the road. The first two hours or so were in heavy rain and lightning. The landy did not leak too much, luckily. It was dark until about 10 am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were headed in the direction of Stuttgart today, but after the rush of the last few weeks had decided we&#39;d stop fairly early, the main agenda for the day was to get out of France, get food and fuel. In the end we made it to Neufchateau for a late lunch. Somehow, to a campsite we had been to on a previous trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130360.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie had some water balloons so, we decided to use her desire to soak us as an opportunity to cool down after lunch, much to her delight. Later in the afternoon we pottered off for a swim in the local lake, which was an uninviting brown pond, for a swim which provided the opportunity for a short walk and a much needed cool down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have decided tomorrow to continue heading towards Stuttgart, we&#39;ll probably stop just after at around the 400 to 450 km mark, we need to break some miles off the journey if we are going to get to Albania. The roads are good in this part of the world, the going will be much slower further down. If we land in a good spot we may spend two nights. If not we&#39;ll move on the following day, to tackle another 450km or so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>