<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Website on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/website/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Website on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;ve moved. Africanuhambo has been transported To Wordpress</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/03/17/weve-moved-africanuhambo-has-been-transported-to-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 21:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/03/17/weve-moved-africanuhambo-has-been-transported-to-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well we are in the middle of moving the website from where it was previously hosted, Google to Wordpress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially we will be moving it to a Wordpress hosted option. This is at Wordpress.com, in the future if we need move flexibility we may actually move to a Wordpress based self hosted server. This should be easily achievable with the export options Wordpress provides. At the moment thou, we will be staying at Wordpress.com they offer a generous amount of storage free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually the third move for our site. The site started on a self managed server previously, we then &#34;simplified&#34; this resulted in a move to google sites, which was ultimately too simple. So this latest move should be a happy medium and offer easy moving options or upgrade options should we need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason for moving is that google sites are not the easiest to update on the road sans wifi. This ultimately resulted in us not updating the site. At least now we can do updates via email, iPad app or PC offline app to be uploaded at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Summer&amp;#039;s trip is only just being typed up and with a month away, typing seven months late actually makes the tale loose it&amp;#039;s charm. Despite the fact we record each day in a Moleskin journal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So looking forward to more updates, wish us luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>