<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maintenance on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/maintenance/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maintenance on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/maintenance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair done</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 17:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130724-184907.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The landy is now back to normal the whole repair is done, seats are in soundproofing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have the fun of packing for the trip. Sorry I did not take a picture of the finished article! But the picture above shows the first of three seats fitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must dash need to iron my pants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There Upstand Assembly</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0109.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much of an update tonight, with the ongoing repair apart from to show some pictures of the panel now it has been fully tweaked and drilled to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished of the drilling tonight and deburred everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final job for the night was to give another coat of etch primer and paint the seat brackets and new panels with stone chip paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are now drying, so tomorrow I&#39;ll start fitting it for real. The only thing I need to do is drill the seat brackets in location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful with a push, I should have it done tomorrow or Sunday at the latest. Not wishing to tempt fate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0111.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Upstand/Upriser Re-Assembly</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0091.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now at the stage of re-assembly. It has been a slow road even to strip the back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mid-crossmember is galvanised and from YRM metal solutions. One of the nice features of the new one, is that the top brackets are loose rather than welded on this makes it easier to get the cross member under the fuel pipes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have had with the crossmember is that the holes, for mounting to the chassis rails where about 3mm out across the vehicle. I am not entirely sure why, but I eventually managed to get the bolts in. I suspect it may have been partially due to the camber of the road. I&#39;ve used stainless bolts so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0095.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note on the cross member is that the cut out for the fuel hoses on my vehicle is in the wrong location. This probably varies from vehicle to vehicle. One was YRM could improve this is to have a wider cut out. I have added additional protection and will tywrap the hoses out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the crossmember was in it was time to start fitting the upstand/upriser. The new item is a different size to the old one. In a good way. The lips are about another 10mm deep. This means that around the top a certain amount of fitting is required, this is around the spars under the floor and the doubler between the separate sections of floor near the doors. I only cut out these areas, I like the idea of the extra depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new item seemed longer also, I did not have to cut it down. The reason is that the old panel was tapered making the top shorter than the bottom edge. I spaced it evenly each side and it seems ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0102.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fitting done, I have now dry fitted it, drilled the holes for the top rivets and will tomorrow drill the sides pieces and seat brackets. At the moment the rivets are all loose. I will strip it out and paint it once I have dry assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The floor is in with a couple of screws at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Minutes jobs are never 5 minutes</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/19/5-minutes-jobs-are-never-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 20:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/19/5-minutes-jobs-are-never-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it every job on my Landy that should be five minutes, takes hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changed the front mud flaps on the Land Rover yesterday... and today. Passenger side easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drivers side was a different story. One of the bolts was heavily corroded into the rivnut. This meant that the rivnut spun... Only choice was to rip the rivnut out and replace it. Luckily I managed to fit a new one of the same size. All without the proper tool to clamp it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice trick with a bolt, washer and nut. Let me know if you can&#39;t figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway another five minute job done in 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Stats - Summer 2012 Trip</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In starting to consider this years plan, i thought i would post some recorded figures from last summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stats from our last trip from 27th July to the 26th August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We covered 3663.1 miles, about 5900 km.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used 606.42 litres of diesel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Averaged 27 miles per gallon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filled up 15 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid 26 tolls totalling 287.8 Euro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most expensive where for the Tunnel de Mont Blanc at 38.9 and tunnel de Frejus at 39.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used the channel tunnel for crossing the channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used a over night ferry from Bari to Dubrovnik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 night in a hotel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 attempted nights at a hotel night resulting in six police officers attending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 nights free camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 none catastrophic car part failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which do you want to know more about!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter cooler Leak Testing - FTP8030 300TDI</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/04/inter-cooler-leak-testing-ftp8030-300tdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 19:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/04/inter-cooler-leak-testing-ftp8030-300tdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Defender has had what I think is a typical inter cooler leak for quite some time, which leads to some power loss often notable on hills. I attempted to sort it out last summer prior to our departure for our summer trip. I purchased a second hand item and found that it was also leaking. Luckily I tested it before I fitted it to the vehicle. I ended up leaving the original in place and living with the loss of power for the trip and manage to get my money back. The seller was very apologetic!
&lt;div&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120404-00134.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-285&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; alt=&#34;300 TDI Intercooler Leak - Back&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture above is typical of the leaks I have seen on these items. If you look on ebay a lot of the second hand inter coolers have the oil stain you see above, in the lower corner of the inter cooler, some have other oil stains which may be a sign of a leak, so please buy with care. This tel-tale sign of oil is what prompted me to test the leaking one I had last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fairly easy to set up a fairly crude off vehicle test. I used an old inner tube, which was cut so the valve was in the middle of a length of inner tube long enough to fit between the two hose connections on the inter cooler, the inner tube was secured with some jubilee clips. I then pumped up the inner tube to about 20 psi and stuck the whole lot in a tub of water. What I found was a constant stream of bubbles from the corner of the inter cooler, indicating a leak. Below you can see my inter cooler test equipment. Impressed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img-20120404-00148.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-289&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Intercooler Test Equipment - Bike Inner Tube&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I managed to purchase a new replacement inter cooler from Motor &amp;amp; Diesel Engineering Ltd, they supply the LGV 2.8 Diesel engine over here which is a development of the 300TDI engine. The item they sent looked to me to be a re-core, but it had comforting stickers on it which suggest it was tested. The price was also very reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fairly easy to change the inter cooler, so I will not get into the detail, you can see that below. I think with my faffing around it took me two leisurely hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/300tdi-intercooler-change-lr.jpg&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-283&#34; width=&#34;516&#34; height=&#34;554&#34; alt=&#34;Defender 300TDI Intercooler Change&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this is of use to someone, has anyone else had the experience, I had with purchasing a bad second hand item?
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just some of the Jobs on Tusky</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/18/just-some-of-the-jobs-on-tusky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 12:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/18/just-some-of-the-jobs-on-tusky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;sites-canvas-main-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;table cellspacing=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;div dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;When we got Tusky, it was clear that after 150,000+ miles she was going to need certain items doing. Most of these have been done by us, either on the road outside our flat or behind the flats in a quite space we have managed to get access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The jobs below are really things that needed doing to get her back up to spec.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;jot-content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;table id=&#34;goog-ws-list-table&#34;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Panhard rod bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace panhard rod bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Trailing arm refurb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace trailing arm bushes, strip and paint arms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Radius arm refurbishment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace radius arm &amp;amp; chassis bushes, strip and paint arms&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Anti-Roll bar bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Replace anti-roll bar bushes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Remove rear side facing seats&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Remove the rear most seats to make way for storage.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Steering Box Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The steering box had a typical leak from the output shaft. As per most land rovers. The solution was to change the box for an reconditioned item.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Steering Hose Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The hose from the steering reservoir to the pump was leaking. This was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Oil Cooler Hose Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Pipe to the oil cooler was leaking this was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Cyclone Breather Change&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The cyclone breather was changed because it was old and very dirty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Turbo Heat Shield&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The turbo heat shield was cracked and about ready to fall off this was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Vacuum Pump Leak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Vacuum Pump was leaking and noisy this was changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Air Filter Mounting Rubbers - Perished&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The air filter housing bracket mounting rubbers where all perished. These have all been changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Upper steering UJ Play&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The upper steering UJ had a lot of play this has been changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Gearbox Recondition and Clutch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;After a long drive, luckily near our home the gearbox selector packed up, turned out to have ended up in the box acording to the garage. So we had our box reconditioned and a new clutch fitted.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Done&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;Rear Diff Pinion Seal - Salisbury Axle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td dir=&#34;ltr&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34;&gt;The rear axle is leaking from the pinion seal. I need to get this changed.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>