<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 21:54:35 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Moved Again</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/post/moved-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 21:54:35 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/post/moved-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having previously moved from Google pages to Wordpress.com. The Blog (this site) has now moved from Wordpress.com to a statically served site hosted on Github.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of the posts are now moved and most content is running correctly. Over the next few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll tweak and fine tune the content and appearance. Previous links should still work, I hope!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I would deploy at this stage despite needing to finish a few bits, to ensure continuity. As an old boss said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let perfect be the enemy of good&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Land Rover has Gone... We will be off soon after.</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2014/01/03/the-land-rover-has-gone-we-will-be-off-soon-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 15:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2014/01/03/the-land-rover-has-gone-we-will-be-off-soon-after/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, the Land Rover left to a new life several weeks ago. I hope she is looked after, it was sad to see her go. Sold to the first viewer at the asking price. I never thought I would sell, but life is full of surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your wondering why? Well we are moving to Melbourne in January 2014 and will start new adventures there. So stay tuned. New Country, New Job... Very Exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on UK soil</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/24/back-on-uk-soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 18:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/24/back-on-uk-soil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well we are back on UK soil, behind on our updates due to a lack of wifi, most are written so we will post them ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long drive home now!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 21 to 24 - B&amp;B, Marina di Ginosa, Cassino to Marina di Massa</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/19/day-21-to-24-bb-marina-di-ginosa-cassino-to-marina-di-massa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 07:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/19/day-21-to-24-bb-marina-di-ginosa-cassino-to-marina-di-massa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The south of Italy was not what we expected. Saying that, exactly what we expected is hard to put into words. But packed, sardine campsites, and undesirable beaches was certainly not it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to get in a little more beach time before we started heading northwards and ultimately towards home. So with this in mind, we continued on down the coast of South Italy in the Puglia area. The map showed plenty of camping and after our usual stint of driving, we pulled off the motorway at Marina di Ginosa. We saw the campsite sign and followed it .. what we pulled up to was a sight that had a 90% majority of motor homes and static caravans. We have turned up in Italy at the completely wrong time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my last post, it was Italy&#39;s national holiday and therefore every Mario, Luigi and his mother were on holiday for 2 weeks. From 10 August till 18 August all factories etc close down and Italy retreats … it seemed to this campsite or part of the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We paid for 1 night, thinking if we liked it we would stay for 2, but that changed very quickly after we went to the beach. Lets just say peacocks have nothing on Italian men and their speedos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Marina di Ginosa we headed up the motorway past Rome. We did a big stint of driving, we simply wanted to get out of Italy. We had no maps for this part of Italy and were now relying on our very old and very worn Europe map for a general motorway overview. Every services we stopped at did not have maps, it was getting very frustrating! We pulled off the motorway at Caserta to look for a campsite. After an hour of driving, nerves and tempers were fraying and we all just wanted to get out of the car and stop. I suggested we head for a big town and go from there. We ended up in Cassino and found a campsite sign. The campsite was strange … an old lady and, i assume, her grand children were sitting at the entrance. The lady greeted us and chatted away in Italian, I assume telling us to go choose a pitch and she&#39;ll bring us our passports. The place was deserted! To say it felt like the twilight zone or something from the movie The Shining would be a good ways to describing the feel of the place. We were THE ONLY people there. We pitched, cooked dinner and quickly went to bed … avoiding ALL contact with the ablutions … eewww!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day we headed Florence direction. The day dawned with Cas needing a wee. As age descended the ladder we heard a &#34;Bonjourno!&#34; from a strange Italian man walking through the campsite … that was our queue to leave. Anoter long day driving, as we passed Florence I asked the team if they&#39;d like to stay in Florence or carry on to the coast, which would mean another 2 hours or so in the car. Cassie opted for the coast, Dan didn&#39;t mind and so the coast it was. We pulled off the motorway at Lido di Camaiore, the map showed lots of camping and we were bound to find something quickly. This was not the case, after about 30min of driving we finally came across a campsite. we pulled in and enquired about a space, no sorry, full! Another 10 attempts later and we still had nowhere to stay. It was getting late again and we were getting tetchy. One last attempt, thank goodness! They had space. The campsite was another of these static caravan and permanent pitch sights. Not to our taste to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Packed Free beach&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0319.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed to the beach to check it out, but what a disappointment. A false bay had been created using boulders. This stopped the sea coming in and out and delivering fresh water from the tide … meaning the water was frothy and dirty. The beaches were also all privatised and the &#39;free&#39; beaches were tiny strips packed with every Mario, Luigi and Poalo. Not fun. Despite this, we decided to stay two nights and to find a swimming pool tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a pool and for €4 each, we had a lovely quiet afternoon by the pool. Quiet yes, but the visions we were treated to were something I don&#39;t think I will ever forget and is my major memory of Italy - the men walking around in their speedos. Or budgie smugglers as Dan and I nicknamed them. Why!? That is my only question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Cassie enjoying the delights of the much quieter swimming pool.&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0338.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 20 - Secret Beach to Italian B&amp;B</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/15/day-20-secret-beach-to-italian-bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 07:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/15/day-20-secret-beach-to-italian-bb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were up very early thanks to having had no sleep. Dan started the day with a 5am swim!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a departure of 6am for us after we brushed our teeth and dressed. We decided to find a café along the way and get some breakfast and a coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140108.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made our way back up the winding road that you take to get down to the Southern part of Albania. At the top there is a restaurant, it looked open and was serving a few travellers, so we decided to stop. We ordered coffee and asked for the menu for breakfast. We got the impression that breakfast wasn&#39;t a big meal in Albania and ordered toast with butter and honey and toast with butter and jam. What we got was warmed up slices of bread with a side plate that had a lump of butter and a dollop of honey or jam. The butter was rancid and the Jam was a little different. We ate the bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0296.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had decided to head for Vlorë and enquire about the ferry, see if it did take cars and how much it was. When we got into Vlorë, we could see the port with a ferry anchored, but we couldn&#39;t see how to get to the port. Eventually we came across a sign and turned down a road … well, we ended up stuck as we found ourselves surrounded by bollards. There was a gap in the bollards where someone had obviously tried to drive over them and knocked one off. We are a high vehicle, so we just drove over it, down the incredibly high kerb and out into the traffic going onto the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0228.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually found the port and parked the land, grabbed our passports and documentation and went in search of tickets. Not a hard thing as the street was lined with ticket shops. The fair, including the car and 2 adults and 1 child came to €206 one way. We were informed it departed at 1pm and to check in at 12.30pm the latest. We bought the ticket, but now had a few hours to kill before we embarked. We decided to wonder around Vlorë, find a supermarket and exchange our LEK. The supermarket part was easier said than done, but we did manage to exchange our left over LEK. With that done we headed for an air conditioned café to have a drink and wait out our remaining time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 12.30 we got in the car and headed towards the ferry. We came across a mishmash of higgledy piggledy park cars and young boys shouting at us to buy cigarettes. One of the young boys pointed to an office and said, &#34;You go give ticket there.&#34;. Dan thanked him and hopped out with the tickets and passports. A gentleman at the office helped Dan with the odd check in procedure and then we were off and boarding the ferry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked, gathered our bits and bobs for the journey and went up to find a table. We were all tired from last night and were hoping to be able to get some shut eye on the journey. The gentleman that had helped Dan appeared, along with his wife and son. He is married to an English lady and every year they journey to Italy and Albania to visit his family. They warned us that even though we were told a 1pm departure, it would be more like 3pm departure. With this knowledge we settled ourselves for a long day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140126.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally at 2.28pm the ferry started moving. We were off! Only another 5 hours to go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey was long and very boring. We were also warned not to eat the food on the ferry, so we settled for pre packaged crisps and biscuits. After disembarking, it was now 7.30pm and we decided to head a little south from Brindisi. We have no Italy maps and our GPS is still dead, so we looked for a services so we could buy a map of the area. After a few failed attempts, Dan pulls into one and manages to get a map. He asked a gentleman in the services if there was camping, the guy was apparently rather rat arsed, but very helpful and pointed Dan in the direction of a few campsites. Now we just had to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a little lost, and as the time ticked on, we could not find a campsite. We looked for the obligatory signs, but found none. After 2 hours we finally see a sign, and we follow it … and we follow it … and we follow it. We are now desperate to sleep and eat and decide to just check into a hotel. The first hotel we see, that is easy to park in, we pull into to ask if they have a room. Unfortunatley for us, they are completely full! We are informed that all the hotels are completely full and that we will struggle to find a room as it is Italy&#39;s 2 week holiday period. He kindly calls around and finds a B&amp;amp;B that have a free room, but it will cost us €100 for the night including breakfast. Bggars can&#39;t be chooses, so we thank the guy and take the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The owner of the B&amp;amp;B came to meet us at the hotel and show us the way back to the B&amp;amp;B. We followed him, pulled into the B&amp;amp;B, took the room key, had a shower and collapsed .. sparko till the next morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke not to early, but not to late and had showers. We then went to have breakfast. We were all starving as we never did get to eat dinner the night before. Breakfast consisted of a buffet style arrangement with fresh fruits, fruit juice, bread, butter, jam and some poached fruit and a lemon compot thing. We were simply enjoying eating when a plate of cakes is put down onto our table … a very sweet breakfast, Cassie certainly wasn&#39;t complaining.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 19 - Bunec to Beach Cove via Butrint</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 07:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/14/day-19-bunec-to-beach-cove-via-butrint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140027.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a fairly ok nights sleep and woke early. We decided to avoid the breakfast spoken of last night as dinner was a little &#39;dodgy&#39;, for want of a better word. We opted for just a coffee instead. Outside our room we bumped into a lovely lady sitting with her grandson. She asked us where we were from and we told her, &#34;England, Brighton&#34;. She said she knew it and lived in Lewisham. She was on holiday with her family and investigating a business opportunity in Albania. I must add, she was Albanian. We chatted for a bit longer and then bid her farewell, we were off for that coffee.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being reinforced with a coffee, we headed out towards Butrint, we wanted to visit the Roman ruins there. After a long and hot drive, we arrived at the entrance car park to the ruins. Immediately we were accosted by a young urchin girl and her male companion. They demanded that we buy bracelets from them. Dan was in the firing line of their deluge and so we ended up buying a bracelet from the girl and one from the boy. By this time I had another little urchin at my window. She begged that I bought a bracelet from her too, I had to say no. The first young girl then came round to my window and asked if she could have my banana that I had sitting in the front. I laughed and had to admire her audacity. I gave her the banana. She immediately peeled it and ate it as she walked away, pleased at herself for getting another tourist in her trap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were now dripping and feeling a little hard done by, having been accosted by the urchins. We went for a cold drink at the restaurant before entering the sight. At the entrance to the ruins the prices were 700 LEK per foreign visitor, 500 LEK per foreign visitor in a group, 300 LEK for an Albanian visitor and 400 LEK for a child. So it was an entrance fee of 1,400 LEK and so we followed the cruise ship visitors that had just descended on the place by bus load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140030.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked around the remains. The signs at the entrance had said no smoking, walk on the path and beware the insects and snakes. The last bit made us hopeful we&#39;d see something other than roman ruins. We waited at the first part, an amphitheatre, for the hoards to disappear. Here Cassie discovered a turtle in the water around the ruins. From here we wondered around, skirting the crowds. It was extremely hot, and we were all dripping in sweat by the end. Afterwrds Dan and Cassie got themselves and ice cream and I got a can of cold Coca Cola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1140071.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to head off and find a camp on the beach somewhere. Yesterday Dan had noticed that the radius arm bushes needed changing, especially if we wanted to tackle a few more gravel tracks during the holiday. We had seen plenty of &#39;Autoservis&#39; places along the road and so we went in search of one that could fit us in. We tried a few and they all pointed us to someone else as they were far to busy. Eventually on the way out of Butrint, we stopped at a small garage we had noticed on our way in. He was now quiet and Dan asked if he could do the work, it would only take 1 hour. The guy agreed. He spoke good english and so Dan changed into some shorts and negotiated the car above a pit. Cassie and I sat in the car trying not to expire, while Dan helped the guy change the bushes. All done for 2000 LEK. Luckily Dan had the spares in the car … Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were off now in search of a beach to stay on. They all looked packed and we could not find a turning to some. So, we decided to stop for lunch somewhere. We came across a little village and went to a restaurant. Here the owner spoke good english and we ordered lamb with a greek salad. The owner chafed to us about working on cruise ships and seeing the world, but how now he water to settle in Albania. We asked him about the ferries from Vlorë to Brindisi. He recommended going from Igoumenista instead and offered to let us use the internet to check fares.We thanked him and Dan did just that. The prices and info was not helpful as the ferry from Vlorë did not show up in the searches. We thanked the owner and hit the road once more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0264.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we stopped at a little cove we had spotted on the way past yesterday. The water edge was lined with mobile homes, which we only assumed were stopping for the night. As we approached and stopped, a funny Albanian man came up to us and asked where we were from. We told him England and asked if it was ok to stay. He said sure no problem, just park. Dan asked if he wanted money, he said that wasn&#39;t necessary, we were his friends … we concluded he was a little strange and parked up anyway, changed into our kozzies, and went for a dip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130968.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0270.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0279.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassie immediately spotted sea urchins in the water, so we tried to avoid these. Later on we spoke to a lady who had stood n one and was trying to get the poison out her toe. Cassie got the snorkel and mask out and did a little look see in the water. She stayed in for ages! All of a sudden there was a ruckus, some locals nearby had caught an octopus. They started throwing it onto the rocks whilst screaming and shouting. I found this really upsetting. Why not just kill it humanely and hopefully not as sport, but to take it back and eat it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we had been sitting on the beach, the wind had been building. We decided to set the tent up and head for the restaurant for dinner across the road from the bay. As we had eaten a big lunch, we decided to go for a snack type dinner … this didn&#39;t really happen. Dan ordered calamari and I the seafood spaghetti, Cas shared both. The wind was now quite strong. We wondered back to the tent and got ready for bed. Whilst we lay in the tent, we were whipped and bashed. Dan and I worried about it not being safe in the tent with the wind at this strength, so we gathered up our sleeping stuff, closed up the tent and bundled into the car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a night of horror! I personally got NO sleep … Dan says he managed a wink or two and I think Cassie was the luckiest out of us all. She probably managed an hour or so. To say we woke early would be an understatement. We were up before 6, teeth brushed and outta there. We were the walking dead but we still headed for Vlorë to see how much it would be to catch the ferry to Brindisi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18 - Kepi i Kalas to Bunec via our Secret beach</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 07:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0254.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Being in a hotel last night meant getting away quickly was easy. We had a local style breakfast of feta, tomato, cucumber and bread. Washed down with a few coffees.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Our plan was to check out a beach I had found on Google earth that looked almost isolated due to the track you had to use to get to it. Due to the GPS problems I had circled it on the map. This meant it was another day heading to a circle. The drive to the beach took about an hour or so. We first had to negotiate some spectacular steep roads with tight hairpins over the surrounding mountains. The roads had various bits missing and loads of fallen rocks which claimed a few victims to punctures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130959.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The turning to the beach was immediately of the bottom of the steep decent. There had been a few attempts to grade it, but the track was pretty bad. On the was down we got held up by a truck rescuing an Italian mobile home who had been over ambitious. Both looked frustrated. The tow rope was in taters. The owner said something to me as we squeezed by. I promised to return with my tow strap and shackles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;By the time I had stopped 50 meters on and returned they appeared to on there way so I returned and we continued to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we got to the bottom we were delighted, we found an almost empty beach except for a couple of 4x4&#39;s and 2 or 3 like minded over landing campers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The beach was made up by sandy white pebbles. The top of the beach had a sand track which was easy to traverse. We headed most of the way along the track then turned down to the sea. Parking 10 meters from the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0253.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Here we swam in crystal clear water and lounged around for the morning. Cassie loved it. Spending most of the time checking out the fishies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on we decided to leave, I was a little apprehensive, as I had noted the sand and shingle made for horribly difficult driving. I had deflated the tyres a little and even in low diff lock, I struggled. I had to repeatedly reverse to get any momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My first attempt to get up the beach failed, I thought I had enough speed but could not get into low third without grinding to a halt and sinking. I stopped and let some more air out of the tyres and reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Foot to the floor I headed slightly back down towards the sea and managed to get some speed and into third. This allowed me to managed the engine speed and get enough velocity to get over the sand up to the slightly better surface to get off the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once I was back on the track at the top, I was hot! So we headed to a small makeshift bar a local had erected in the rock walls of the mountain that encapsulated the beach. I had a fanta and a beer to chill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had received we headed south to find a place to stay. We had again opted out of camping as we had no supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130983.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We eventually after some chaos ended up at a tiny restaurant at Bunec beach, which had rooms. The owning family lived in a tent. They were very nice and cooked us a traditional pasta dish and we drank loads of beer and swam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130990.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The rooms in these places are basic but functional and clean. We paid 30 euro with breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17 - Koplic to Kepi i Kalas via the Karavasta Lagoon.</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 18:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130905.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the heat we did quite well this morning and managed to get packed up and on the road by 0945, after we had a slow coffee and showers all round. Our original plan was to head up to Thethi, which is said to be beautiful, but have a difficult road, especially after rain. Given that the last two days there had been storms in the area, we decided we would not attempt that, but perhaps try on the return route. Instead today we would head for the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gus and Helen who we met at the campsite had lent us a map which they had been given, by another traveller in Albania on a bike. Many of the circles were on the places we had read about, some were alien to us. Anyhow I copied the circles to our map. Todays plan was based on circles. We would head to the circle at Karavasta Lagoon. We had no idea what was there so Wendy read up in the guide book on the way between navigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary was that it is a wet land with many birds and lots of wild life. At night it is apparently a mosquito hell hole. Cool, sounds like an ideal place to visit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130908.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we left we found the roads in the area where we stayed all seemed ok, well sign posted and smooth. Petrol stations everywhere. It was not long before we were in chaos though, Sckoder was manic and it was every man for himself. The roads had occasional road markings, round abouts and traffic signals. Pedestrian crossings never mind those. We encountered various types of traffic, bikes, people, horse and cart, three wheel trucks and even motor bikes which had a tray arrangement welded to the from that formed a kind of three wheel truck thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic involved people and cyclists moving the wrong way and or on the wrong side of the road. Putting themselves in danger. The drivers used their horn to say either hello, we are over taking or we are coming through regardless. Undertaking was the norm. This was probably because the fast lane was used to avoid the chaos at the side of the road with the triple parked vehicles and other oddities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At roundabouts most people don&#39;t bother indicating, if they do it means nothing because they forget to change it as the filter off with the opposite indication. The roundabouts work a bit like a drain hole. In that no one stops, they just continue being sucked into the vortex and some break free when they need to leave. Occasionally you&#39;ll get some one a little bit more crazy who will just fly across the round about breaking the vortex. You&#39;ll have warning if you are lucky by way of continuous multiple beeping of the horn. Beep Beep beep beep beep beep beep beep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually made it out of Sckoder, shocked but unharmed! It was exciting. The only negative for me was the begging on the out skirts at the traffic lights which meant we locked the doors and put the windows up. Sorry. I felt really bad about that, but did not want to encourage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the main road overtaking is an art, you&#39;ll often be confronted by a speeding car in your lane flashing lights at you. They are overtaking. They expect you to assist be moving out of the way. Several occasions having held my ground, I took evasive action, either by braking, making use of the dirt hard shoulder or swerving. These guys are good at Chicken. I think I saved us a few times from accidents by braking to allow people to hop from behind and avoid the front of busses by feet, not meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We endured this for several hours, even trying the motor way, which although wider had limited road markings and was just a bigger play ground.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0156.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually arrived at Karavasta. Here we headed along dirt tracks, paid a toll and continued to the beach, we were able to drive all the way up the beach until we found a quiet spot. You can&#39;t do that in many places. Here we relaxed for an hour or so had a swim and lunch. Previously we had tried about 4 km up the beach, but being near a river outlet there was a lot of plan debris on the beach making it look undesirable amongst all the rubbish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having refreshed ourselves and having convinced ourselves it was not an ideal place to camp, we headed back out on the dirt road which we entered, this then lead us to take a turning to follow one of the waterways of the lagoon. We came across some locals fishing and checked with them we were headed in the right direction. They basically as usual said keep going!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0182.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were not headed basically down a raised section of the lagoon that had a track on it. The track continued for about 5 km, it was wet but ok. I was obviously concerned as it may have got very boggy. It was just wide enough for a car.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0190.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we saw loads of small birds, which appeared not to have the ability to fly, but to merely run around scatter brained. There were also lots of herons. The star of the afternoon was a tortoise we came across just wandering the track. We jumped out to get photos quickly, before it disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0198.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time we got out of there it was getting late, so we headed just south of Vlora to hunt down a room to stay in. We found a nice hotel perched on a cliff top with a private beach for 35 Euro a night with breakfast. We had a swim, then freshened up for the evening opting to eat at the hotel and drink a few beers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 - Koplic, Lake Shkrodër</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to stay two nights at Lake Shkodër. Today we woke slowly, having been woken by Cassie in the middle of the night again. After we finally dragged her sleeping items into the tent, thunder rolled in. There had been a little rain too, but not a significant amount. Needless to say, it was a little bit of a restless night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was warming up already by mid morning, and I had decided that the sheets, towels and pillow cases needed to be washed. We also needed to get some food. We asked the owner of the campsite if here was a shop close by and he said yes, just walk up to the main road, over the bridge and there is a shop there. So we handed over our washing, as he had a machine, and set off for the shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130897.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked we were shocked by the rubbish we saw on the side of the road and dumped in ditches, We passed two young boys by the overpass burning their rubbish. It was a reminder that Albania still had ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were perspiring by the time we got to the shop and had to stop for a cold drink at one of the bars. Afterwards we went to the shop and bought essentials .. water, beer, biscuits and other food items. Now for the walk back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the campsite, Cassie made friends with a young girl from a German family staying a few pitches down. She played all afternoon with Lea and her brother Nic. It was nice for her to have company, and Lea wanted to practice her English as she had recently started learning it at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day Thunder had been rumbling in the background but despite this, it had been warm and sunny.. with a slight cloudy haze. But by afternoon, the lightening started making an appearance and we decided to pack up Cassie&#39;s tent and head for the restaurant/bar. And a good thing we did, as the heavens opened with an almighty bang and gush of wind and it did not let up for hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had grabbed a table inside and here we stayed for the most of the evening. Eventually to be joined by Frank and Anjita, Cassie&#39;s new found friends&#39; parents. The evening was great. We swopped travelling stories, places to visit and even swopped blog addresses. It&#39;s always nice to make friends along the way, so thanks Fank and Anjita for a great evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a second Land Rover at the camp, owned by a Scottish couple that were travelling. We had spoken to them the day before about their set up and swopped maps for tips on places to travel. Anyway, Gus and Helen also ended up at the bar/restaurant and as our table was already full, they sat with a trio of Austrian guys next door to us. As the evening progressed, they ended up joining our table too. We all had a wonderful time drinking wine and beer and swopping stories. Thanks Gus and Helen for your tips and your extending fork!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0134.jpeg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 15 - Kostanijica to Kopliku</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/10/day-15-kostanijica-to-kopliku/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 17:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/10/day-15-kostanijica-to-kopliku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is our 5th Wedding Anniversary, so we hoped to make it somewhere nice. Lake Shkodra had been recommended to us by our Dutch neighbours, so that&#39;s where we decided to head as it would also be an ideal place to stop just inside Albania. It has also been recommended to us to cross at the border by Podgorica as the other crossing was obscenely busy.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130861.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey around the Kotor Bay and up and out towards Cetinje was magnificent. We managed to navigate ourselves to Cetinje, but once there, there happened to be absolutely no signs telling you how to get out of the town. We had seen a Policeman standing on a corner, so decided to head for him and ask for directions. We had already passed him and when we pulled up alongside him he humourously exclaimed, &#34;I know why you are here! I&#39;ve seen you already, you are lost!&#34;. He very kindly gave us good directions to find the road out and towards Podgorica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we neared Podgorica, we experienced the no road sign phenomonon again. With great &#34;Navigation by Wendy&#34;, we managed to stay on the road out Podgorica and towards the border at Hani Hotit in Albania. Although heading in the correct general direction, we had somehow managed o drive straight through the shanty part of Podgorica, giving us a real insight into the developing world of both Montenegro and Albania. We drove into a town, and as we stopped to consult our map, an old man came towards us, I can only assume asking us if we were ok. In my best pigeon Montenegrin I asked for Shkodër. The man said in many words I did not understand to keep going straight and not turn right! This we followed and eventually made it to the border crossing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130859.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time it was HOT and the sweat was simply dripping from us. Leaving Montenegro was fairly straight forward. The border guard looked at Dan sitting in just his board shorts and advised him that driving shirtless in Albania would receive him a fine from the Police. We thanked him and headed for the Albanian border control. Here I pulled out the Albanian phrase book and was flabbergastered at the huge change in language that we would have to master. Hello was not simply Ciao and thank you was no longer Hvala. We were going to be stumped. The border crossing was amazingly simple and we got insurance then and there from a man that was talking to the border guard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in Albania! Yee Hah!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 14 - Kostanjica</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/09/day-14-kostanjica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 20:34:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/09/day-14-kostanjica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0038.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took it easy today, not a lot to say. We woke up late, had a slow breakfast and coffee. Caught up on laundry and swam in the sea. At lunch time we headed back to the campsite to get out the sun and fell asleep in the shade. About 1600 we headed back to the beach for another swim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We chatted with people, our neighbours and had a generally good time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening we had dinner at a cool restaurant behind the town which was another little paradise set in an old mill. Cassie had loads of fun exploring while we waited for dinner.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0070.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we head south.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 13 - Jablaničko Jezero to Kostanjica</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/08/day-13-jablanicko-jezero-to-kostanjica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 20:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/08/day-13-jablanicko-jezero-to-kostanjica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9981.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we headed for Montenegro, our cunning plan was to head out on the main roads so we could get there in good time to relax. That is where we went wrong!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed out from Konjic diligently following the signs to Nevesinje. Within a few miles the signs became vague and then non-existent. We were planning to get most of the way through Montenegro in order to get in to Albania asap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Round about when we got to Glavatičevo some 20 km after we started we took the first wrong turning. We passed a town name which we found on the map, Ladanica. This had a nice looking Cafe Restaurant so we stopped to have a coffee and get our bearings, apparently we should have gone right at the bridge. Which was a dirt track indicating a place we could not find on the map. Sceptical I asked someone passing, they confirmed we should have gone up there via, some other towns… Not shown on the map. This was not the main road we had hoped to be on. Still doubtful we tracked back to some shops up the road and asked some ladies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9987.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ladies eventually concluded we should follow them, it would be easier. These ladies drove an Audi with a German plate. They took us up the dirt track, after about 2 km, they pulled into a drive. We concluded this was there place. Handed us a hand drawn map, and said just keep going, don&#39;t turn left. The map showed two town names and a turning. They told us it was 10 km to Nevesinje. We soon realised that they would be able to go no further.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9989.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track continued to degrade, but remained ever present. We gradually climbed a fairly big mountain side. Emerging in some farm land, by this time we had passed about 10 turnings left. I was starting to loose faith. However eventually we came across a farm, with a driery looking guy sitting out side, he confirmed we were headed in the right direction. About 40 minutes later we came across another person, at a small house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enquired with the person about out destination, he suggested I need to keep going. As I walked off I became alarmed, by his gestures which he repeated when I looked at him questioningly. He was indicating or seemed to be suggesting it was a long way to Nevesinje. He did this by drawing his hand down from his chin as if twisting a beard. I think he was saying you&#39;ll have a beard by the time you get there. I laughed worried and told Wendy who looked slightly alarmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 30 minutes later we arrived on tarmac at a junction. I now concluded that the guy previously had a sense of humour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We opted to turn right. Headed for Luka. Within 1 km we were on gravel again precisely what we did not expect. We continued at speed but tentatively on the track for about 20 minutes before an old soviet truck approached us thundering. We asked if Nevesinje was the way we were going he indicated we had to turn around. We managed to do this some 500 meters later. We passed the truck again and he moved over to let us pass. We beeped in thanks and joy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this we seemed to be on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some two hours later we arrived at the wrong border crossing to Montenegro having been redirected once or twice. We had hoped to cross at Bileća, but had missed the turning ending up crossing in reverse where we entered Bosnia and Herzegovina two years ago at Dolovi. With this we took the easy option headed for the beach in an area we know to chill for two nights.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0018.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Kostanjica and just relaxed. Phew. What a great but unexpected day. Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12- Sarajevo to Jablaničko Jezero via Lukomir</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/07/day-12-sarajevo-to-jablanicko-jezero-via-lukomir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 06:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/07/day-12-sarajevo-to-jablanicko-jezero-via-lukomir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So having spent the night in a hotel, which is fairly civilised for us, we got cracking early after a light breakfast. The plan for today was to find our way out of Sarajevo and head for the village of Lukomir. After which we would find some camping etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out of Sarajevo was easier said than done. The city has a one way system, we wanted to head out of the city to the southwest. For a start vaguely towards the airport and then end up on road 18. We only need to get out a few kilometers, to find the turn off to the roads in the mountains. But there was a surprising lack of signs indicating places and exits out of Sarajevo. You would expect for instance to see the airport sign posted or the next largest city. But there was nothing. Well nothing we could see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the city driving is fairly easy, there was a big circular oneway system around the centre, it takes about 10 minutes to go around. The previous day we did it several times, so by now we were experts. Once we got to the western end of the system we headed south over one of the bridges and eventually with a few missed turnings found our way out, with some amusement.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130773.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We needed a few supplies before we headed up to Lukomir, I was anticipating wild camping up on the mountains somewhere, as without decent scale maps or a working GPS I was a little vague on how exactly to get there or what to expect. The best map we had was a 1:200 Bosnia and Herzegovina map, which turned out to be totally inaccurate for the dirt roads. Anyway, conveniently there was a fuel station at the hotel and also conveniently at the turning off the main road was a tiny shop. Which meant we were now ready for anything ... sort of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we headed up off the main road towards Bjelašnica which is the local Ski resort, we climbed at first what seemed a fairly none descript dusty road past a load of industrial cement works (I think), beyond these as we continued up toward Bjelašnica, the road continued to become smaller and with occasionally broken tarmac. By comparison, with French and Swiss Ski resorts, Bjelašnica is tiny.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130801.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to follow the signs to the most easily accessible village of Umoljani. This is reasonably well sign posted and only involves a short section of dirt track to get to the village from Bjelašnica. What we found out was that if you approach from the other side, via Ozimine, is that you can do the whole route by tarmac, on very minor roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9916.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to get to Umoljani then try and find Lukomir. Which we thought would be a simple affair as the map shows a track to Lukomir and we also saw the occasional sign. But we where wrong, these just lead to Umoljani. After about 40 minutes or so, we decided to just follow a track we came across in the opposite direction to which we had been indicated. I think we had given up on the idea of Lukomir and just fancied doing a bit of exploring, I could see a zig-zag track going up what I think was Vlahinja, which looked like it could also turn out to be a good stop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130814.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after about 15 minutes we spotted a small sign indicating Lukomir so obediently turned as indicated by the sign. The track seemed to go on forever. But eventually after passing a few shepards and their flocks we could see houses in the distance. Just outside the village is a tourist sign, which tells the &#34;Story&#34; of the village, we parked there and went for a wander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9923.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that hits you is the smell of sheep manure, there were huge piles of it, setting the odour of the area, it was not unpleasant, just strong. As we passed the first houses on the track through the village, the old ladies of the houses shouted for us to buy some of there products, which they had hanging on the fence. The seemed to mainly be slippers made of wool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to wander along the track and we got to the water spring in the centre of the village, which in the heat, offered an opportunity to cool off. Here we saw there was a small wood sign indicating food, which lead us to a few tables outside a house. We sat down and tentatively asked for drink. Cassie had juice, I cheekily asked if they had beer ... I was in luck. The guy running the place stopped to have a drink too, he had been cutting wood. He was spending the summer up in the village with his mother, at his grandfather&#39;s house. He used to be a tram driver in Sarajevo, but having spent a year training he had been waiting for two years to get a new contract. This was an opportunity for him to earn some cash for the winter, in Sarajevo. He explained that not many people spend the winter on the mountains anymore, most opt to return to Sarajevo or lower towns for the cold months. We also learnt some of the villagers stories and how sometimes too many tourists can appear. Which seemed a shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later we purchased some slippers and grabbed some stuff out the car, so we could go for a short walk and have a picnic lunch. We found an excellent spot on a peak over looking the canyon beyond the village. During lunch we talked about what to do next, I had asked if we could camp nearby and the guy who gave us drinks said we could camp where we parked. Wendy was not comfortable with that, feeling like we were intruding. So we drove down from the mountain tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first we headed out the way we came, but spotted a sign to Vrdolje and opted to follow that a different was down. This would we hope lead us to a main road on which lies Konjic, which we thought would have camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tracks require a certain amount of faith. You&#39;ll pass loads of branches, and with no signs, we always opted to take what we fought was the continuation of the main route. Always what plays in you mind is mines, which are normally indicated and should not be a problem in the area we were in but, it just sits there. We were lucky we passed a man and he confirmed we were headed in the right direction and that we should just continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About an hour or so later we popped out on the main road, and looked for camping on Konjic. Which was fairly well sign posted. We had to pay a small 5 KM toll to take the road into the campsite, which considering it was 50m beyond the toll man was steep. We did not mind though. The campsite was basic, which we like, outdoor shower, lake to swim and a horrible toilet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked, grabbed a beer from the fridge and went to cool down in the lake. Later we popped into the restaurant in the site and had Ćevapi for dinner with several beers. All of these places have restaurants and being so cheap, we have been using them rather than cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11 - Jajce to Sarajevo</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 19:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130707.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We packed up fairly sharpish this morning the plan was to have coffee and breakfast in Jajce, then explore. We got in to town easily from the campsite and managed to find parking. Dan accidentally purchased a day of parking for 5 KM (about 2.5 euro). Jajce is a candidate for a Unesco site, so we expect to find something fairly special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked into what we thought was the Old Town, the traffic was immense. The heat was already building and we decided to stop and have a coffee and breakfast before we headed out to explore. This being easier said than done. All the cafés were a little strange, so we opted for the most full…going with the thought process that if it&#39;s full, it must be ok. We decided to order a cappuccino instead of a coffee…we will not do this again. We promptly drank up and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130714.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wondering around and down a slippery, pebble polished set of stairs (from all the wear), we had no idea where we were going. We couldn&#39;t find the Old Town or the waterfalls mentioned to fall from Jajce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we still had not eaten, our stomachs won and we headed for the Pekara (bakery) we had seen on our way in to get some breakfast, or now, brunch. Cassie asked if we could go to the underground church she had seen a sign for, so we headed for that. Low and Behold! We were in the the Old Town. We should have simply headed that way to begin with. We paid 6KM for all of us to go down into the catacombs. They weren&#39;t extensive, but still a lot cooler than outside as the heat was blaring and interesting. A shame that on many of the alls there was engraved graffiti as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p11307261.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130727.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we wondered up to the top of the Old Town walls, we had a look around and decided to start our journey to Sarajevo. The drive was a hot one. As we entered the city, we found it hard to navigate with our large scale map and a guide book city centre map. We eventually managed to get onto a road that was shown on the map in our Bradt guide book. From here we were able to navigate ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130747.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking … Oh parking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was none!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We navigated the one way system roughly 4 times before we decided to head on out of the city and find a hotel on the outskirts, with parking, and catch a taxi into the centre. Just on the fringe of the one way system there was a petrol station and a tiny hotel next door. It had parking! Dan pulled in and went to ask if they had a room for the night and the cost. BINGO! We were in. We decided to have a shower, a beer and then go out and explore Sarajevo and find some dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we wondered in, Dan had seen an Apple store at the Sarajevo School of Arts, so we decided to head there and see if they had some noise cancelling headphones for Dan and Cassie to use. Cassie wanted to cross the bridge on the entrance to the centre as it was &#34;curly&#34;. We then decided to get a city map so we could find the Turkish quarter (Baščaršija) where the guide book said it was the best place to get a feel for Sarajevo. After wondering a bit and finding the quarter, we explored the stalls and did some souvinir shopping. Cassie and I bought some clothing from a shop that sold only hand made Bosnian clothes. Cassie got a shawl/poncho and Wendy got a lovely top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130751.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went in search of a place that sold ćevapi, as we had seen everyone sitting outside on the street restaurants eating ćevapi. Ćevapi is a meat sausage made from lamb or beef, or a mix, in a pita type bread served with sour cream/yoghurt and onions. It was lovely! The restaurants were full and after wondering around a bit we found one where the waiter put us on a table with another lady. She happened to be a student from Holland doing her Thesis in Bosnia on Genoside and Reconciliation. She was very good company and a lovely dinner partner to chat to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130767.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we looked for a place to have a beer, but being in the muslim part of the town, beer was a tad hard to find being served. We decided to just head back to the hotel and have a beer there. An opportunity to update this blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130750.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10 - Bihac to Jajce</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/05/day-10-bihac-to-jajce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 16:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/05/day-10-bihac-to-jajce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130633.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a short day today, we left the campsite at a leisurely pace and drove around 150km to Jajce. It looked to be a fairly simple drive following the road numbered 5 for Sarajevo. Jajce was before Sarajevo but signs did not appear until about 70km from Bihac.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130623.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this thing about having to have my headlights on in the summer, I know it is the law in a lot of countries. But I just don&#39;t like it. I would understand in the winter, but in the summer it does nothing but waste fuel! Anyhow this again got me pulled over by the Police (it also happened in Serbia twice and once in Montenegro), I did not see them in time to put the lights on, a grumpy cop pulled me over in a Serbian part of the country as we passed through. I apologised pretending to be forgetful, he asked me to get out and demanded documents, we had everything so he did not seem too fussed. He asked where we were going, I pointed at Jajce on the map. He sent us on the way. We joked that had it not been in the Serbian part the cops would not have cared. We did pass lots of Police prior to the incident and got away with it. Oh well. It was fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway we got to Jajce in time for lunch by the lake, followed by a swim and a beer in the local lake side restaurant, Cassie spent time looking at the fish and getting Damsel flies to land on her hand. The lake was nice and had interesting mills, but was not the most pleasant place to swim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later we went looking for the &#34;Autocamp&#34; we had passed, it was simple, not next to the lake and once we were in, fairly pleasant. We spent the afternoon catching up on stuff. Reading on the grass and checking maps etc. I also checked out routes to Lukomir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, Jajce is a candidate for a UNESCO site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished the evening by having dinner and several locals beers. We also booked into a Sarajevo Hotel online to allow us to explore tomorrow. Tomorrow we planned to have a look around Jajce and head for Sarajevo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>