<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bovec on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/bovec/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bovec on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/bovec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7 - Rafting Bovec</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/02/day-7-rafting-bovec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 20:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/02/day-7-rafting-bovec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we said last night, we were today booked to go rafting. Cassie and I (Dan) needed to be in town for just before 1300 to get kitted up. This made for an easy start to the day, we planned to have several coffees and breakfast very slowly. After which we headed for the river again, to our secret beach. Shhh. We spent a few hours perfecting our little dam that formed a pool, we did not really swim in it though, just spent the whole time building it. I guess someone else will enjoy it after us!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9856.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we planned on walking to town, we had a very early lunch and were munching just before 12. Just as we were finishing, ready to walk into town, our German neighbour popped over to offer us a lift. He is a German from Hamburg with a deep Irish accent ... still can&#39;t get my head round it. Needless to say, this meant Cassie and I were in town with 45 minutes to kill. We made light work of this thou. We each had an ice cream, then disappeared looking for a sticker for the car. With this done, it was time to go and get kitted up. It turned out it would be us and a Czech family in the raft, once we got all the kit sorted we all jumped into the van on a short drive to the Srpenica1 launch point. What followed was around 10km of fun, which encompassed around two hours of laughs and excitement. We eventually exited at Trnovo1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9888.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the start and finish, we spent a lot of time paddling, which was broken up in the calm sections by some swimming, a stop to drink the water. We also stopped to use the raft as a slide and also for a grown up jump. The kids where not allowed as it was over 7 meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9892.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final section of the run was very calm, so Cassie and I bailed out and floated the final section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9907.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half an hour later Cassie and I were wandering home, well, to the camp through the woods. She had an Ice Tea and chocolate, I had a Radler Beer. Very cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 - Bovec</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/01/day-6-bovec/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/01/day-6-bovec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Order of today was to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The girls asked for a nice walk along the river, so after gathering breakfast and lunch goodies from the camp shop, we packed up and set off for a leisurely walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9746.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walk took us across a few rope bridges on the Soča and Koritnica rivers, much to my dismay, with Cassie and Dan happily jumping on them to make them swing up and down. I decided that crossing once they got to the other side was a lot less stressful. At one particular bridge we came across a group of kayakers that were climbing up from the river, to the bridge, and then jumping off the bridge into the river. The whoops of joy could be heard echoing up and down the river.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9760.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while Cassie wanted to have a swim in the river. Luckily at this point our walk ended up at the bridge near the kayak school near Čezsoča and so we decided to have lunch down by the river here and have a dip, if we were brave enough to submerse ourselves in the freezing water. I was the first to get in and get wet by simply bumbling along and falling in the water. Dan encouraged me to dive under and so I did, coming up with brain freeze! Dan was next and Cassie just ambled up and down the river playing with the rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9756.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan was interested in kayaking the river, so we enquired at the kayak school about both him and Cassie going on a trip. After a chat, we decided to head up into Bovec, do some shopping and enquire at a few more places. Dan eventually booked himself and Cassie in for a 1pm rafting tour the following day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf9794.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Cassie had managed to sleep the whole night in her own tent. Dan had promised her an ice cream sundae and so we stopped at a lovely ice cream place she has had an ice cream at before, which must be one of the last few places to have ice cream at a euro a scoop. Cassie ordered a whopper of a banana split. With the specific rule that we were allowed to let her eat the whole thing without stopping her. This we agreed to. She never did manage to finish it. Luckily Dan was around to finish up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to camp for a dinner at the camp restaurant and a few, much need beers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 - Ramsau am Dachstein to Bovec</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/31/day-5-ramsau-am-dachstein-to-bovec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 19:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/31/day-5-ramsau-am-dachstein-to-bovec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not a lot happened today. Today was a relatively short hop to one of our favourite areas, we have been to Bovec several times, normally because it is convenient to stop at on our journey to where ever we are going. The difference this time was that we wanted to stay at a campsite we had walked through near the river Koritnica, which is actually in Vodenca about 2 km from Bovec. Having left early from yesterdays campsite, stopped for breakfast and lunch we arrived relatively early at about 1330. Unfortunately the reception of the campsite was closed until 1600.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting here was interesting, we used the &lt;a title=&#34;Wurzen Pass&#34; href=&#34;http://www.dangerousroads.org/austria/259-wurzen-pass-austria.html&#34;&gt;Wurzen pass&lt;/a&gt; on the way out of Austria which features 18% inclines and a few hair pins, for this with the fully loaded Landy low range is fairly useful. This was followed by using the 206 road which goes from Kranjska Gora to Bovec. This road we had previously travel in the other direction several years ago and resulted in Cassie reliving her breakfast. This&lt;a title=&#34;Vrsic Pass&#34; href=&#34;http://www.dangerousroads.org/slovenia/619-vri-pass-slovenia.html&#34;&gt; road&lt;/a&gt;, has some pretty serious gradients and cobbled sections, the views are spectacular. There are 50 numbered hairpin turnings, but I would say at least a hundred turns in total, as they are only numbered if they are proper hairpins! I think both of these roads feature on the Dangerous roads website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Vodenca, as we knew the area, we just left the car on the side of the road and wandered down to the river, to have lunch on the other side. To cross the river you have to use one of the wire bridges, which Wendy does not like, Cassie and I bounced over it in joy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water was no warmer than usual, it must be about 10 degrees Celsius, cold enough to cause pain in your feet and hands. Cassie got dunked for soaking me having promised she would not and I eventually managed to get in and out in a very short second. Wendy took the option of looking pretty on the stoney beach. By the time this was done it was almost time for the reception to open so we killed the last few minutes, having a Radler at the bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan for tomorrow was to have a chilled day of walking and swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>