<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>National Park on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/national-park/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in National Park on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/national-park/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 19 - 21: 17 - 21 AUGUST 2011 Trogir (Croatia) – Plitvička Jezera Nationalni Park (Croatia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/22/day-19-21-17-21-august-2011-trogir-croatia-plitvicka-jezera-nationalni-park-croatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 17:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/22/day-19-21-17-21-august-2011-trogir-croatia-plitvicka-jezera-nationalni-park-croatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Korana 171KN per night – 3 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Well…what a record, up and gone by 8.15hrs!!! Plus, Wendy went to pay for the night and made a complaint about being put on a pitch that wasn’t a pitch but a dog toilet! Well…they didn’t like this, but they still gave us a “discount”. We just wanted to leave this awful place. We decided to head for Plitvička Jezera. No GPS to navigate us, so we decided to just head for the motorway. It was a toll road but fast, so we just sat back and drove. We finally made our exit and headed for the lakes. We found a campsite and decided 3 nights was a good stop. We were fairly early, so set up camp, went looking for a shop to buy lunch and dinner for today from. Back to camp and we just chillaxed, as Dan and Cassie say. Cassie and Dan watched a movie on the laptop while Wendy lay in the sun reading. Ah! Great to relax. We did some washing of clothes and got wifi at the information centre. Here we also got information on the lakes and entry prices. Had a beer at the bar and then headed back for our braai for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9547.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 20: THURSDAY 18 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Had a little lie in, but the heat of the sun coming over drove us out of our tents. We had a lazy breakfast and headed off to explore the lakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;SHEESH!!! Talk about crowds! It was 11.30hrs and the car park was packed. We wondered over to the entrance and joined the extremely long queu for tickets. Dan managed to get student price by showing his University of Birmingham student card and Cassie being 6yrs old, was free! Actually, thats been a good thing about travelling through most of these countries, under 6yrs and you aren’t charged for them…BONUS!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So we followed the hoards into the national park, boy were there hoards. We made the choice to walk around and not catch the boat across the big lake. Once we got passed the point where everyone was boarding the boats, the crowds fizzled out and you could actually enjoy the walk. The walk took us 3½hrs and left the lakes at 15.00hrs. The lakes were beautiful. Crystal clear, you could see right down to the bottom of quite a few of them. Fish and ducks galore. We headed back to the supermarket for supplies. Back at camp, we lazed around and did a bit more washing etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A little accident happened to us the night before, we had bought 2 bottles of olive oil, one for us and one as a gift. Dan got ours out to cook with and when he went to open it, the cork popped out like gun fire. He asked me to find the second bottle, but I couldn’t find it. Dan eventually found it, exploded in the toiletry and medical box! Needless to say, we spent the next hour or so cleaning olive oil off our medicines. Not a happy moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we took the computer to the bar and had a pivo whilst checking emails etc. Then we went back to camp and had another braai for dinner. We were going to head for the Barać caves just up the road tomorrow, then come back, do house keeping ready to leave early the next morning before the sun’s heat becomes unbearable in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9455.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9457.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9469.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9494.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9506.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9514.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 21: FRIDAY 19 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Another lazy start with a leisurely breakfast. Dan and Cassie went to check emails whilst Wendy went to shower. All dressed, so off we set for the Barać caves. After a little navigating hiccup, we found our way there and set off for the tour. We were told by some nice Dutch couple that the caves were 9°C, we decided to brave it without a jumper. In a small group, with our guide, we headed up to the caves. Hard hat kitted out, we entered the cave and so the tour began. We were told that flashes on our cameras were not allowed, but people continued to use them and eventually our guide banned the use of cameras outright. We managed to get a few pictures though. And I didn’t use the flash I might add. Cave expedition over, and back to camp we headed. Again we did mundane house keeping – clothes washing etc. and then relaxed in the sun. That evening we packed up camp ready for an early rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9553.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9569.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 13/14: 11/12 AUGUST 2011 Žabljak (Montenegro) – Donji Morinj (Montenegro)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/13/day-1314-1112-august-2011-zabljak-montenegro-donji-morinj-montenegro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 17:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/13/day-1314-1112-august-2011-zabljak-montenegro-donji-morinj-montenegro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Ravela €30 – 2 nights + €6 for electricity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today we drove down to the coast of Montenegro. We first took the scenic route out of Durmitor…what a drive. Amazing views and mountains. We stopped for a coffee along the way and Dan managed to buy himself a Durmitor t-shirt. When we arrived at the coast, and drove around the bay, the views were wonderful. Especially the drive down the mountain to the bay. We stopped off and bought some wine from a couple selling home made vino. We wanted to get as far around the bay as possible. But even so, we didn’t find a campsite till much later on. We were praying we wouldn’t have to stay in a pension as it looked like an expensive area. We finally found a nice little campsite nestled on a river with lime and olive trees planted around it. We even camped next to another Landy! We set up camp, it was late, so we wondered up to the mini market and got a small snack for dinner. An early-ish night, ready for the beach tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8981.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;101&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8982.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8983.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8992.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8998.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;99&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 14: Friday 12 August 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Last night there was very load Montenegrin music. Apparently there is a music festival happening over the weekend. Woke up and did some much needed clothes washing! The day was already stinking hot and the few bits and bobs Wendy washed yesterday were already dry. Once everything was hung up, we headed for the beach. It was a scorcher of a day but the sea was quite chilly. Wendy read her book and soaked up the rays whilst Dan and Cassie paddled and explored. After a couple of hours on the beach, we went and got some bits and bobs for lunch and took it all back to the campsite. Here we did some more washing, ate lunch and went on the internet. After the heat got to us a little more, we went back for another dip in the sea. We also investigated the local restorant to see what their prices were like…EXPENSIVE! Back to the supermarket to get a snack dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9010.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9014.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9027.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9041.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9058.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9059.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9065.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9086.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 11/12: 9/10 AUGUST 2011 Studenica (Serbia) – Durmitor National Park (Montenegro)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 17:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/11/day-1112-910-august-2011-studenica-serbia-durmitor-national-park-montenegro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Autokamp Razvršje €10 – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We attempted to have a lie in this morning, we managed to sleep until 7.50am! A shower to wash away the bed bugs and another cereal breakfast in our room. Off into the Monastery for a look see. The monastery was quiet, we seemed to be the only visitors at that time. The restoration team were there hard at work and inside the chapel it seemed like they had a lot of work on their hands and perhaps for a few many years. Off we went onto our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8851.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8869.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8883.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Back through that little town Ivanjeca, where this time we bought a plastic sealed drum/tub to act as our washing machine. Our washing was now getting out of hand. The border crossing into Montenegro was a breeze with the Green card only €15 this time! We finally made it to Durmitor and we found a campsite! A stop of 2 nights and a proper rest up. It was our anniversary, we wanted to go out for dinner, but town was a bit of a walk. Instead, we had dinner cooked by the campsite owner an elderly local lady. Trout, Bean soup, salad and potatoes oh and free beer. It was a lovely meal. They had erected an old military mess tent to act as a dining room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8914.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 12: WEDNESDAY 10 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It rained last night, not heavily, but a lot. And when we woke up, it was still raining. We stayed in the tent because of the rain. Dan got up and made us tea and coffee, we drank it inside the tent. Today was a day that having our big tent would have been useful with its big middle bit. We’d used up all the milk, so we decided to go into town to get breakfast. As we left we thought we’d look at the time…it was 11.30! We walked into town and attempted to change our Serbian Dinar into Euro, but no-one was having it. We went to the baker and got: 1 loaf of bread, 2 donuts, 1 pastry, 2 sausage rolls and 1 jam cake slice…all for €3.30! Bargain! It was off to the supermarket for supplies. As it was still raining on and off we decided to come back into town for dinner. We stopped for a coffee and juice and headed back to the camp. We made up a sandwich for Wendy, packed up the back pack and headed off for Crno Jezero or Black Lake. The walk was 20-25 min walk there. Along the way we walked through an abandoned Serbian holiday camp. Very eerie and spooky. When we got to the lake, we walked around it to find Tito’s cave where he’s said to have hid his supplies during the 2nd World War. The cave was no longer a cave, it seemed to have been blocked up. A little disappointing. We walked back to camp. The walk back was a little harder as all up hill. When we got back none of us were hungry, so we decided to just have a drink and snack and possibly an early night, with prayers of a sunny morning. We ended up ordering food from the lady again: pork chops, potatoes and salad, free beer too.. We had an early night, ready to move on in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8915.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8923.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8927.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8928.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8941.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8951.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8945.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF8947.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>