<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Serbia on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/serbia/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Serbia on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/serbia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Serbia, Unexpected off road</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/01/serbia-unexpected-off-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 09:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/01/serbia-unexpected-off-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just been playing with the iPad iMovie app. Last year when we were in Serbia, we were following the GPS to go from the Studenica monastery to Durmitor and ended up going along a grade gravel road. This as it turned out, was the foundation for a section of soon to be E-760, we think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;We ended up turning back after giving the workers a few laughs. We had fun, they got a laugh everyone&amp;#039;s a winner. After turning back we ended up following another proper farm track which turned out to be good fun. We got a little lost and came across a farmer who looked bemused!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we popped out the other side a little muddy and happy with the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first video shows were the GPS thought we were. The second shows the farm track that we eventually used.
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HWU9MqfHTYU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JB1uuHmhOEg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 10: MONDAY 8 AUGUST 2011 Mokra Gora (Serbia) – Studenica (Serbia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/09/day-10-monday-8-august-2011-mokra-gora-serbia-studenica-serbia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 17:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/09/day-10-monday-8-august-2011-mokra-gora-serbia-studenica-serbia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: Studenica Hotel €15 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Up early with a breakfast of our cereal and milk. A shower and change and off to Mokra Gora Ŝargan Eight Railway. We got there early, so bought tickets, sorted out the back of the Landy and went to have a coffee. We saw crowds growing and the engine head for the carriages. Dan went to pay and Cassie and Wendy went to get a seat on one of the carriages. So the journey began. The train had speakers playing the story of the railway in Serbian, and surprisingly, English too! The journey up was interesting, a few tunnels we went through and a stop at the top where we bought an ice cream. Then, on the journey down the train stopped at all these platforms, the story referred to them as ‘crazy stops’, it made the journey back a lot longer than it needed to be. When we got back, we loaded ourselves up and set off for Studenica and the Monastery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8730.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8734.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8735.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The drive was hard going with the windy mountain passes. We stopped in a funny little town called Ivanjeca for lunch and to get some more money. We decided to have ice cream sundaes for lunch as non of us were particularly hungry…probably the stinking heat we were experiencing today. The sundaes we ordered turned out to be fruit salads with ice cream and cream. Dan’s was a kind of float sundae concoction. Yummy never the less. Off we trudged for the rest of our journey. As we drove we wondered where on earth the monastery was. It seemed as though we were just driving and getting no where! Finally, around the corner it came into view! Relief washed over us. We had made it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;First thing we saw was a great big sign telling us: NO SLEEVELESS SHIRTS, SHORT SKIRTS TO GO INTO THE MONASTERY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That counted that evening out as Wendy was in a boob-tube and skirt, Cassie was in a sleeveless shirt and Dan was in shorts…non of us were in the mood to change either. We decided to park at the sign that showed sobe/rooms and enquire about prices to stay. We thought that we would stay 2 nights, firstly to rest and secondly to explore and maybe take a swim in the river. The receptionist told us €15 for the 3 of us for 1 night. We agreed, got our key and went to investigate. The smell hit us first…damp, old and mothballs. Then the visual got us…pot hanging from the ceiling in the corner to catch water, ceiling masking taped together, light bulb cello-taped together and the list carried on. We thought this was the only place to stay, so we gathered our bits and bobs and put them into the room and went for a pivo and sok. The “hotel” had no kitchen so we had to walk up behind the monastery to get food. It turns out there’s another hotel, one in much better condition that we could have stayed at…oh well…too late now! A Serbian guy at the hotel, who was working at the monastery on a conservation project, told us that the hotel we were eating at and the Studenica Hotel were taken over by the Monastery. They were now just resting places. The one we ate at had just had some work done to it, but the one we were staying at hadn’t had anything done to it for at least 30 years! That night we slept wondering if bed bugs were going to gnaw us and if the ceiling would collapse on Wendy in the night. We woke up in one piece and decided to hit the road. One night was enough. It was off to Durmitor National Park in Montenegro. Good bye to the Hotel from the Shinning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8814.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8815.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8817.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8821.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 9: SUNDAY 7 AUGUST 2011 Fruŝka Gora (Serbia) – Mokra Gora (Serbia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/08/day-9-sunday-7-august-2011-fruska-gora-serbia-mokra-gora-serbia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 17:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/08/day-9-sunday-7-august-2011-fruska-gora-serbia-mokra-gora-serbia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Private room €20 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We went to see the Ravanica Monastery near Vrdnik. They were having a service, which was expected as it was Sunday. We respected Catholic culture and crossed ourselves as we entered the church. We stayed a few minutes and listened to the priest give his sermon, not that we could understand his Serbian. We left and decided to go to another Monastery. When we got to the next Monastery, there was a sign saying, “No short skirts or strappy tops”. Both Cassie and Wendy were wearing strappy tops and Dan didn’t feel comfortable going in wearing shorts. So we walked around the side to see if we could peak in, but the monastery had a high wall. We went back to the car and decided to go off and find the next monastery. Now this part was an adventure…. We followed the GPS directions and ended up following a gravel track. We carried on a bit further and found no monastery, so we decided to just head straight for Mokra Gora. The battery for the camera ran out at this point and we missed out on taking photos of the beautiful scenery we passed on the way to Mokra Gora. We stopped at a little bar for lunch and the lady made us, what we think was a Serbian Hamburger, it was more like a lardy shredded pork pattie. We then hopped back into the car and made our way. We stopped at a roadside stall to buy some Med (honey) and some Rakija, a plum brandy made in Serbia. We should have haggled with the ladies, but when you can only ask how much and understand the basics of what they are hand gesturing to you, bargaining isn’t quite on the cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Wendy had found a campsite mark on the map, so we tried to find it, to no avail. We don’t think they have campsites here and unfortunately, we just weren’t brave enough to free camp in the area as it looked to be mostly farmed land. As we saw the sign for Mokra Gora, we saw a sign for sobe. Dan went to go and enquire. The sobe turned out to be a small apartment. Cassie stayed free and it was €20 for Dan and Wendy for 1 night. Bargain! We stayed, and had to reverse Tusky into the track alongside the apartment. That was a little challenge. At one point Tusky tipped and it felt as if she was going to tumble sideways…but she didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we walked up to the film set town – Mećavnik to have dinner. The town was built by a Serbian film director for a movie. It is built as a typical 19th century Serbian town and serves typical Serbian dishes in it’s restaurants. There were some singers and a band performing classic Serbian songs. Which, according to Dan, gave the place a surreal feeling. We ate dinner, had a wonder around and walked back down to our room. We planned to leave early and catch the Ŝargan Eight Railway. After that, we were to head to Studenica and the monastery there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8688.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8699.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8707.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8701.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8724.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8702.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 8: SATURDAY 6 AUGUST 2012 Velika (Croatia) – Fruŝka Gora (Serbia)</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/07/day-8-saturday-6-august-2012-velika-croatia-fruska-gora-serbia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2011 17:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/07/day-8-saturday-6-august-2012-velika-croatia-fruska-gora-serbia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;Camping Costs: Hotel/Pension Restoran Zmajevac €27 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to head off into Serbia today but stop in a town called Ilik to see a castle and war memorial. We stopped for coffee which was very nice. Afterwards we headed off to Ilok. The town holds a memorial for the 1991 war. We first stopped at the Ovĉara Memorial which is the site of a mass grave. The towns people of Vukovar were massacred by the Serbs during the invasion. 200 people fled and hid in the local hospital. The Serb army found them and mass murdered them, burying them in a mass grave. Ovĉara is a memorial on the sight where they were found. The floor is set with with all the bullets found in the grave. A very humbling experience. From there we stopped at a vineyard, as Ilok is a wine region and had lunch. The wine was Traminac and was VERY nice, so we bought some. From here we headed to the Serbian border, where we waited to get Green Card Insurance. Here we waited, in the steaming sun, for 40 min or more. The insurance turned out to be €110 for 1 month. When the man finally returned with our insurance, we started our adventure into Serbia. We looked for road signs to Fruŝka Gora, but didn’t see any till we got into the industrial area of Novi Sad. Serbia looks very different to the other countries we have been in so far. A lot more rural even in the city. We stopped for money and to try use the GPS to help navigate us. Serbia uses a cryillic alphabet, it makes reading road signs etc. a lot harder. We found ourselves at the top of the road turning in the Fruŝka Gora park, but not having seen any signs for camping. We decided to carry on looking. We saw some people pitched on the side of the road in a caravan, but we were a little nervous of free camping. We managed to find a sign that said “sobe”, meaning rooms, and headed in that direction. We found a restaurant that also had rooms above it. The price was €27 for all of us, (Cassie stayed free), including breakfast. We decided to stay. We got out the maps and guide books and planned for where to go next. We decided to go and see the monasteries in the park and then head for another national park where they have a little railway you can go on. Mokra Gora, the line used to run all the way to Sarajevo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8638.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8640.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8643.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8650.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8667.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning the Summer 2011 Trip</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/07/26/planning-the-summer-2011-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/07/26/planning-the-summer-2011-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This Summer Dan has managed to wangle 4 weeks off work. To add to that, Wendy has changed jobs and now has the school holidays off, so she has 6 weeks holiday over the Summer! This has allowed us to open up our plans, expand our horizons and we have this year decided to travel down to the Serbia, Montenegro and the Bosnia area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As usual we consulted our UNESCO World Heritage book for ideas of places to stop in the countries we would like to be visiting this year. We also bought Bradt travel guides for the same countries and started our “plan”, we only do this to amuse Wendy, Dan would rather just book the ferries point the Landy in the right direction and be done with it. Luckily the plans are never stuck too, not even the ferry bookings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have a Michelin Europe Map (705), which is on a really large scale (1:3 000 000), which is great for planning our trips. It gets more and more tatty each year, not to mention colourful. So, we sat down with our trusty old Europe map and plotted places we found in book, on-line and in the guides. With help from a few glasses of Vino, this is what we came up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8029.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had this plotted, we decided to draw up a Google map. Unfortunately Google won’t route you through Bosnia, so we have had to route around Bosnia to create our map. Pity really. We have shared this Google map with family so that they know the rough route we plan on travelling. We should really just say we are heading to Devon for a month, any mention of going further a field tends to instil panic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/summer-2011-overview-map.jpg?w=640&#34; width=&#34;515&#34; height=&#34;371&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Between the plan’s inception and leaving there were a few things to sort out. When you leave the EU you need an international driving permit (IDP), we got this at a local post office in WHSmiths, what a bad experience! The cue was massive and the staff a bit unfamiliar. Next time I think we will use the AA postal service. Apart from the IDP, insurance is an issue. The EU 3rd party cover will not be valid in some countries out side Europe, like Serbia. We managed to confirm that a green card would be available on the border. Prices vary wildly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Over and above paper work, maps needed sorting, both paper 1:200 000 and GPS. The car needed a service and a couple of niggles sorting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Only 4 days to go and the car needs to be packed up by Thursday as Dan has a meeting Friday. The flat once again looks like a camping store with piles here and boxes there… Clothes are being washed ready to get packed up. Pity the English weather isn’t being helpful in the way of supplying sunshine. But it looks like all is going ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>