<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maps on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/maps/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maps on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/maps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit to the Map Shop - Stanfords</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 18:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/image.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves at a loose end this morning, the weather was iffy. So we took a pleasant ride into London for a wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are considering are plans for the summer so decided we&#39;d pop to the map shop in London. Those of you who don&#39;t know it. This is probably the best place to purchase maps and travel books in London. It has three floors of books and maps normally in the scale you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a Bradt Albania Guide, a 1:150k Kosovo map, 1:200k Albania map, 1:400 Bulgaria map and 1:500k Romania / Moldova map, the latter two are not ideal scales for what we need but they&#39;ll do. I&#39;ll probably get better scales if I can find them. Unfortunately I could not find a decent Macedonia map so had to resort to Amazon for that and a Kosovo and Macedonia guide book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance you should pop in, it is a pretty cool shop!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful maps for exploring the Maritime Alps</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; If your planning on exploring the tracks around the Maritime Alps on the French / Italian border, you&amp;#039;ll need a few maps of the area. The best single retailer for maps in the UK is Stanford maps in London. They have three floors of travel books and maps. This is where I got our maps months prior to departing. Of course you can try online also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#039;t have to buy the maps before you leave, they are sold locally in France. You will need something with some detail though, equivalent to the UK Ordnance Survey (OS) map, which is 1:25k or 1:50k depending on the series you go for. In France the equivalent is the Institut Geographique National (IGN) they do a 1:25k map series which covers the whole of France. Where ever you go in France you can normally by IGN maps of the local area. So you could buy on arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the IGN maps, we also used the Italian equivalent as we found the IGN maps loose detail on shortly after the border. These maps are Istituto Geografico Centrale (IGC). At Stanfords they had these in 1:50k. They have a slightly vintage feel in the style of printing, but they are very clear. Interestingly they also show prohibited routes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I should also mention is that Garmin maps have a lot of the tracks we used, well certainly in the European City Navigator 2012. Not all though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1320.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Here are some pictures of the maps we used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 8 Alpi Marittime E Liguri (ISBN 9788896455081)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 1 Valli Di Susi Chisone E Germanasca (ISBN 9788896455012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3841 OT Vallée De La Roya, Vallée Des Merveilles, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 3282113841030)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3741 ET Vallées De La Bévéra Et Des Paillons, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 9782758524083)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1319.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-2129.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And in case you are interested the back of the first one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-13191.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Durmitor National Park, Montenegro - Garmin Maps</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/28/durmitor-national-park-montenegro-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 20:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/28/durmitor-national-park-montenegro-maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-11-sep-2011-10142.jpg?w=253&#34; alt=&#34;Durmitor National Park 1:25000 map&#34; width=&#34;253&#34; height=&#34;338&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we stayed in Durmitor National park, during our August 2011 trip, the guy who seemed to run the camp site at &lt;a title=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.durmitor-autocamp.com/home.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;Autocamp Razvršje&lt;/a&gt;, gave us a great walking map, which I kept, being a map addict. Actually I think he gave one to everyone, so we weren&#39;t special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, by luck the other day they sent out a marketing email. Intrigued I browsed their site and noticed they had an electronic copy of the map and others on their site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are pretty good maps of the area in 1:25,000 scale. So I thought I would grab a copy for next time I am there. Anyway, follow the link above to their site to get a copy or there are links below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also if you need a place to stay, Autocamp Razvršje is as good as any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Some Garmin devices such as the Montana series allow the importing of custom maps. This is done via Google Earth. You have to import the map as a layer to Google Earth then align it (georeference), then save it as a KMZ. Once this is done you can import it to Garmin&#39;s Basecamp or upload it and save it to the Custom Map folder on your GPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a copy of the Durmitor KMZ I made click &lt;a title=&#34;Garmin Durmitor KMZ&#34; href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/Durmitor National Park Map 25k.kmz&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructions on creating custom maps are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/custommaps_instruct.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:none;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-19491.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-19491.jpg?w=650&#34; alt=&#34;Durmitor&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;469&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:none;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1949.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1949.jpg?w=650&#34; alt=&#34;Tara Canyon&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;469&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/tara-kanjon-karta.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tara Canyon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/primorje.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Montenegro Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/060214_m.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Montenegro General&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>