<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Littlehampton on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/littlehampton/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Littlehampton on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/littlehampton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend stroll - Ford to Littlehampton, West Sussex</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/28/weekend-stroll-ford-to-littlehampton-west-sussex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 19:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/28/weekend-stroll-ford-to-littlehampton-west-sussex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the weather forecast looking good, we decided that today we were going for a walk, a walk with criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The criteria was that it had to have a start and finish at a railway station and that we wanted to say away from crowds. It also had to have locations that would be suitable for a picnic lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said we decided to head on the train to Ford from our local station, 36 minutes away. The plan was to follow the river Arun towards the beach the follow the foot paths and a byway to bring us on to the beach circa 2 miles west of Littlehampton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/fordtolittlehamptonwalk.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had lunch on the beach then headed for the railway station in Littlehampton to head home. We timed it perfectly arriving three minutes before the 1414 to London departed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This route took us about 2.5 hours and is pretty flat, it is just under 10 kilometers. So with lunch we averaged about 4 km/h.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to download the GPX file, you can grab it from &lt;a title=&#34;GPS Route&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B3lq5J_TSkjFMDBmTmU3TnZ2dzg/edit?usp=sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>