<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slovakia on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/slovakia/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slovakia on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/slovakia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 13: 19 AUGUST, Vodńa Nádž (Voklav, Slovakia) – Martin (Slovakia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/20/day-13-19-august-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia-martin-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 16:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/20/day-13-19-august-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia-martin-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Hotel cost: €80 double room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Up at the normal time, packed up and made tracks for Martin. Not too much of a journey today thankfully. We reached Martin at about 2pm and parked up to look for a hotel/B&amp;amp;B. We managed to find a B&amp;amp;B, but it happened to be a 4* hotel. A decision was made to stay for the night. For a 4* hotel, the room were pretty undistinguishable and there was no air conditioning. At this point Cassie had decided to go up to the rooms with Pete and did not tell us where she had gone. I had been at the car getting clothes and Dan had been sorting out the payment and did not see her go with Pete. We were both in an absolute panic! The receptionist saw this and simply stood there looking at us! I mean, she did absolutely nothing and when we asked her to call Pete’s room she simply said “I already have, there’s no answer”, Dan was starting to loose his temper and asked her to try again. That was it for me, the hotel dropped all it’s 4* in my eyes thanks to their receptionists disgusting behaviour. I decided to go up to the rooms to look for her whilst Dan stayed downstairs. I managed to find her with Pete. Phew! Panic over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We dumped our stuff in the room and went off out into town for a beer and snack. The beers in Slovakia are strong, 12%, needless to say this loosened Dan up and he declared “Lets go buy a tent!”. Martin seemed to have many camping and outdoor extreme sports stores. He had been saying for ages that he wanted us to have 2 smaller tents for these trips and the big tent for camping back home. So what happened? We ended up buying 2 new tents! After this we had to go back to the hotel so Dan could erect the new tents. We all had a bath, shaves etc. and then went down to the bar for a beer. We wondered around looking for a restaurant. We managed to find a restaurant tucked away inside a mall. Lucky for us the menu was in English/Slovak. Our phrasebook was turning out to be damn useless at deciphering menus and road signs. This meal was expensive compared to all the others we have had, city prices I guess. Back to the hotel and a farewell to Pete as he was getting up early to leave in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Breakfast was nothing exciting. Once again the hotel showed its rubbish customer service. We showed up in the dining room with no staff there to tell us where to sit, so we sat at any table. Got food, sat down only to be told very gruffly to move to another table. We weren’t even offered any help to carry our food to the other table, at the other end of the room too! We ate and left, nice to see the back of that place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080838.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080839.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080844.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 11/12: 17/18 AUGUST,  Nová Sedlica – Vodńa Nádž (Voklav, Slovakia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/19/day-1112-1718-august-nova-sedlica-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2010 16:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/19/day-1112-1718-august-nova-sedlica-vodna-nadz-voklav-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping costs: €22 – 2 nights for 3 adults, 1 child, 2 tents &amp;amp; 2 cars&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to stop at the pension we had wanted to stay at for a drink before setting off again. What a pity it had been full, it looked like a lovely place to stay. Perhaps if we are back in that neck of the woods again we might book into it. Out of interest we asked when they would have a free room, they said they were fully booked for the next week. There were plums and apples growing on the side of the roads next to the pension, Cassie picked some and ate them. Not quite ripe enough, but she seemed to enjoy them all the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Today’s camp site search was a long and interesting one. So, the map showed a camp site, we headed there. Only to find that it was just day camping, for swimming. We decided that it was a good enough spot to have lunch and look at the map to see where the other camp sites were plotted. We saw that there were 3 on the other side of the lake and decided to head for those. The first one was full of travellers, scary, so we moved on. The next we just could not find. The 3rd, again was a site for travellers. There were these camp sites on the map, but they just didn’t exist. It was now getting late. Pete decided to consult his GPS to find B&amp;amp;Bs listed in the area or camp sites. He finds a camp site, hotel and B&amp;amp;B listed on the opposite side of the lake. We decide to head there. When we get there, there is a toll to pay to access the road down to the camp site. We paid €2.50, Pete paid €2…why Pete paid a different price, we just don’t know. We finally stumbled across the camp site and decided to stay. The lake was warm, there were toilets and showers so we decided to stay for 2 nights. The tents got put up and off we went for a beer up at the bar. We made the decision to braai tonight and go out for dinner tomorrow, so off we trudged back down to the tents to cook dinner. At the Tesco in Snina we had picked up some meat, ready made Slovakian salads and vegetables. The salads were not very tasty, what was in them I still have no clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Our tents were under a street lamp type light, it was very bright. Poor Pete ended up moving his tent and Dan and I decided to put up with the light. Wendy had an awful nights sleep, but that could have also been due to a VERY loud party happening next to the camp site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080760.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080763.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 12: 18 AUGUST&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We decided to treat ourselves to a breakfast of french toast and coffee, to make up for the terrible nights sleep. We spent the day lazing in the sun and Cassie got a day swimming in the lake. A nice lazy day. We also determined the next leg of our journey, where Pete would be leaving us. We decided to head for Martin in Slovakia where Pete would go his way and we’d head off into Czech. We showered and walked to find the local eatery. The menu was small. Dan ordered what he was told to be a typical Slovak dish: Bryndzové halušky (potato dumplings with sheep’s-milk cheese). Pete and I were unadventurous and had burgers, Cassie had chicken in a mushroom sauce with chips. We paid up after Dan and Pete devoured a chocolate tart slice each. The night turned chilly and we walked back for a cold nights sleep, big contrast to the scorcher of a day we had had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080764.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080774.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080795.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 10: 16 AUGUST,  Poroszlo (Hungary) – Nová Sedlica (Slovakia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/17/day-10-16-august-poroszlo-hungary-nova-sedlica-slovakia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 16:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2010/08/17/day-10-16-august-poroszlo-hungary-nova-sedlica-slovakia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Pension: €10.00 pppn €5.00 for a child&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Up bright and early, packed up and ready to leave at our best time yet! Off into Slovakia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Tokaj (pronounced Tokay), is a lovely little town with lovely cheap wine. We bought 3 bottles and a grape juice or non alcoholic wine. The bottles were 1.5ℓ as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Ready to head off out into Slovakia. The roads were awful. HUGE potholes, making you drive in the centre of the road so as to avoid them. We made our way to Nova Sedlica to find a pension Dan and I had read about in the internet. Unfortunately, when we got there the pension was full, so we had to go back to the previous town to find another pension. When we finally found a pension, it happened to be brand new. The building hadn’t yet been rendered or fully painted. It was clean and cheap.We had dinner in the restaurant – 3 beers each, drinks for Cassie and paid for the rooms and it came to only €58.00! Comfortable nights sleep with clean shower in the morning. We had breakfast in the restaurant – 5 coffees, 3 orange juices, toast, scrambled eggs and a toasted sandwich only came to €15.00. Slovakia so far has proven to be cheap. We decided to go back to Nova Sedlica for a walk as that was the reason we wanted to stay there in the first place. The walk took us roughly 1 &amp;amp; half hours. Butterflies, insects, blackberries were but a few of the things we found along the way. We decided to go to Snina and stop at a Tesco, just to see what they are like here. We also need diesel and food before the next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080673.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080688.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/P1080726.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>