<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bavaria on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/tags/bavaria/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bavaria on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/bavaria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 - Neufchateau to Westerheim</title>
      <link>/2013/07/29/day-3-neufchateau-to-westerheim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 19:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/29/day-3-neufchateau-to-westerheim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We started the day with a good deed, jump starting a fellow camper who had apparently defective heater plugs and a weak battery. I did not ask I just obliged.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Killing miles again today, we made a plan to be beyond Stuttgart before we stopped. We were hanging by the time we got to Stuttgart, so as we passed we looked up a campsite on the GPS. We picked the nearest in the direction we were heading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130390.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some 43km later, apart from passing some camels on the way to the campsite, we did not achieve anything of much interest, the campsite was a metropolis. Had we not been stopping for one night only we would have carried on. Cassie loved it, purely because it had three pools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130397.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Needless to say as we rolled in we got one of the last spots and were tired enough not to care. Given the fact that the skies were turning eerie again and we were in for a battering. So the order of the afternoon was tent up and secured, swim for Cassie as Mum and Dad supervised with a beer, then as the rain hit, we headed for the camp restaurant for some Bavarian pork and beer. We had a two person platter which was way to much for us and drank enough beer to help us sleep throughout the storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/p1130404.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way drinking beer to get through a storm is stupid. The rain and beer make you need to pee five times more than normal… Broken night it was then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>