<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>France on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/tags/france/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in France on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful maps for exploring the Maritime Alps</title>
      <link>/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; If your planning on exploring the tracks around the Maritime Alps on the French / Italian border, you&amp;#039;ll need a few maps of the area. The best single retailer for maps in the UK is Stanford maps in London. They have three floors of travel books and maps. This is where I got our maps months prior to departing. Of course you can try online also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#039;t have to buy the maps before you leave, they are sold locally in France. You will need something with some detail though, equivalent to the UK Ordnance Survey (OS) map, which is 1:25k or 1:50k depending on the series you go for. In France the equivalent is the Institut Geographique National (IGN) they do a 1:25k map series which covers the whole of France. Where ever you go in France you can normally by IGN maps of the local area. So you could buy on arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the IGN maps, we also used the Italian equivalent as we found the IGN maps loose detail on shortly after the border. These maps are Istituto Geografico Centrale (IGC). At Stanfords they had these in 1:50k. They have a slightly vintage feel in the style of printing, but they are very clear. Interestingly they also show prohibited routes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I should also mention is that Garmin maps have a lot of the tracks we used, well certainly in the European City Navigator 2012. Not all though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1320.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Here are some pictures of the maps we used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 8 Alpi Marittime E Liguri (ISBN 9788896455081)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 1 Valli Di Susi Chisone E Germanasca (ISBN 9788896455012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3841 OT Vallée De La Roya, Vallée Des Merveilles, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 3282113841030)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3741 ET Vallées De La Bévéra Et Des Paillons, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 9782758524083)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1319.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-2129.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And in case you are interested the back of the first one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-13191.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Col Linaire, Col de Sanson, Pas de Colle Ardente - Mount Saccarel</title>
      <link>/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 19:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/04/col-linaire-col-de-sanson-pas-de-colle-ardente-mount-saccarel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7871723104_817a4bd793.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;The next track&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;282&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After finishing up on Col de Tende we headed back down to the town of Tende for supplies and to freshen up at the local piscine (swimming pool) (If only they had known!), before we departed for the second section of our little off road trip. Again we planned to stay at least one night up on the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The local chap at the fuel station we met the day before, had been correct about Col de la Boaïra being block from the Fort Central end, so we decided to heed his advice again and took his recommended entry point to the next pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With a plan in place, we kicked off by heading south from Tende fully refreshed and clean towards St Dalmas de Tende, where we turned left to head east on the D43 past La Brigue. This took us to the turning for the D143 on the right that allowed us to get to what would be the start of our next off road excursion at Notre-Dame des Fontaines. Apparently this is worth a stop to have a look, we did not take the opportunity unfortunately but will next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed straight up towards Col Linaire, which would take us up through the forest &#34;Bois Du Pinet&#34; along what seemed considerably more dusty gravel tracks than the day before. On the way up we passed an old Willis Jeep heading down, the driver, his dog and Family looked local and to be having a great time. I guess the old Williss is ideal for adhoc dog walking on your local mountain. What an awesome playground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Given the time we left Tende after our swim and restock, it was not long, probably 8 km from the church until we decided we would stop for a light lunch. We stopped at a 5 point junction that offered to easily get us lost. Luckily it was easy to work out the exit we needed, after removing the closed piste and the exit we arrived from! The junction on the map is at &#34;Cime du Pinet&#34;, which is the Top of the Pinet hill. There were various logs lying around for us to sit on to enjoy lunch. There must be a certain amount of forestry undertaken, perhaps to control the fire risk? While we were there another car was parked up with a local who had just gone mountain biking, he did not seem so friendly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7871721608_6d3de535d8.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Forest Roads&#34; width=&#34;334&#34; height=&#34;250&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After having lunch we continued up the fourth exit... Towards Col du Loup, this continued through the Forêt Communale de la Brigue it was great driving through the forests, they provided a welcome break from the heat. As we were driving up, I was conscious that although we had enough water to last us easily for at least two nights, we did not have a lot spare, so was keeping an eye open for a source that would allow is to fill the solar shower and water carrier. At this time of the year there did not seem to be many streams around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7871715168_50ec94991d_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Topping up with water&#34; width=&#34;227&#34; height=&#34;302&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily we happened upon a water trough that was reasonably full. The water looked clean enough for the intended purposes and had a steady flow into it, which meant it was not stagnant. We filled up the shower and most of the carrier. But it was a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14236.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Border marker&#34; width=&#34;339&#34; height=&#34;254&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After getting water, our final re-supply item we continued up to the border area to Col de Sanson / Baisse de Sanson. The next section hugs what I think is the 1947 border of France and Italy, it was fairly spectacular along the ridge or the south east side of Mont de Colle Ardente for the first 5 km or so, then the track pops over the top for the next roughly 6 km along the north west side of Mont Saccarel, I think this is Pas de colle Ardente or part of. This leads into Pas du Tanarel which will have you emerge on the eastern side of Mont Tanarel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14326.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-14575.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34; href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15173.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-15323.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track to Mont Saccarel &#34; width=&#34;322&#34; height=&#34;242&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It is about 2 km south of this point you have the option to proceed down towards San Bernardo and off the mountain or as we did proceed towards Mont Saccarel which is at 2200 meters. Mont Saccarels&amp;#039; summit overlooks a 12 meter statue of Jesus, that was placed there is 1901. The statue has a fantastic view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we stayed on Mont Saccarel, just below the summit which had the remains of some old fortifications. When we arrived at the summit there were some local Italians having a braai, that had driven up in there 4x4&amp;#039;s. We parked above them on the summit and decided to walk to have a look at the statue, it was about 1 km walk and would allow us time to see what the local chaps did. As it goes they disappeared shortly after we started our stroll. So after taking some photos of us and the Jesus statue we wondered back and pitch camp where they had been. Our camp straddled the border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-17542.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from the summit&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-16451.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Jesus Statue&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1646.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Group shot&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That evening we used some of the water we collected on the way up, to boil up some pasta and washing up water, no one had the trotts in the morning so needless to say the water was fine. We had a hearty vegetable pasta dish for dinner followed by beer! The rest of the evening was spent admiring the changing view in the evening light and listening to the distant cattle grazing it&amp;#039;s way across the slopes below. Once the sun had gone down we went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night I got up to look at the stars (have a pee) which were almost blinding due to the lack of light pollution, in the distance far below us there was the orange clusters of street lights in local towns and villages. I spent a few minutes admiring until the cold got to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the morning, we woke to a definite chill as you&amp;#039;d expect from a clear night at that height, the morning was glorious and I could not wait to see the view first from inside the warm shelter of the tent, then while I enjoyed the warmth of a warm fresh coffee. There was a problem though, I first had to go for a climb!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;During the night we had visitors... My flip flop had gone for a walk, only one. So armed with one of Wendy&amp;#039;s on my once bare foot, I dug out the binoculars and eventually far below I spotted the outline of my black flip flop in the rocks and shrubs. Off I trekked to get it, shortly after I put the kettle on. On recovery of my flop, I was suspicious, apart from some sizeable teeth marks, there was also a fairly stinky deposit of what I think was pee. I suspect a fox or something decided to mark it&amp;#039;s territory on my flop flip. I promptly returned to camp to deal with the situation, both proud and puzzled. By this time the kettle was boiling and with my now clean flop, we enjoyed our coffee and I pondered the curious event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My flip flops will live another summer by the looks of things, I guess the wife&amp;#039;s did not smell nice enough for our visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-3-aug-2012-0659.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Solar shower&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having fed ourselves and packed up, we freshened up under the solar shower, the moon had little effect on it&amp;#039;s temperature thou, so it was rather refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We then headed down the track we arrived on before turning off down the mountain towards San Bernardo for a coffee, before we headed for Cinque Terre our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFNXBiaFM5VFBnSmM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Gps track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1528.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The road down&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1755.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Panoramic from summit&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;165&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baisse d&#39;Ourne, Col de Tende - Fort de la Marguerie, Fort Central</title>
      <link>/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/02/col-de-tende-fort-de-la-marguerie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning we woke at our Campsite in Barolo in Italy early, the plan was to get to Tende in France, stock up on supplies at the super market, fill up with diesel, grab some petrol for the stove and head up to Col de Tende. We did fairly well and managed to have breakfast, coffee and pack up to be on the road by 0920 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-10201.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tunnel de Tende&#34; width=&#34;395&#34; height=&#34;296&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the minor back roads from Barolo to enter France via the Tunnel de Tende, on the SS20/N204. The tunnel was interesting in that it was only open one way at a time. We arrived at the back end of a line going our way, so decided to stop at the restaurant by the tunnel for a coffee and a pastry. That also gave us the opportunity to investigate the oil pressure light that was coming on in the in-laws car. We found nothing that would explain the light... Kicking the tyres did the trick thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tende is a picturesque town, that has houses perched on top of one another, we found a supermarket on the main drag, which was conveniently located next to a souvenir shop followed by a cafe. After getting supplies we made a pitch at the cafe for a light refreshment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-12071.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Tende town centre&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We managed to get diesel just south of Tende, while filling up we met a local driving an old Toyota Land Cruiser, 80 series I think, who we got chatting to about the tracks on the surrounding mountains. He gave us the low down and a few decent pointers including telling us about some closures due to land slides etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armed with this new info we headed back towards Tende, where we planned to pick up the road Chemin Des Spegi towards Gite d&amp;#039;Etape which we entered through some sleepy back streets of the town, we then planned to continue up to eventually camp near or at Fort de la Marguerie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13361.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Colla Megiana&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assent to Gite d&amp;#039;Etape was slow it took about an hour to get to the top, most of the corners required at least a three point turn, in a 110 Defender. There seemed to be a never ending flow of hair pin bends. Chemin Des Spegi eventually turns into Chemin Muletier Des Spegi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roads up the mountain are gravel, which is a welcome change after about a thousand miles on Tarmac since leaving the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surroundings are initially sparse coniferous forest and dry grey rock. The forest eventually gives way to open rocky, green vast land scapes. Occasionally the roads are fringed by sections of granite wall, some with vast sheer drops. It is very easy to imagine military vehicles on the roads. Meeting one on the assent would certainly make for an interesting manuvoure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way up we noticed that the in-laws car was starting to over heat and loose a bit of coolant from the expansion tank. It appeared the low range work and slow speeds were not allowing the engine to keep cool, we noticed that the car was missing it&amp;#039;s thermostat. This it would seem, was a good time to have lunch, we managed to find a spot were we could put the cars into the wind, top up the coolant and have a nice shady lunch, near the turning for Colla Megiana. After the break we never did see the temperature of the Pajero rise again. Apart from the missing thermostat I wonder if there was an airlock or something in the system after the major service and the radiator flush we had just before departing on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-13311.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Recovery Time&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;232&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued after lunch towards the fort along Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino. We had originally planned to do a longer route to the fort, but during the day we lost a fair amount of time. With time now cracking on and it being after three we decided to go for the shorter option, so at Baisse de Peyrafique we kept to the right. We had originally planned to go left and do a loop via Mount Paracouerta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16121.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping to the shorter route kept us on Route Stratégique Du Col de L&amp;#039;agnéllino, this took us along spectacular gravel road all the way to our camp at the Fort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the Fort to find another nice Landy from Germany pearched just where I had planned to camp, with the view you could hardly blame them. I had a look there was still room for us, so decided to ask if they would mind us joining them. They were fine with that, I guess they had no choice really, but I asked anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-16331.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;View from Camp&#34; width=&#34;534&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17081.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Camping spot next to the Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually felt sorry for them, it was very pieceful before we arrived, at least we could not destroy there view!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We manoeuvred the vehicles in to position then, set our selves up for the night. It was still light enought to allow us to go and explore the fort. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from the UK it was surprising that we were able to roam freely in the fort. It is clear that some do not respect the fort as much as we did, there was plenty of graphitti and rubbish inside the fort. We spent about an hour looking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17111.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Is it spooky?&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Proud of her self!&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17231.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Room 44&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-1733.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;On top of the fort&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17431.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;From the draw bridge to the court yard&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-17391.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;The draw bridge&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-18021.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our camp site&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from the camp was super. Stretching towards the Italian border and Fort Central, we could also see Tende far below and Fort Tabourde and Fort Pepin in the distance, giving an appetiser for what would be comming in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner we had a simple vegetable pasta, lots of beer and kept warm as the sun disappeared over the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-1-aug-2012-19131.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Simple dinner&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the binoculars we were able to spy on the sheep and a lone hand gliding camper at Fort Central.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to take an early night, but... At about 2300 we were woken by a load rusling and a bit of a commotion, we had made a &#34;school-boy&#34; error. We left the rubbish out in a black bag. This of course had been found by a fox who seemed a bit brave for the wild. Needless to say, our rubbish was everywhere and I was running round in my boxers chasing the rubbish and the fox! Half way down a mountain freezing in boxers is something I will always remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are on the subject of rubbish. I personally found it really appalling that the land scape was scarred  with toilet paper and other rubbish. If you take a dump, take the paper with you and be considerate where you dump. As they say take only photos and leave nothing but a foot print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow once we had delt with the rubbish and the fox, if was off to sleep for a pleasant but cold night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0956.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Central&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke to a spectacular view. After breakfast and coffee, we packed up and headed towards fort central. It was surprising again for us to be able to look around. We spent about an hour scouting around and then explored the track towards Fort Pepin. We found that the track was closed due to a land slide, apparently the local authorities do not have the budget to restore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After coming to a dead end we headed down to Tende via another thousand hair pin bends, where we used the local pool for a shower and a very pleasant swim. We also got a few more supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0940.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Sentry Post&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-0959.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#039;s here&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1009.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Walls&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1029.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking back to The fort&#34; width=&#34;453&#34; height=&#34;339&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1026.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Gun points&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;667&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1014.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Inner buildings&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1022.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Looking up from a lower floor&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-2-aug-2012-1041.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Driving through&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I have uploaded the GPS track, if you would like to get a copy please click &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B3lq5J_TSkjFMk5wUW92VzhIaWs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;GPS Track&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chez Wardie &amp; Lancie - St Jean D&#39;Aulps</title>
      <link>/2012/07/30/chez-wardie-lancie-st-jean-daulps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 19:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/30/chez-wardie-lancie-st-jean-daulps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; We took the mountain roads to St Jean D&amp;#039;Aulps. We had informed Anna that we were coming, but due to the incident in Paris, we were early by a day. We decided to stop in Taninges for lunch before arriving at there&amp;#039;s late afternoon. We had a lovely pizza in a sleepy pizzeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7862343290_daa6316b71_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone&#34; alt=&#34;View from bridge in Taninges&#34; width=&#34;217&#34; height=&#34;290&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, we had a warm welcome from Anna and Lance. It&amp;#039;s been awhile since we have managed to get together so it was good to see them again. They had friends staying, so Carole and Daniel were given the other spare room and Cassie, Dan and I slept in the roof tent out in the garden. The guys had a great time chatting all things technical as Dan set the tent up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7862351588_bd1795dfc0.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Tent set up&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had gone to the supermarket on the way to Anna and Lance&amp;#039;s and gotten bits and pieces for dinner. We&amp;#039;d decided to fire up the Braai. Anna had outdone herself this year and had a magnificent veggie patch. Cassie and her raided the veggies to make us an assortment of fabulous salads to accompany our dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7862347748_f4fef7fa68_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Anna &amp;amp; Cassie with their veg patch spoils&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day we decided to go into Les Gets to take the cable car up to Mont Cheri and then the chair lift to the very top. Carole is not good with heights, so she decided to stay at the bottom and wait for us. We bought our tickets and made our way to the cable car, bidding Carole a farewell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cable car journey up was uneventful, we sat and watched mountain bikers come down the mountain and Daniel recorded the journey up on his video camera. From there we hopped onto the chair lift. I was a tad nervous as I&amp;#039;ve never been on a chair lift before. It was a white knuckle experience for me. About a 3rd of the way up, Daniel went to put the strap of his camera case over his head and knocked his glasses off...we watched them slowly fall to the ground under the chair lift. Silly Billy! We&amp;#039;d have to go back and look for them on the way down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7862371672_8a9e03015d.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;White knuckles!&#34; width=&#34;382&#34; height=&#34;286&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from the top was magnificent. We took our touristy, scenic photos and then decided to walk down, instead of catching the chair lift down. The walk down was beautiful and we found some carvings made out of tree stumps, all of elves/gnomes. Daniel walked down on a mission, leaving us in his dust, he was on a mission to go and try find his glasses. As the rest of us got back to the bottom, Dan went off to help Daniel find his glasses. Cassie and I went and had a nice cold drink, whilst we sat and watched the 2 Dans look for the sunglasses. Dan suddenly shouted jubilantly, he had found them!! Meanwhile Daniel was almost at the top looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7862372918_ec7903e4ae_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;What a view&#34; width=&#34;356&#34; height=&#34;475&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down we went to find Carole and go back to Anna and Lance&amp;#039;s. We had also been advised to go to Lac Montriond where there was a beach where Cassie could go for a paddle. The ladies spent a lovely day down at the lake paddling and reading, whilst the 2 Dans spent the afternoon fishing. They managed to catch a few tiddlers, nothing of an eatable size. Never the less, they had a good afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We retired back to Chez Anna to have another lovely meal round the table of braaied lamb and fresh veggie patch salads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bade a fond farewell to our lovely hosts, we were heading off into Italy for some offloading adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2012: Calais to St Jean D&#39;Aulps - Leg 1</title>
      <link>/2012/07/29/summer-2012-calais-to-st-jean-daulps-leg-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 15:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/29/summer-2012-calais-to-st-jean-daulps-leg-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; Dan woke on our departure morning with unusual pre-trip nerves. We packed the vehicles and headed for a pre journey tea and cake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our European journey started out with us managing to get onto the Chunnel earlier than expected. The excitement was building, with boarding looming for what we hoped would be another Summer Adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/7862486536_94dd931b1d.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;405&#34; height=&#34;304&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first night was uneventful, having booked ourselves into the Formula 1 (motel) at Abbeville. We pulled in, checked in and found a restaurant just a hop and a skip down the road. Had a pleasant first meal. Formula 1&amp;#039;s are basic: simple room, separate showers + an ok nights sleep. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were abruptly woken early the next morning by some snotty, screaming children running up and down the hallways...not happy! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made an early start, we are now heading for Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we arrived at the Premiere Class (similar to the Formula 1) we were booked into, we decided to check in and then take the lift to go and check out our rooms before heading off for some food. Our rooms were on the 3rd floor and as the lift came to the 3rd floor, it stopped! The lift would not go up or down or open the doors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 6 adults and Cassie in the lift, and it was HOT, HOT, HOT! We had little air circulation and four 50 watt halogen bulbs burning down on us. Clearly it was going to get hotter. Dan made the decision to remove all but one of the bulbs, to minimise the heat build up. Being so hot already and not wanting to burn himself he removed his soaking shirt to handle the bulbs. In the end we were stuck in the lift for over 45mins. Cassie had to sit on the cramp floor to avoid fainting. She also started to have a mild panic attack, we had to quickly calm her down. We were all dripping after 10 minutes. If it had not been for a French speaking man in the lift with us, that had his mobile phone with him, we probably would have been stuck in that lift for a LOT longer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staff at the hotel simply did nothing about us being stuck in the lift, choosing to stay in reception instead, despite the knowledge we were stuck with an infant, no one from the hotel staff attended to provide assurance they were aware of our problem or that someone would attend imminently. We had to call the maintenance company ourselves and then the fire brigade to chivvy them along. Eventually we were set free. We were now rather hot, angry and irrational. We headed downstairs to speak to the receptionist to get a refund and leave. To put it bluntly, the receptionist simply did not give a damn. As he said to us &#34;it is not a problem, only a small one&#34;. We were told that we had to wait till 15.00hrs for the Manager before anything could be sorted out....so outside to the car we went to sit and wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Manager arrived and we went in to speak to her about a refund. The conversation got a little heated and the Manager decided it would be better if the police were around, so called the Gendamerie. So we waited for the Police to arrive, during the wait the Manager would not talk calmly to us to sort the matter out. Another hotel Manager had since arrived, she kindly translated and spoke to the Manager for us. She agreed with us and our situation and seemed appalled that the Manager would not listen or give a refund. The Police arrived, they spoke to the Manager and then called Dan into another room to speak to him, and simply agreed with Dan that the Manager was out of order, and allowed us to go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Police arrived, the manager was suddenly cooperative and listened to what we had to say. Her argument was that there we&amp;#039;re too many people in the lift. We argued that we had called the fire brigade for help as her receptionist would not help, and there would be a recorded call with the operator that said we had 6 adults and 1 child in the lift. Anyway, after a long, heated debate, we decided to cut our losses and leave Paris, head to St Jean D&amp;#039;Aulps, to Dan&amp;#039;s sister and brother in law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a campsite on the outskirts of Paris, a Euro Disney visitors campsite it would appear, and stayed 1 night. The campsite scored Cassie points as it had a swimming pool. Short stay, with no more events to be noted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day we broke camp a little to late. We drove as far a Dijon and managed to find a campsite in Dijon. We managed our first shopping trip and had a lovely Braai of spatch-cock chicken and potatoes. Did some clothes washing and sorted out our travel plans to get to Anna and Lance the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another late break from camp, hopefully we will get better at this as we go on. Looking forward to a break from driving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 27: THURSDAY 25 AUGUST 2011 Villey le Sec (France) – Hove (England)</title>
      <link>/2011/08/27/day-27-thursday-25-august-2011-villey-le-sec-france-hove-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/27/day-27-thursday-25-august-2011-villey-le-sec-france-hove-england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We woke up in the pouring rain! We decided to pack up and see how the weather goes as we drive. Needless to say, that it did not clear up rain, rain, rain. We stopped just outside reims to get some food from the supermarket. We made the decision that as we were only 200km (give or take), so we decided to just carry on all the way to Calais.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We arrived at 15.45hrs and were told we could board at 17.45hrs. We had 2 hours to kill. We wondered around the port for a bit, then got a coffee from the vending machine. Above the vending machine was a sign for a restaurant on the 2nd floor of the port building. We decided to go and find it. We wondered across but failed to gain access as we needed our ticket and passports. Dan decided to go and fetch them whilst Cassie and I waited. When we found the restaurant, we had some explosively expensive drinks and sat and whiled away time. We got to the car to load onto the ferry. Once on the ferry, we had a small snack to keep us going. Finally back in the UK…back to grey, cloudy, dreary UK. We made it home at 20.30hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The end to the 2011 Summer Adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 25/26: 23/24 AUGUST 2011  Altkirch (France) – Villey le Sec (France)</title>
      <link>/2011/08/25/day-2526-2324-august-2011-altkirch-france-villey-le-sec-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 17:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/25/day-2526-2324-august-2011-altkirch-france-villey-le-sec-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Camping de Villey le Sec €44.60 + electricity – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A little late rising, but not an issue as we had packed things up the night before. In the morning, tents packed up and off we went back to the supermarket to get a map so we could navigate back to Calais. Map bought, and off we went, in the right direction. We drove to Nancy and decided that we’d pull over and look for a supermarket for food and then a campsite. After our supermarket trip, we saw signs to a campsite and so we decided to follow them. The campsite was ok, so we decided to stay for 2 nights. We put up the tents, awning and had lunch. Dinner that night was simple, sausages, rolls, gherkins and mustard. As we cleaned up after dinner and put Cas to bed, we heard thunder rolling in, luckily Cas was asleep. The heavens opened up and it absolutely bucketed down! As the night wore on, the thunder got worse and such Cassie woke up. She ended up in our tent again for the night. To say that we got no sleep would be an understatement. The storm did not relent, it just got worse. The rain got heavier, and as we were camped between a river and a lake, we thought that with both rising we might actually wash away. At one point, the thunder was so loud, it scared the living daylights out of us. From the outside, the tent must have jumped off the ground with our fright! The tent held up despite the immense amount and heaviness of the rain, it did not leak once! Morning arrived and Cassie happened to be the only one out of us 3 that had managed to actually get a good nights sleep! The day seemed cloudy, but dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9648.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 26: WEDNESDAY 24 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Tired and worn from the previous nights storm and restless sleep, we got up and had breakfast followed by 2 coffees! We simply lazed around. Cassie took some bread from todays baguette and went to feed the ducks. Cassie and Dan then played Mario Bros. on her Nintendo DS… Dan got carried away and had to get to the point where you could actually save your game. After a stroll around the camp, Cassie started chatting to 2 English girls and so Dan and I got chatting to their parents. We shared holiday routes and jourmney lengths etc. They were travelling in a bongo and so Dan had a look out of interest for Carole and Daniel (Wendy’s Biological Parents who would be visiting us next Summer). The family were leaving that afternoon, and after a nice long chat we decided to let them pack up whilst we went back to the tent for lunch. The sky looked ominous, so we decided to string our tarp up over the tents. We then decided to take Cassie’s tent down, put her in our tent again, so that if it did rain again we’d only have 1 tent to take down in the rain. As we moved the tent under the tarp and got it semi to our desired set up, the heavens opened. We were thankful we’d put the tarp up and ate our lunch under the awning and tarp in dryness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As quickly as the heavens had opened, they cleared up and the sun showed it’s face again. We all moved our chairs out into the sunshine and sat reading and playing games. We idled the day away, playing with Cas in the park, playing music, Dan taught Cassie knots and before we knew it, dinner time was upon us. A simple dinner of steak and salad which Dan made whilst Cassie and Wendy played in the park. Dinner over and dishes washed, Cassie showered, it was bedtime. Now the skies were clear and blue, Murphy’s law, take precaustions and what you plan for never happens. Better to be prepared though. Time to move on again tomorrow, heading for Reims. We will try to get 200km covered so we are near enough to calais for the ferry and last stop. The eeking out of the last days of holiday. Lets hope they stay sunny!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9655.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9656.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9676.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 23/24: 21/22 AUGUST 2011  Forno di Zaldo (Italy) – Altkirch (France)</title>
      <link>/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 17:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Les Acaises €32 – 2 nights incl. electricity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were up late, but still managed to pack up and leave in good time! It was a long drive today. We managed to find a garage for diesel and luckily some better maps. We started our navigation out of Italy, through Austria, into Switzerland and finally…just through the border into France. Once in France we decided to stop for dinner as it was very late, then go and find a campsite. After a nice pizza and salad, we went in search for a campsite…what a search that was. After driving and driving we finally found signs to a campsite! We were saved! This was the latest we had ever left it to find a camp – 21.00hrs! We set up tents, had showers and put Cassie to sleep. We would spend 2 nights here so we could relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9639.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9636.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9646.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAY 24: MONDAY 22 AUGUST 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke up at leisure today. Wendy washed some more clothes and then we went in search of a supermarket. We didn’t have anything for breakfast, so stopped off and bought some croissants along the way. After wondering through town, we hadn’t found a supermarket, so we sat and had a coffee. We had also seen signs for a swimming pool, but couldn’t see find it anywhere. Dan asked a man if there was a supermarket and he gave us directions. We did minimal shopping as we had to carry it all the way back again, and it was a trek back to the campsite. Back at the campsite, we decided to hop into the car and go in search of the swimming pool… unfortunately we did not find it. Back at the campsite, Dan and Cassie went to the bar to use the internet. The couple that run the campsite have 2 children and they connected a hosepipe to a tap and started running in the spray. Cassie went and joined in. After a good run around, Cassie and the daughter came back to our camp to watch Lady and the Tramp. Dan did a few housekeeping bits to the Landy whilst Wendy baked in the sun. After awhile, Cassie went back to join the fun in the hosepipe, and Dan and Wendy joined them too. That evening we went up to the bar and partook in a couple of beers and iced tea for Cassie. After putting Cassie to bed sudden rain came down. It wasn’t hard, but strange as there were no clouds about to warn of rain. Dan and Wendy went to bed with Thunder and lightening. It didn’t last long, thankfully, as we dreaded the thought of having to pack wet tents in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 1: SATURDAY 30 JULY 2011, Laon (France) – Anould (France)</title>
      <link>/2011/07/31/day-1-saturday-30-july-2011-laon-france-anould-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 17:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/31/day-1-saturday-30-july-2011-laon-france-anould-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Lѐs Acacias €13.90 – 1 night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We thought we’d do a long one today and head for Interlaken, try to get a day ahead. Our start wasn’t brilliant, wrong input into the GPS and after 45min of driving, we realised we were heading back along the way we drove yesterday! After stopping and re-jigging the GPS, lovingly named Hannah (Hannah Montanna, get it?!), we were back on track. But we did have to go back the way we had just come, again! This time we noticed a police car trapping, a few cars had been flashing us and now it fell into place as to why. Dan flashed a few cars to warn them, and one of the cars he flashed happened to be a police car! We all found this hilarious and had a good giggle for a few minutes. As lunch drew nearer we looked for a nice picnic spot, but couldn’t find one. Town after town went by and we couldn’t find a decent place to stop and eat. A turning that Hannah wanted us to take was closed, so we followed the recalculated route that came up on the GPS. This took us to a gravel track going into a forest. I had spotted a few parking spaces down the road and suggested we park there, have lunch and reassess how to get out of this town. The parking spaces overlooked a lovely, peaceful cemetery. Lunch with a view.We managed to navigate ourselves out of town, and were now making headway. Unfortunately the GPS said that our ETA was 19.00hrs! After a few more hours driving, we decided to stop and camp for the night. Interlaken would have to wait till tomorrow. We found a supermarket to get supplies for dinner and went in search for the nearest campsite.To Cassie’s delight, the campsite had a swimming pool AND she made a friend, someone to swim with. A lovely braai for dinner along with some local beer and wine. Ready for a nice short journey tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF8198.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF8215.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF8219.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>