<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Italy on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/categories/italy/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Italy on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/categories/italy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 21 to 24 - B&amp;B, Marina di Ginosa, Cassino to Marina di Massa</title>
      <link>/2013/08/19/day-21-to-24-bb-marina-di-ginosa-cassino-to-marina-di-massa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 07:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/19/day-21-to-24-bb-marina-di-ginosa-cassino-to-marina-di-massa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The south of Italy was not what we expected. Saying that, exactly what we expected is hard to put into words. But packed, sardine campsites, and undesirable beaches was certainly not it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was to get in a little more beach time before we started heading northwards and ultimately towards home. So with this in mind, we continued on down the coast of South Italy in the Puglia area. The map showed plenty of camping and after our usual stint of driving, we pulled off the motorway at Marina di Ginosa. We saw the campsite sign and followed it .. what we pulled up to was a sight that had a 90% majority of motor homes and static caravans. We have turned up in Italy at the completely wrong time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my last post, it was Italy&#39;s national holiday and therefore every Mario, Luigi and his mother were on holiday for 2 weeks. From 10 August till 18 August all factories etc close down and Italy retreats … it seemed to this campsite or part of the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We paid for 1 night, thinking if we liked it we would stay for 2, but that changed very quickly after we went to the beach. Lets just say peacocks have nothing on Italian men and their speedos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Marina di Ginosa we headed up the motorway past Rome. We did a big stint of driving, we simply wanted to get out of Italy. We had no maps for this part of Italy and were now relying on our very old and very worn Europe map for a general motorway overview. Every services we stopped at did not have maps, it was getting very frustrating! We pulled off the motorway at Caserta to look for a campsite. After an hour of driving, nerves and tempers were fraying and we all just wanted to get out of the car and stop. I suggested we head for a big town and go from there. We ended up in Cassino and found a campsite sign. The campsite was strange … an old lady and, i assume, her grand children were sitting at the entrance. The lady greeted us and chatted away in Italian, I assume telling us to go choose a pitch and she&#39;ll bring us our passports. The place was deserted! To say it felt like the twilight zone or something from the movie The Shining would be a good ways to describing the feel of the place. We were THE ONLY people there. We pitched, cooked dinner and quickly went to bed … avoiding ALL contact with the ablutions … eewww!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day we headed Florence direction. The day dawned with Cas needing a wee. As age descended the ladder we heard a &#34;Bonjourno!&#34; from a strange Italian man walking through the campsite … that was our queue to leave. Anoter long day driving, as we passed Florence I asked the team if they&#39;d like to stay in Florence or carry on to the coast, which would mean another 2 hours or so in the car. Cassie opted for the coast, Dan didn&#39;t mind and so the coast it was. We pulled off the motorway at Lido di Camaiore, the map showed lots of camping and we were bound to find something quickly. This was not the case, after about 30min of driving we finally came across a campsite. we pulled in and enquired about a space, no sorry, full! Another 10 attempts later and we still had nowhere to stay. It was getting late again and we were getting tetchy. One last attempt, thank goodness! They had space. The campsite was another of these static caravan and permanent pitch sights. Not to our taste to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Packed Free beach&#34; src=&#34;/assets/dscf0319.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed to the beach to check it out, but what a disappointment. A false bay had been created using boulders. This stopped the sea coming in and out and delivering fresh water from the tide … meaning the water was frothy and dirty. The beaches were also all privatised and the &#39;free&#39; beaches were tiny strips packed with every Mario, Luigi and Poalo. Not fun. Despite this, we decided to stay two nights and to find a swimming pool tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a pool and for €4 each, we had a lovely quiet afternoon by the pool. Quiet yes, but the visions we were treated to were something I don&#39;t think I will ever forget and is my major memory of Italy - the men walking around in their speedos. Or budgie smugglers as Dan and I nicknamed them. Why!? That is my only question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Cassie enjoying the delights of the much quieter swimming pool.&#34; src=&#34;/assets/dscf0338.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale</title>
      <link>/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 09:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastlane99.plus.com/&#34;&gt;Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just found this link via a reply to a &lt;a title=&#34;HUBB&#34; href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/europe/familly-friendly-4x4-tours-alps-70380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post on Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;. If your looking at exploring the tracks of the Alps. There some nice pictures on here from the early 2000&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Jafferau and Lago Di Rochemolles</title>
      <link>/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1220.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125197.9639&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track Up To Fort Jafferau &#34; width=&#34;417&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After spending the night at &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/&#34;&gt;Fort Pramond&lt;/a&gt;, we had a plan today to driver up to Mount Jafferau then on to a nearby Lake that is now a reservoir, we were hoping to spend the night by the river there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to pack up fairly promptly and were on the way by the time the day was heating up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-0911.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125203.729&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Exit of the exciting tunnel&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was kind of excited about the day, because we were heading along a track that showed a cool tunnel on the map. I dunno how I came to that conclusion,  just by looking at the map. The tunnel on the track is circa 800 meters long, unlit, unpaved and leaks more than you would see in a normal road tunnel as it is not lined. This leak leads to a stream of water in the tunnel that is often a few inches deep. Oh and the end never seemed to appear, leading to a further sense of excitement under the dim light of the Landys head lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1213.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125156.5093&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Jafferau&#34; width=&#34;358&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The other thing about the day that excited me was the climb to the Fort on Mount Jafferau, this sits at circa 2800 meters and promises spectacular views. We were not let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Most of the track up to Jafferau is easy in a 4 x 4, I am not sure how far you&amp;#039;d want to go in a ordinary car. There are some fairly rocky sections, not hard but difficult in most cars. If the weather was bad, you would not consider it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the way up to Mount Jafferau, we were listening on the CB to other people that we could not see. We could hear that they were watching us, as they were mentioning the English vehicles. Even with the aid of the binoculars we could not see who was watching us and nor could we find them. It was rather creepy being in a valley, with all the ex military sites and the creepy night we had the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The track we were following stopped at Jafferau... Sort of. We had a plan to asses the situation at the end. This was because we had a map that showed a 500 meter foot path then the start of a new track down the other side of Mount Jafferau. Well when we got there we found that there was a track down, that was fairly steep and circa 1000m descent. Linking the track up and the track down was actually the easy bit. We did the whole descent in low range 1st gear, but had to occasionally slow the descent a little on top. It was great because we were following the Ski run literally, so naturally this led to us arriving at the top of the bubble lift and at the restaurant at the top of the lift. A convenient place to stop for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1311.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125181.358&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Nice Lunch Stop&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel had a double helping of home made Lasagne, made by the Owners Wife and Wendy and I had a local platter of meats and cheeses. After a good fill. We carried on our descent, we had about another thousand meters to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed down towards Bardonecchia to pick up the track to take us up to the Lake for the next night. Unfortunately we found the/a track but could not find our way onto the one we wanted that led to the lake. We ended up back tracking and taking a scenic road that met up with the track we needed. The track was really easy and fairly pleasant if busy. You could have done this section in a car. Apart from going to the actual camping spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1546.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125152.4119&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Valley of Lago di Rochemolles &#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;107&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The road continues on from where we camped to one of the highest glaciers you can drive to in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1702.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125163.2832&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Refreshing Bath&#34; width=&#34;341&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We stopped for the evening at the river that feeds Lago di Rochemolles, it was obviously icy cold, but was great for a very invigorating bath and cooling some Prosecco. The valley was very scenic and a great stop for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1704.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125195.692&#34; class=&#34;alignnone&#34; alt=&#34;Cutting Wood&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;263&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we had a proper fire in a pit made by some predecessors, we managed to find enough wood nearby and an old sauce pan to warm water for washing up. Dinner that night was slightly left field. We had failed to stop for more supplies since our last supermarket stop, we had some powdered soup from Croatia. This was very nice, I think it was called Dalmation soup.... We also had three military ration packs, which had been given to us by John in Cinque terra. Our plan was to enjoy these as pudding after we had the roast potatoes. Unfortunately being military ration novices what we cooked for pudding was awful. I feel for the boys who eat them, this looked off. So we ended up going to bed a bit hungry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Update: I have since learnt that the packs last for 10 years. Sorry John. If you are reading this John, we lost your email address, hope you had a cool trip. It was great having a BBQ with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-2043.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125179.4502&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Girls Washing up.&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;233&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping by a stream led to a lot of night time pees. In the morning we woke stinking of smoke. Had breakfast and headed for the road. It was here, well in Bardonecchia we would say bye for a few days to Carole and Daniel. Obviously we did this over coffee and pastries. They were heading to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-17021.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125165.5713&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our Spot&#34; width=&#34;363&#34; height=&#34;272&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We from hear ambled our way via a few one night stops home, as usual once we got half way up France the heavens opened and we just headed back to the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 23/24: 21/22 AUGUST 2011  Forno di Zaldo (Italy) – Altkirch (France)</title>
      <link>/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 17:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/23/day-2324-2122-august-2011-forno-di-zaldo-italy-altkirch-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Les Acaises €32 – 2 nights incl. electricity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were up late, but still managed to pack up and leave in good time! It was a long drive today. We managed to find a garage for diesel and luckily some better maps. We started our navigation out of Italy, through Austria, into Switzerland and finally…just through the border into France. Once in France we decided to stop for dinner as it was very late, then go and find a campsite. After a nice pizza and salad, we went in search for a campsite…what a search that was. After driving and driving we finally found signs to a campsite! We were saved! This was the latest we had ever left it to find a camp – 21.00hrs! We set up tents, had showers and put Cassie to sleep. We would spend 2 nights here so we could relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9639.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9636.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9646.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAY 24: MONDAY 22 AUGUST 2011&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke up at leisure today. Wendy washed some more clothes and then we went in search of a supermarket. We didn’t have anything for breakfast, so stopped off and bought some croissants along the way. After wondering through town, we hadn’t found a supermarket, so we sat and had a coffee. We had also seen signs for a swimming pool, but couldn’t see find it anywhere. Dan asked a man if there was a supermarket and he gave us directions. We did minimal shopping as we had to carry it all the way back again, and it was a trek back to the campsite. Back at the campsite, we decided to hop into the car and go in search of the swimming pool… unfortunately we did not find it. Back at the campsite, Dan and Cassie went to the bar to use the internet. The couple that run the campsite have 2 children and they connected a hosepipe to a tap and started running in the spray. Cassie went and joined in. After a good run around, Cassie and the daughter came back to our camp to watch Lady and the Tramp. Dan did a few housekeeping bits to the Landy whilst Wendy baked in the sun. After awhile, Cassie went back to join the fun in the hosepipe, and Dan and Wendy joined them too. That evening we went up to the bar and partook in a couple of beers and iced tea for Cassie. After putting Cassie to bed sudden rain came down. It wasn’t hard, but strange as there were no clouds about to warn of rain. Dan and Wendy went to bed with Thunder and lightening. It didn’t last long, thankfully, as we dreaded the thought of having to pack wet tents in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 22: SATURDAY 20 AUGUST 2011 Plitvička Jezera (Croatia) – Forno di Zaldo (Italy)</title>
      <link>/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 17:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/21/day-22-saturday-20-august-2011-plitvicka-jezera-croatia-forno-di-zaldo-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Camping Al Pez €26.80 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We were up, packed up and gone by 8.30hr! We had decided to miss out Venice as most of the campsites wanted a weeks booking, we only wanted to stay for 2 nights. Instead we were going to head for Northern italy, then using our already purchased Swiss Vignette to bomb through Switzerland and straight through France, using the fast motorways. We didn’t want to get stuck in expensive Austria or Switzerland again. Unfortunately we only had a large map of Italy to guide us. A day driving on toll roads, and as we left Croatia, we got stuck in a queu of Italian cars that were also leaving Croatia. We headed into Italy navigated by Wendy and maps. Needless to say, we took an incorrect exit and ended up in a horrendous traffic jam! Once through it, we found our way back onto the correct course. We finally beat all the traffic and navigational errors and found camping in a small mountain town. It was a no car next to tent camp, but the man let us camp in a field next to a motorhome. We noticed toilet paper in the spot we had to put our tent, so we decided to stay only one night. We put up our tent and then went in search of a beer. After being told that there wasn’t a bar, we wondered around and just happened upon a bar! We treated ourselves to an Italian beer. A pasta dinner and an early dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9577.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9578.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/assets/DSCF9580.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>