<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storm on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/storm/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storm on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/storm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 - Westerheim to Ramsau am Dachstein</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/30/day-4-westerheim-to-ramsau-am-dachstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 19:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/30/day-4-westerheim-to-ramsau-am-dachstein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We woke to pouring rain again, the flavour of the trip so far. We decided to simply pack up and move on. Dan and Cassie went to get breakfast from the camp shop. Croissants and Coffee to go.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another day of driving it was to be. We headed out and decided to make it all the way to Austria. Again it was to be a day of clouds and rain. As we decided to stop, Cassie chose the camp off the GPS and we headed in that direction. Unfortunately two things happened…the camp was full and the GPS decided to fail on us. We could not get it to start again and so just drove until we saw a sign for camping and stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/p1130436.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again they were full, but gave us a spot at the top in the car park of the Pension/House. Grey skies loomed and so we battened down the hatches, expecting the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camp/pension grill was where we decided to have dinner, but the old guy that ran the place decided that it wasn&#39;t good enough to open with just a few people and closed for the night. We made our own concoction for dinner of potatoes, bacon and onions alongside scrambled eggs. We fondly named this &#34;Bubble and Peep&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then headed off to bed in anticipation of another stormy night with interrupted sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>