<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Military on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/military/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Military on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/military/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful maps for exploring the Maritime Alps</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; If your planning on exploring the tracks around the Maritime Alps on the French / Italian border, you&amp;#039;ll need a few maps of the area. The best single retailer for maps in the UK is Stanford maps in London. They have three floors of travel books and maps. This is where I got our maps months prior to departing. Of course you can try online also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#039;t have to buy the maps before you leave, they are sold locally in France. You will need something with some detail though, equivalent to the UK Ordnance Survey (OS) map, which is 1:25k or 1:50k depending on the series you go for. In France the equivalent is the Institut Geographique National (IGN) they do a 1:25k map series which covers the whole of France. Where ever you go in France you can normally by IGN maps of the local area. So you could buy on arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the IGN maps, we also used the Italian equivalent as we found the IGN maps loose detail on shortly after the border. These maps are Istituto Geografico Centrale (IGC). At Stanfords they had these in 1:50k. They have a slightly vintage feel in the style of printing, but they are very clear. Interestingly they also show prohibited routes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I should also mention is that Garmin maps have a lot of the tracks we used, well certainly in the European City Navigator 2012. Not all though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1320.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Here are some pictures of the maps we used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 8 Alpi Marittime E Liguri (ISBN 9788896455081)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 1 Valli Di Susi Chisone E Germanasca (ISBN 9788896455012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3841 OT Vallée De La Roya, Vallée Des Merveilles, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 3282113841030)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3741 ET Vallées De La Bévéra Et Des Paillons, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 9782758524083)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1319.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-2129.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And in case you are interested the back of the first one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-13191.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mount Jafferau and Lago Di Rochemolles</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 07:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/24/mount-jafferau-and-lago-di-rochemolles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1220.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125197.9639&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Track Up To Fort Jafferau &#34; width=&#34;417&#34; height=&#34;313&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After spending the night at &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/&#34;&gt;Fort Pramond&lt;/a&gt;, we had a plan today to driver up to Mount Jafferau then on to a nearby Lake that is now a reservoir, we were hoping to spend the night by the river there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We managed to pack up fairly promptly and were on the way by the time the day was heating up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-0911.jpg&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125203.729&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Exit of the exciting tunnel&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was kind of excited about the day, because we were heading along a track that showed a cool tunnel on the map. I dunno how I came to that conclusion,  just by looking at the map. The tunnel on the track is circa 800 meters long, unlit, unpaved and leaks more than you would see in a normal road tunnel as it is not lined. This leak leads to a stream of water in the tunnel that is often a few inches deep. Oh and the end never seemed to appear, leading to a further sense of excitement under the dim light of the Landys head lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1213.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125156.5093&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Jafferau&#34; width=&#34;358&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The other thing about the day that excited me was the climb to the Fort on Mount Jafferau, this sits at circa 2800 meters and promises spectacular views. We were not let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Most of the track up to Jafferau is easy in a 4 x 4, I am not sure how far you&amp;#039;d want to go in a ordinary car. There are some fairly rocky sections, not hard but difficult in most cars. If the weather was bad, you would not consider it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the way up to Mount Jafferau, we were listening on the CB to other people that we could not see. We could hear that they were watching us, as they were mentioning the English vehicles. Even with the aid of the binoculars we could not see who was watching us and nor could we find them. It was rather creepy being in a valley, with all the ex military sites and the creepy night we had the night before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The track we were following stopped at Jafferau... Sort of. We had a plan to asses the situation at the end. This was because we had a map that showed a 500 meter foot path then the start of a new track down the other side of Mount Jafferau. Well when we got there we found that there was a track down, that was fairly steep and circa 1000m descent. Linking the track up and the track down was actually the easy bit. We did the whole descent in low range 1st gear, but had to occasionally slow the descent a little on top. It was great because we were following the Ski run literally, so naturally this led to us arriving at the top of the bubble lift and at the restaurant at the top of the lift. A convenient place to stop for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1311.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125181.358&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Nice Lunch Stop&#34; width=&#34;368&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel had a double helping of home made Lasagne, made by the Owners Wife and Wendy and I had a local platter of meats and cheeses. After a good fill. We carried on our descent, we had about another thousand meters to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We headed down towards Bardonecchia to pick up the track to take us up to the Lake for the next night. Unfortunately we found the/a track but could not find our way onto the one we wanted that led to the lake. We ended up back tracking and taking a scenic road that met up with the track we needed. The track was really easy and fairly pleasant if busy. You could have done this section in a car. Apart from going to the actual camping spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1546.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125152.4119&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Valley of Lago di Rochemolles &#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;107&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The road continues on from where we camped to one of the highest glaciers you can drive to in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1702.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125163.2832&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Refreshing Bath&#34; width=&#34;341&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We stopped for the evening at the river that feeds Lago di Rochemolles, it was obviously icy cold, but was great for a very invigorating bath and cooling some Prosecco. The valley was very scenic and a great stop for the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-1704.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125195.692&#34; class=&#34;alignnone&#34; alt=&#34;Cutting Wood&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;263&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;That night we had a proper fire in a pit made by some predecessors, we managed to find enough wood nearby and an old sauce pan to warm water for washing up. Dinner that night was slightly left field. We had failed to stop for more supplies since our last supermarket stop, we had some powdered soup from Croatia. This was very nice, I think it was called Dalmation soup.... We also had three military ration packs, which had been given to us by John in Cinque terra. Our plan was to enjoy these as pudding after we had the roast potatoes. Unfortunately being military ration novices what we cooked for pudding was awful. I feel for the boys who eat them, this looked off. So we ended up going to bed a bit hungry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Update: I have since learnt that the packs last for 10 years. Sorry John. If you are reading this John, we lost your email address, hope you had a cool trip. It was great having a BBQ with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-2043.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125179.4502&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Girls Washing up.&#34; width=&#34;310&#34; height=&#34;233&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping by a stream led to a lot of night time pees. In the morning we woke stinking of smoke. Had breakfast and headed for the road. It was here, well in Bardonecchia we would say bye for a few days to Carole and Daniel. Obviously we did this over coffee and pastries. They were heading to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-aug-2012-17021.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1368379125165.5713&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Our Spot&#34; width=&#34;363&#34; height=&#34;272&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We from hear ambled our way via a few one night stops home, as usual once we got half way up France the heavens opened and we just headed back to the UK. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fort Pramand, Mount Pramand Overnight</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 08:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/23/fort-pramand-mount-pramand-overnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1825.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394770.2654&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Fort Pramand&#34; width=&#34;388&#34; height=&#34;291&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since leaving the Plitvička national park, in Croatia where we visited the former top secret airbase of &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/&#34;&gt;Zeljava&lt;/a&gt; we made our way to Fort Pramand, which was the next area we planned to do some off-road exploring, near Oulx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-18-aug-2012-1909.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394854.0425&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Drinking Prosecco&#34; width=&#34;306&#34; height=&#34;229&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt; On the way we stopped in Slovenia at the Bovec national park to chill out for a day or so, around the beautiful mountains and river Soča, we seem to like that area and always have a good time exploring. We also stopped in Revine, which is near Connegliano in Italy, the area famous for Prosecco sparkling wine. We obviously had to grab a box from a vineyard. The main reason for stopping here though was to use it as a gateway to Venice. There is an intercity train that will take you straight into Venice main station. That&amp;#039;s another story though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After this we travelled towards Oulx, barring another one night stop at Lago Maggiore. Oulx is one of the nearest towns to where we had planned to head up to the tracks I had researched. So the original plan was to stock up with and food, water and beer we needed then go. Oulx has a few official camp sites in the immediate vicinity, should you need a base to explore from. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;But the Landy had other ideas. I had noticed that on occasion with increasing frequency, that the battery voltage was creeping up to the point of potentially over charging the batteries. This was concerning, as apart from potentially screwing up my expensive new batteries it was likely to mean we could not depend on them when we were off the beaten track. Luckily when we stopped in Oulx, we had a fiddle with the alternator which was fairly new as I uprated it a few months earlier and found that some of the terminals must have either worked loose or built up a resistance on the regulator sensing connection. This obviously led to the regulator over exciting the alternator giving a high output voltage. It was interesting because none of the connections were noticeably loose. It has been fine since. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1448.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394803.1416&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;On the up&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So now the beer could be kept cool we headed up to the mountain tracks, via the main road that runs parallel to the E70 motorway, I think it is the ss n 24 headed east we took the left that leads up past Fort Fenils. However the excitement was not over! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As we started to ascend we suddenly noticed a strong smell of smoke and soon came to some mountain fire trucks, police and lots of people. It was a forest fire approaching the road, we were lucky though they guided us past. The road is tarmac for a few kilometres on the way up before it turns to easy gravel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Next the Pajero which Carole and Daniel were driving started to overheat! So we had to stop shortly after hitting gravel for lunch. Luckily to get to Fort Pramand we did not have far to go so, time was on our side. You&amp;#039;d think that was the end of the drama though surely. Luckily the next incident started as we approached the fort. The Pajero decided that the automatic transmission oil indicator would light, suggesting it was overheating. We guessed it was because of the low range work and slow speed, not helped probably by the earlier overheat. Oh well it would get a chance to cool overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1629.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394765.179&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Tracks up&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The tracks up to Fort Pramand are easy, until you get to the last bit leading up to the Fort, which is a turn off from the main track anyhow. The track narrows because of trees either side that lean towards the center of the track. The ground has a few large roots to climb. It is not to bad in a small or low 4x4, but with the root tent on the Landy it was a little tricky, we clipped a corner of the tent lightly. Just a scuff mark no damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The Fort itself is fairly big, but in a very poor state of repair it sits at 2162 meters, there are various warnings spray painted on the walls warning of Danger. The roof is in a poor state of repair. I suspect it has had a few vehicles on its roof. You can walk onto it by following the track up, the view is excellent from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1746.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394771.471&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;Dinner&#34; width=&#34;356&#34; height=&#34;475&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we settled up there and started to cook and set ourselves up for the night it started to feel a bit spooky. The girls were convinced it was haunted. Especially when something took exception to Wendy&amp;#039;s singing. For some reason after we all told her not to quit her day job, and that she did no justice to Black Betty, the radio in the car came on and started blaring!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We had a nice dinner which was made even better with the red wine we got from Connegliano to season it. Shortly after the clouds rolled in so we disappeared for what we thought would be a peaceful night. However with the girls convinced we were being watched by spooky ghosts, Wendy woke a few times to noises, saying she felt like someone was climbing the ladder to the roof tent. She then woke me up because she was too scared to go to the toilet! The conversation went along the lines of.... &#34;Do you need a pee. no. Can you come with me. Do I have too. Yes. Well I am not going twice get Cassie, we&amp;#039;ll have a family pee.&#34; Needless to say. There was no ghost waiting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-22-aug-2012-1754.jpg?w=500&#34; id=&#34;blogsy-1366450394800.108&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Setup&#34; width=&#34;366&#34; height=&#34;275&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;With hind sight I guess being parked with the ladder right against the Fort, between two very dark portals was probably adding to the girls apprehension. In the morning Carole got out of the tent having had no sleep, because she was also convinced ghost soldiers were marching across their tent!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After breakfast we left a little tired and headed for Mount Jafferau, via a cool tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;If you want to download the GPS track from this post and the next you can download it here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikiloc.com/wikiloc/view.do?id=3261982&#34;&gt;Wikiloc&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/view_trip.php?trip_id=1741579&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Everytrail&#34;&gt;Everytrail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Feel free to leave a comment if you want to know more. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeljava Airbase - The Former Yugoslavia&#39;s Most Secret Airfield</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 18:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/08/16/zeljava-airbase-the-former-yugoslavias-most-secret-airfield-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889158964_c853f3ebe0.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;DC-3 abandoned&#34; width=&#34;427&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The main reason for heading up to the Plitvička National Park again, was not this time to visit those beautiful lake, which bring most tourists to the area. My research for interesting things to see on our travels, had caused me to stumble  upon the abandoned airbase at Zeljava. Some of which is on the Croatian side, the rest spans the border of Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having seen the lakes and tourist crowds a year ago, we decided to fore go the experience again. We planned the day such that the bio-in-laws, would disappear in the morning to the lakes, Cassie was desperate to join them so went to show them around. Then if they returned in time they would join Wendy and Myself to visit Zeljava to try and find the base. As it goes they did return and three of us disappeared to find the base. Cassie stayed at camp with Carole. We had spent the morning tidying up the car and catching up on what would be best described as administrative tasks. Oh, I also spent the morning superglue&amp;#039;ing the rear indicator lens back together, from two million pieces in the grass...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889406454/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889406454_5ea4028caf_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;209&#34; height=&#34;279&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;From our campsite across the valley we could see mount Plitvička and mount Gola which hid Zeljava from us, the summit is home to modern radio masts, probably cellular these days. Being over looked by this helped build up the anticipation for me, we had been longing to do something different since Mont Saccarel in Italy. We did not manage to get to the top of the hill to explore, although I had a gps track to find our way. I believe during the period that the base was in use, the mountain over the airbase housed a radar warning system which was part of a network for Yugoslavia, this formed a early warning system for the airspace around Yugoslavia similar to NORAD. Regardless of what was now at the top, it would have been nice to explore, and it probably would have provided great views of the base, back to the camp and also over Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889378116/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889378116_1a38622bd4.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889398448/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889398448_71685d1284.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;360&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;On the net there is a lot of interest around military bases and sites, Zeljava is no different. It did not take long to establish it&amp;#039;s location months before we departed the UK. I used google earth to verify and then generated a waypoint for the GPS. As I also had 1:200k maps of the area from our last visit, I drew a box around the area and highlighted it so I could find it during the trip. Before we departed the UK, I had been to Stanford Maps in London looking for more detailed maps, I would have preferred 1:50k or 1:25k, but they had nothing better than I had. I also had a look on the Internet for a source but was not successful, I don&amp;#039;t know if such detailed maps are produced for the area? Perhaps not for walkers, I guess the land mine risk is still very real, I expect military maps do exist thou, in fact I have seen extracts of Military maps, so am sure they exist. If you know a source please leave a comment or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889447928/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889447928_c316a60bd3.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;429&#34; height=&#34;322&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889451114/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889451114_d4300e011a.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;357&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Getting to the Plitvička area had been a great drive the previous day, although it was slow. I set the GPS to go via a couple of minor towns along the border area, and also set it to minor and un-paved roads, avoiding highways and major roads. Oh how the route impressed us, we went through tiny habitations and along mostly single carrage roads were the Tarmac barely remained. One section saw us follow about 20 km along a gravel route to a lake, I think the people there before us had stayed the night, it was a watering hole for a horse trek also. Had we been on our own I think we would have stayed the night. At the exit of this track we took the oppurtunity to stop at a sign that said &#34;Med&#34;, which is honey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889430760/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889430760_9c19261aeb.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;321&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The locals sell their honey, local plum brandy known as Rijeka and often wine, being tourists, they took the oppurtunity to sell us the golden delight at a much inflated rate, not speaking Croation meant we had little choice, but to  either except or move on. Needless to say we choose the former, two gigantic jars of Honey for 150 Kuna. Working out the price I have no idea how we got to it, when we did not understand the man, he just shouted louder! Our indications to write it in the dirt got lost in translation. Oh well we leave richer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889428454/in/set-72157631307007120&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:right;float:right;margin-bottom:1em;margin-left:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889428454_84d179df0a.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;370&#34; height=&#34;277&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on the route took us along routes that over looked Bosnia and Herzegovina, where we could see old border walls from the conflict, deserted habitations and bullet ridden houses, signs for mines are still a fairly common sight and leave otherwise beautiful land abandoned. Croatia has always struck me as a country of contrast, in respect to redevelopment post conflict. The coast is very built up and apparently affluent, were as if you head inland, there are still areas were buildings are derelict and bare the bullet scares of the war. The people on the coast are mostly involved in some way with tourism, the people inland are hard working farmers and manual workers. They look honest and interesting, I wish I could converse with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Thanks to the net there is a lot of information available about the history of the base. It&amp;#039;s construction was started around 1948, at the time it was known as Objekat 505. The actual pooring of the concrete is in some of the info I read is supposed to have started a few year later in the 50&amp;#039;s. Construction was finished around 1968. On completion it was given the name &#34;Klek&#34; and had a military post cost of 4868, to reflect the start and finish years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The design of the base is such that the tunnels are semicircular, and big enough to allow fighter jets to enter, the tunnels are about two jets wide. When the tunnels were constructed they had positions for explosives to be placed, such that detonation would cause the facility to become unusable. The entrance to the tunnel is shaped to allow the tail of the aircraft to enter the tunnel like an upside down &#34;T&#34;shape, these could be blocked by 1 meter thick pressurised doors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The internal sections of the base are designed to withstand a 20 kilo-tonne nuclear bomb. Which I have read is equivalent to the nagashima bomb, in Japan during world war two. As you would expect being able to withstand such a blast would imply that the doors would have to be kept shut. The base internally had generators, fuel storage, waste storage and water. The most important facilities were all located in the tunnels, with a mess room capable of seating 1000 people. Fuel was piped from storage tanks located 10 to 20 km away in a mountain in Bosnia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Above the main tunnels in the mountain, accessed by elevator only from inside the tunnels, was a room that was used for strategic planning and by the operators of the early warning radar system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The base was in use until the 1990&amp;#039;s and at one stage was looked at with a view to modernisation around the late 1970&amp;#039;s. When it was first built it is said to have cost some where between 4 and 6 billion US dollars. Apparently the funding came from the world bank and was secured for development of communication routes (motorways and roads) in the former Yugoslavia. The construction was carried out by a Serbian firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the end, during the conflict it was the Yugoslav Peoples Army (JNA) who detonated the pre-prepared explosives for distruction of the base on there retreat. I guess the base would have been rather useful to advancing forces. Later there was further distraction of the base using 56 tonnes of explosives, by the military of Serbian Krajina, this was carried out in 1995. Articles on the web site locals as saying that the force shock local towns like an earth quake and that the tunnels smoked for 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/76486608@N05/7889025612/in/set-72157631310217932&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;clear:left;float:left;margin-bottom:1em;margin-right:1em;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/7889025612_623531420e_c.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;External to the tunnels there are five runways on the base three lead straight into tunnels. The last two were used for other aircraft to land. The total area I&amp;#039;d the base was on the order of 9km by 4km.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Ordinarily staff at the base lived in the town of Bihać, which is in Bosnia now, this was the nearest city. I have read on one site that there was a dedicated bus service between Bihać and the base for staff to commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our Visit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Croatian side of the airbase comming from the Plitvička national park there is only really one way to get to the base by road. In order to this your arrival is via the small village of Zeljava, which seemed almost empty save for a few dozen people who live in the houses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the village and the base are various buildings that appear to be abandoned almost deralict in some cases. Shortly after the village on the main road on the left you pass gates, behind which it is possible to glimpse an old military plane. It is possible to see how cars have avoided the closed gates and damaged fence, to make there own path to the road behind the gates. Where it eventually leads who knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued past the planes to the find the rest of the base, about 1 kilometre further, we came across what was our first sign of more to be seen. Buildings hidden on the right by trees, this time of the year the dense trees and shrubs provide good cover for the buildings and relics hidden around the base. We cut off the main approach road, to explore what appear to be vehicle maintenance or facility areas. We abandoned the car at this stage choosing instead to explore by foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceeding towards the runway areas south east from where we were brought us via vehicle inspection ramps to another open area, that we were not sure of the use of, but it was littered with hydraulic hoses and metal scraps, there were various bullet ridden sign posts and behind the trees, what looked like a discarded bomb, that was not / had not detonated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We continued towards the end of what was runway 4 and runway 3, which meet at the what looks like an apron, prior to the entrances to the tunnels 1 &amp;amp; 2. Turning right, past another mine warning, the open apron gives way to the approach to the tunnels, which was almost claustrophobic with the tree cover that was slowly reclaiming the base, making it feel close. As you approach the tunnel entrance you feel that there is something watching you. All the time listening to rustling and noises in the trees,never being able to identify what the source was. Eventually we knew we were close by the wall of cold air that hit us, emerging from the tunnels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Shortly before the tunnel entrance we noticed a strange metal object that although half complete looks like a soldier or guards metal hat. The tunnel mouth although visible is obscured on the lower half by a mount of dirt that has been placed to prevent people taking vehicles into the tunnels. Entrance by foot is possible, having no torches or breathing equipment we choose to avoid this option on this occasion, instead staring into the dim light. We chose to avoid entrance because of a report I had read warning of toxic chemicals in the dust and potentially radio active waste from the fire detection equipment that was unaccounted for. Appart from this entry is fairly hazardous due to the unstable nature, but probably would not have prevented us if we had not been fortunate enough to read the report (available in the site links below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After this we went on to explore tunnel entrance two, but were interrupted by the sudden noise of several 4x4&amp;#039;s at first we were unsure of the nature of these vehicles, as I had previously read of border police being sensitive in this area, probably because of the unguarded border to Bosnia and Herzegovina. Luckily the vehicles turned out to be civilians tourists. With this we recovered our vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We returned back with the vehicle to explore the remaining section beyond the apron towards the unmanned Bosnian border, along the approach we passed various buildings for fire and parking areas. In one area, we came across the remains of a military vehicle minus the chassis and engine on its side. This looked like it had been hit by something, judging by the holes in the body. Not sure what it was used for thou. Along the road we came across spent bullet shells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We proceeded further to the border, where we came across an eyry owl, that was remarkably tame. Was this some kind of sinister warning? After taking some film we stopped at the UN border barrier for some photos, before making our way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the way out we wanted to look at the abandoned aircraft near the base entrance. These turned out to be a DC-3 and two F-84 fighters, I was not able to work out the exact type. But they proved an interesting addition to the visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References / More Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found most of the info I wanted by following links out of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C5%BDeljava_Air_Base&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Wikipedia Zeljava Airbase&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeljava-lybi.com/Zeljava-index2_eng.html&#34;&gt;Zeljava Lybi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>