<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Off Road on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/off-road/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Off Road on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/off-road/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17 - Koplic to Kepi i Kalas via the Karavasta Lagoon.</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 18:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130905.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the heat we did quite well this morning and managed to get packed up and on the road by 0945, after we had a slow coffee and showers all round. Our original plan was to head up to Thethi, which is said to be beautiful, but have a difficult road, especially after rain. Given that the last two days there had been storms in the area, we decided we would not attempt that, but perhaps try on the return route. Instead today we would head for the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gus and Helen who we met at the campsite had lent us a map which they had been given, by another traveller in Albania on a bike. Many of the circles were on the places we had read about, some were alien to us. Anyhow I copied the circles to our map. Todays plan was based on circles. We would head to the circle at Karavasta Lagoon. We had no idea what was there so Wendy read up in the guide book on the way between navigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary was that it is a wet land with many birds and lots of wild life. At night it is apparently a mosquito hell hole. Cool, sounds like an ideal place to visit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130908.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we left we found the roads in the area where we stayed all seemed ok, well sign posted and smooth. Petrol stations everywhere. It was not long before we were in chaos though, Sckoder was manic and it was every man for himself. The roads had occasional road markings, round abouts and traffic signals. Pedestrian crossings never mind those. We encountered various types of traffic, bikes, people, horse and cart, three wheel trucks and even motor bikes which had a tray arrangement welded to the from that formed a kind of three wheel truck thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic involved people and cyclists moving the wrong way and or on the wrong side of the road. Putting themselves in danger. The drivers used their horn to say either hello, we are over taking or we are coming through regardless. Undertaking was the norm. This was probably because the fast lane was used to avoid the chaos at the side of the road with the triple parked vehicles and other oddities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At roundabouts most people don&#39;t bother indicating, if they do it means nothing because they forget to change it as the filter off with the opposite indication. The roundabouts work a bit like a drain hole. In that no one stops, they just continue being sucked into the vortex and some break free when they need to leave. Occasionally you&#39;ll get some one a little bit more crazy who will just fly across the round about breaking the vortex. You&#39;ll have warning if you are lucky by way of continuous multiple beeping of the horn. Beep Beep beep beep beep beep beep beep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually made it out of Sckoder, shocked but unharmed! It was exciting. The only negative for me was the begging on the out skirts at the traffic lights which meant we locked the doors and put the windows up. Sorry. I felt really bad about that, but did not want to encourage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the main road overtaking is an art, you&#39;ll often be confronted by a speeding car in your lane flashing lights at you. They are overtaking. They expect you to assist be moving out of the way. Several occasions having held my ground, I took evasive action, either by braking, making use of the dirt hard shoulder or swerving. These guys are good at Chicken. I think I saved us a few times from accidents by braking to allow people to hop from behind and avoid the front of busses by feet, not meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We endured this for several hours, even trying the motor way, which although wider had limited road markings and was just a bigger play ground.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0156.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually arrived at Karavasta. Here we headed along dirt tracks, paid a toll and continued to the beach, we were able to drive all the way up the beach until we found a quiet spot. You can&#39;t do that in many places. Here we relaxed for an hour or so had a swim and lunch. Previously we had tried about 4 km up the beach, but being near a river outlet there was a lot of plan debris on the beach making it look undesirable amongst all the rubbish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having refreshed ourselves and having convinced ourselves it was not an ideal place to camp, we headed back out on the dirt road which we entered, this then lead us to take a turning to follow one of the waterways of the lagoon. We came across some locals fishing and checked with them we were headed in the right direction. They basically as usual said keep going!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0182.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were not headed basically down a raised section of the lagoon that had a track on it. The track continued for about 5 km, it was wet but ok. I was obviously concerned as it may have got very boggy. It was just wide enough for a car.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0190.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we saw loads of small birds, which appeared not to have the ability to fly, but to merely run around scatter brained. There were also lots of herons. The star of the afternoon was a tortoise we came across just wandering the track. We jumped out to get photos quickly, before it disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0198.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time we got out of there it was getting late, so we headed just south of Vlora to hunt down a room to stay in. We found a nice hotel perched on a cliff top with a private beach for 35 Euro a night with breakfast. We had a swim, then freshened up for the evening opting to eat at the hotel and drink a few beers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirations for 2013&#39;s Trip</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 19:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2013-1900.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as I mentioned earlier in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, we have been thinking about what we might do this summer. Actually we have been thinking since last summer. I guess we are probably not alone on this, we tend to think from trip to trip, from day to day, even during a trip. I guess most people who enjoy travelling have this problem. Is it wrong? I don&amp;#039;t want to wish my life away, but I love thinking about possibilities, getting the map out while drinking wine or beer in camp. Is that dreamin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us we have been to lots of places in Europe, we still have much of Northern Europe to go and places on our own door step such as Scotland and Ireland, but the weather makes life tricky in those places. We don&amp;#039;t want to be confined, confined to a hotel. We want the option to camp, we like camping. No we are not poor, we just like to get away from it. I camp in hotels all year for work, I really don&amp;#039;t like it. So I guess sooner or later we need to take the plunge and face the weather, before we loose the opportunity to see the places we take for granted on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we have been thinking about travel this August. Unfortunately during tourist season, we are bound to this because of school holidays, we tend to get away lightly due to the places we visit, not always. Our plans have been a little hampered this year, domestics are getting in the way! We had to have the kitchen done... I guess you are wondering what the hell I am on. Well it is all about economics. The kitchen cost a fortune (it is still not finished). This has hampered our trip money saving ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this has meant that, although we have &amp;#039;planned&amp;#039;, the plan is more of an &amp;#039;aspiration&amp;#039;. Let me explain. I guess what we are saying is that, we refuse to give up the opportunity of our annual trip. Regardless of how far we have saved, we&amp;#039;ll see how far we can go on what we&amp;#039;ve got! So if we don&amp;#039;t know what we will be able to do we should plan for what we&amp;#039;d like to do. So I guess you&amp;#039;d say plan for your aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that explained. We&amp;#039;d like this year to explore some more dirt roads in the Alps, there is a warren up there and plenty of places to wild camp without having to part with Euros. After that we&amp;#039;d also like to explore Kosovo, Albania and Macedonia. These are completely new to us and potentially very exciting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-may-2013-2022.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we get from the Alps to Albania and the surrounding areas, would either be by road or by sea. We used a ferry last year from Bari to Croatia which made life very easy, but expensive. The easiest ferry option for Albania is from Ancona to Durrës. This costs circa €400 but saves probably about three days in raw driving, that is really more because we stop and take a non direct route. The ferry crossing is around 20 hours. The saving is definitely not in fuel, even in a Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of getting to Albania from Ancona, is that we can use the days saved to spend more time exploring before heading back, it is probably about 1500 miles (2600 km) to Brighton from there. Which would be about 7 days driving, we&amp;#039;d need to allow about 10 so we could chill a bit. This would leave us about 2 weeks in the area we want to be. In reality I&amp;#039;d hope to be able to build some of the return days into the route to allow us to look at possibly Kosovo, Montenegro and Bosnia and Herzegovina a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks we&amp;#039;ll be looking at every country we aspire to visit this year and posting a bit about sites and areas that have caught our attention. This will hopefully culminate with a rough route plan. Hopefully we&amp;#039;ll be able to research some more Alps routes too. So stay tuned if you want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 09:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastlane99.plus.com/&#34;&gt;Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just found this link via a reply to a &lt;a title=&#34;HUBB&#34; href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/europe/familly-friendly-4x4-tours-alps-70380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post on Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;. If your looking at exploring the tracks of the Alps. There some nice pictures on here from the early 2000&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>