<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re taking Blogsy on a road trip.</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/20/were-taking-blogsy-on-a-road-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 09:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/20/were-taking-blogsy-on-a-road-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-19-apr-2012-1947.jpg?w=164&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;166&#34; alt=&#34;Blogsy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have traditionally kept a Moleskin notebook with us when we are on the road, the current one is on its third trip. I would hate for it to go missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the back we record all the cool things like mileages, fuel costs and locations we fill up at. This enables us to keep a log of our fuel consumption. Potentially a sign of an impending problem. We also record accommodation, ferry and toll costs. I often think it would be good if there was more cost information available for overlanders. My intention is to look at the general cost per unit of distance. I believe an accurate assumption can be made for longer trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In the front we use it as a diary or journal we record how the day went, what we did, what was said, funny moments and other such things. The journal itself is a good read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Traditionally when we get home we have every intention of putting our journal story on the web, this often happens many months later. The moment has passed and the story element is lost. Reading the past storys can be a slog. This is for a few reasons; the delay in transferring the story to the site, the size of the task. We are aware of these issues and hate that the moment can be lost in the writing, as the journeys to us are so much more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;To try and improve on these issues we are still going to use our journal, but have decided we will post the story in the style of a blog rather than a webpage. To do this we will use the iPad to post the blog as we go. We often camp and it is at these moments we have time, we are relaxed and in the mood to write these entries. The iPad is the ideal tool for this. The important part of this is we will be immersed in the trip while we are writing, so still living the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;To enable us to do this we are going to use a few tools, firstly we will be using Blogsy which is a blogging app for the iPad, I suggest you check it out by the way, it is the best of what I have tried. For some reason this app makes you want to post, it has a great feel and brings together everything you need in a great interface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We will also be using iPhoto to manage, edit and upload photos. To do this we will be getting a camera connection kit for the iPad shortly. I&amp;#039;ll update you on this soon on this. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;ve moved. Africanuhambo has been transported To Wordpress</title>
      <link>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/17/weve-moved-africanuhambo-has-been-transported-to-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 21:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/17/weve-moved-africanuhambo-has-been-transported-to-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well we are in the middle of moving the website from where it was previously hosted, Google to Wordpress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially we will be moving it to a Wordpress hosted option. This is at Wordpress.com, in the future if we need move flexibility we may actually move to a Wordpress based self hosted server. This should be easily achievable with the export options Wordpress provides. At the moment thou, we will be staying at Wordpress.com they offer a generous amount of storage free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually the third move for our site. The site started on a self managed server previously, we then &#34;simplified&#34; this resulted in a move to google sites, which was ultimately too simple. So this latest move should be a happy medium and offer easy moving options or upgrade options should we need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason for moving is that google sites are not the easiest to update on the road sans wifi. This ultimately resulted in us not updating the site. At least now we can do updates via email, iPad app or PC offline app to be uploaded at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Summer&amp;#039;s trip is only just being typed up and with a month away, typing seven months late actually makes the tale loose it&amp;#039;s charm. Despite the fact we record each day in a Moleskin journal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So looking forward to more updates, wish us luck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>