<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Defender on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/categories/defender/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Defender on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/categories/defender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 20 - Secret Beach to Italian B&amp;B</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/15/day-20-secret-beach-to-italian-bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 07:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/15/day-20-secret-beach-to-italian-bb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were up very early thanks to having had no sleep. Dan started the day with a 5am swim!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a departure of 6am for us after we brushed our teeth and dressed. We decided to find a café along the way and get some breakfast and a coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1140108.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made our way back up the winding road that you take to get down to the Southern part of Albania. At the top there is a restaurant, it looked open and was serving a few travellers, so we decided to stop. We ordered coffee and asked for the menu for breakfast. We got the impression that breakfast wasn&#39;t a big meal in Albania and ordered toast with butter and honey and toast with butter and jam. What we got was warmed up slices of bread with a side plate that had a lump of butter and a dollop of honey or jam. The butter was rancid and the Jam was a little different. We ate the bread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0296.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had decided to head for Vlorë and enquire about the ferry, see if it did take cars and how much it was. When we got into Vlorë, we could see the port with a ferry anchored, but we couldn&#39;t see how to get to the port. Eventually we came across a sign and turned down a road … well, we ended up stuck as we found ourselves surrounded by bollards. There was a gap in the bollards where someone had obviously tried to drive over them and knocked one off. We are a high vehicle, so we just drove over it, down the incredibly high kerb and out into the traffic going onto the roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0228.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually found the port and parked the land, grabbed our passports and documentation and went in search of tickets. Not a hard thing as the street was lined with ticket shops. The fair, including the car and 2 adults and 1 child came to €206 one way. We were informed it departed at 1pm and to check in at 12.30pm the latest. We bought the ticket, but now had a few hours to kill before we embarked. We decided to wonder around Vlorë, find a supermarket and exchange our LEK. The supermarket part was easier said than done, but we did manage to exchange our left over LEK. With that done we headed for an air conditioned café to have a drink and wait out our remaining time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 12.30 we got in the car and headed towards the ferry. We came across a mishmash of higgledy piggledy park cars and young boys shouting at us to buy cigarettes. One of the young boys pointed to an office and said, &#34;You go give ticket there.&#34;. Dan thanked him and hopped out with the tickets and passports. A gentleman at the office helped Dan with the odd check in procedure and then we were off and boarding the ferry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked, gathered our bits and bobs for the journey and went up to find a table. We were all tired from last night and were hoping to be able to get some shut eye on the journey. The gentleman that had helped Dan appeared, along with his wife and son. He is married to an English lady and every year they journey to Italy and Albania to visit his family. They warned us that even though we were told a 1pm departure, it would be more like 3pm departure. With this knowledge we settled ourselves for a long day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1140126.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally at 2.28pm the ferry started moving. We were off! Only another 5 hours to go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey was long and very boring. We were also warned not to eat the food on the ferry, so we settled for pre packaged crisps and biscuits. After disembarking, it was now 7.30pm and we decided to head a little south from Brindisi. We have no Italy maps and our GPS is still dead, so we looked for a services so we could buy a map of the area. After a few failed attempts, Dan pulls into one and manages to get a map. He asked a gentleman in the services if there was camping, the guy was apparently rather rat arsed, but very helpful and pointed Dan in the direction of a few campsites. Now we just had to find them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a little lost, and as the time ticked on, we could not find a campsite. We looked for the obligatory signs, but found none. After 2 hours we finally see a sign, and we follow it … and we follow it … and we follow it. We are now desperate to sleep and eat and decide to just check into a hotel. The first hotel we see, that is easy to park in, we pull into to ask if they have a room. Unfortunatley for us, they are completely full! We are informed that all the hotels are completely full and that we will struggle to find a room as it is Italy&#39;s 2 week holiday period. He kindly calls around and finds a B&amp;amp;B that have a free room, but it will cost us €100 for the night including breakfast. Bggars can&#39;t be chooses, so we thank the guy and take the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The owner of the B&amp;amp;B came to meet us at the hotel and show us the way back to the B&amp;amp;B. We followed him, pulled into the B&amp;amp;B, took the room key, had a shower and collapsed .. sparko till the next morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke not to early, but not to late and had showers. We then went to have breakfast. We were all starving as we never did get to eat dinner the night before. Breakfast consisted of a buffet style arrangement with fresh fruits, fruit juice, bread, butter, jam and some poached fruit and a lemon compot thing. We were simply enjoying eating when a plate of cakes is put down onto our table … a very sweet breakfast, Cassie certainly wasn&#39;t complaining.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18 - Kepi i Kalas to Bunec via our Secret beach</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 07:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/13/day-18-kepi-i-kalas-to-bunec-via-our-secret-beach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0254.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Being in a hotel last night meant getting away quickly was easy. We had a local style breakfast of feta, tomato, cucumber and bread. Washed down with a few coffees.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Our plan was to check out a beach I had found on Google earth that looked almost isolated due to the track you had to use to get to it. Due to the GPS problems I had circled it on the map. This meant it was another day heading to a circle. The drive to the beach took about an hour or so. We first had to negotiate some spectacular steep roads with tight hairpins over the surrounding mountains. The roads had various bits missing and loads of fallen rocks which claimed a few victims to punctures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130959.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The turning to the beach was immediately of the bottom of the steep decent. There had been a few attempts to grade it, but the track was pretty bad. On the was down we got held up by a truck rescuing an Italian mobile home who had been over ambitious. Both looked frustrated. The tow rope was in taters. The owner said something to me as we squeezed by. I promised to return with my tow strap and shackles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;By the time I had stopped 50 meters on and returned they appeared to on there way so I returned and we continued to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we got to the bottom we were delighted, we found an almost empty beach except for a couple of 4x4&#39;s and 2 or 3 like minded over landing campers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The beach was made up by sandy white pebbles. The top of the beach had a sand track which was easy to traverse. We headed most of the way along the track then turned down to the sea. Parking 10 meters from the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0253.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Here we swam in crystal clear water and lounged around for the morning. Cassie loved it. Spending most of the time checking out the fishies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Later on we decided to leave, I was a little apprehensive, as I had noted the sand and shingle made for horribly difficult driving. I had deflated the tyres a little and even in low diff lock, I struggled. I had to repeatedly reverse to get any momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;My first attempt to get up the beach failed, I thought I had enough speed but could not get into low third without grinding to a halt and sinking. I stopped and let some more air out of the tyres and reversed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Foot to the floor I headed slightly back down towards the sea and managed to get some speed and into third. This allowed me to managed the engine speed and get enough velocity to get over the sand up to the slightly better surface to get off the beach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once I was back on the track at the top, I was hot! So we headed to a small makeshift bar a local had erected in the rock walls of the mountain that encapsulated the beach. I had a fanta and a beer to chill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had received we headed south to find a place to stay. We had again opted out of camping as we had no supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130983.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We eventually after some chaos ended up at a tiny restaurant at Bunec beach, which had rooms. The owning family lived in a tent. They were very nice and cooked us a traditional pasta dish and we drank loads of beer and swam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130990.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The rooms in these places are basic but functional and clean. We paid 30 euro with breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17 - Koplic to Kepi i Kalas via the Karavasta Lagoon.</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 18:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/12/day-17-koplic-to-kepi-i-kalas-via-the-karavasta-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130905.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the heat we did quite well this morning and managed to get packed up and on the road by 0945, after we had a slow coffee and showers all round. Our original plan was to head up to Thethi, which is said to be beautiful, but have a difficult road, especially after rain. Given that the last two days there had been storms in the area, we decided we would not attempt that, but perhaps try on the return route. Instead today we would head for the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gus and Helen who we met at the campsite had lent us a map which they had been given, by another traveller in Albania on a bike. Many of the circles were on the places we had read about, some were alien to us. Anyhow I copied the circles to our map. Todays plan was based on circles. We would head to the circle at Karavasta Lagoon. We had no idea what was there so Wendy read up in the guide book on the way between navigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary was that it is a wet land with many birds and lots of wild life. At night it is apparently a mosquito hell hole. Cool, sounds like an ideal place to visit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130908.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we left we found the roads in the area where we stayed all seemed ok, well sign posted and smooth. Petrol stations everywhere. It was not long before we were in chaos though, Sckoder was manic and it was every man for himself. The roads had occasional road markings, round abouts and traffic signals. Pedestrian crossings never mind those. We encountered various types of traffic, bikes, people, horse and cart, three wheel trucks and even motor bikes which had a tray arrangement welded to the from that formed a kind of three wheel truck thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic involved people and cyclists moving the wrong way and or on the wrong side of the road. Putting themselves in danger. The drivers used their horn to say either hello, we are over taking or we are coming through regardless. Undertaking was the norm. This was probably because the fast lane was used to avoid the chaos at the side of the road with the triple parked vehicles and other oddities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At roundabouts most people don&#39;t bother indicating, if they do it means nothing because they forget to change it as the filter off with the opposite indication. The roundabouts work a bit like a drain hole. In that no one stops, they just continue being sucked into the vortex and some break free when they need to leave. Occasionally you&#39;ll get some one a little bit more crazy who will just fly across the round about breaking the vortex. You&#39;ll have warning if you are lucky by way of continuous multiple beeping of the horn. Beep Beep beep beep beep beep beep beep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually made it out of Sckoder, shocked but unharmed! It was exciting. The only negative for me was the begging on the out skirts at the traffic lights which meant we locked the doors and put the windows up. Sorry. I felt really bad about that, but did not want to encourage it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the main road overtaking is an art, you&#39;ll often be confronted by a speeding car in your lane flashing lights at you. They are overtaking. They expect you to assist be moving out of the way. Several occasions having held my ground, I took evasive action, either by braking, making use of the dirt hard shoulder or swerving. These guys are good at Chicken. I think I saved us a few times from accidents by braking to allow people to hop from behind and avoid the front of busses by feet, not meters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We endured this for several hours, even trying the motor way, which although wider had limited road markings and was just a bigger play ground.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0156.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We eventually arrived at Karavasta. Here we headed along dirt tracks, paid a toll and continued to the beach, we were able to drive all the way up the beach until we found a quiet spot. You can&#39;t do that in many places. Here we relaxed for an hour or so had a swim and lunch. Previously we had tried about 4 km up the beach, but being near a river outlet there was a lot of plan debris on the beach making it look undesirable amongst all the rubbish.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having refreshed ourselves and having convinced ourselves it was not an ideal place to camp, we headed back out on the dirt road which we entered, this then lead us to take a turning to follow one of the waterways of the lagoon. We came across some locals fishing and checked with them we were headed in the right direction. They basically as usual said keep going!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0182.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were not headed basically down a raised section of the lagoon that had a track on it. The track continued for about 5 km, it was wet but ok. I was obviously concerned as it may have got very boggy. It was just wide enough for a car.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0190.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way we saw loads of small birds, which appeared not to have the ability to fly, but to merely run around scatter brained. There were also lots of herons. The star of the afternoon was a tortoise we came across just wandering the track. We jumped out to get photos quickly, before it disappeared.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0198.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time we got out of there it was getting late, so we headed just south of Vlora to hunt down a room to stay in. We found a nice hotel perched on a cliff top with a private beach for 35 Euro a night with breakfast. We had a swim, then freshened up for the evening opting to eat at the hotel and drink a few beers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 - Koplic, Lake Shkrodër</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/11/day-16-koplic-lake-shkroder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to stay two nights at Lake Shkodër. Today we woke slowly, having been woken by Cassie in the middle of the night again. After we finally dragged her sleeping items into the tent, thunder rolled in. There had been a little rain too, but not a significant amount. Needless to say, it was a little bit of a restless night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day was warming up already by mid morning, and I had decided that the sheets, towels and pillow cases needed to be washed. We also needed to get some food. We asked the owner of the campsite if here was a shop close by and he said yes, just walk up to the main road, over the bridge and there is a shop there. So we handed over our washing, as he had a machine, and set off for the shop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130897.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked we were shocked by the rubbish we saw on the side of the road and dumped in ditches, We passed two young boys by the overpass burning their rubbish. It was a reminder that Albania still had ways to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were perspiring by the time we got to the shop and had to stop for a cold drink at one of the bars. Afterwards we went to the shop and bought essentials .. water, beer, biscuits and other food items. Now for the walk back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the campsite, Cassie made friends with a young girl from a German family staying a few pitches down. She played all afternoon with Lea and her brother Nic. It was nice for her to have company, and Lea wanted to practice her English as she had recently started learning it at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day Thunder had been rumbling in the background but despite this, it had been warm and sunny.. with a slight cloudy haze. But by afternoon, the lightening started making an appearance and we decided to pack up Cassie&#39;s tent and head for the restaurant/bar. And a good thing we did, as the heavens opened with an almighty bang and gush of wind and it did not let up for hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had grabbed a table inside and here we stayed for the most of the evening. Eventually to be joined by Frank and Anjita, Cassie&#39;s new found friends&#39; parents. The evening was great. We swopped travelling stories, places to visit and even swopped blog addresses. It&#39;s always nice to make friends along the way, so thanks Fank and Anjita for a great evening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a second Land Rover at the camp, owned by a Scottish couple that were travelling. We had spoken to them the day before about their set up and swopped maps for tips on places to travel. Anyway, Gus and Helen also ended up at the bar/restaurant and as our table was already full, they sat with a trio of Austrian guys next door to us. As the evening progressed, they ended up joining our table too. We all had a wonderful time drinking wine and beer and swopping stories. Thanks Gus and Helen for your tips and your extending fork!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/dscf0134.jpeg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9 - Duga Resa to Bihać</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/04/day-9-duga-resa-to-bihac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 19:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/04/day-9-duga-resa-to-bihac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well we had a surprisingly quiet night. We thought we would be woken up, having seen and heard the action at the bar, but managed to sleep through. We packed up promptly and made for a café in Duga Resa. The plan was to have some coffee and find something for breakfast. Duga Resa is a tiny place. At this stage I should point out that we still had not found a local cash machine and all I had was Euros. Which is fine for bigger places, but the lady in the café, did not accept them. By the time I remembered it was obviously too late and I had already ordered the coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the lady had a plan, there was a tiny tiny shop around the corner run by two ladies, who were obviously used to all the tourists from the campsite popping in for bits and bobs. I asked if they would mind changing some Euros for me, they agreed, but had to have a discussion about changing as much as 50 Euro, of course it was by this time too late for me to say &#34;How about 30, then?&#34; which fell on deaf ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now back at the café, I sat down for Wendy to tell me what she heard. I should mention that a fat man with a very bad blonde mullet with an irish accent, driving a slovenian plated white van, left the campsite at the same time as us and followed us in to the café. Anyhow, on entering the café I offered for him to go before us in the café while we procrastinated, he declined. After placing our order we heard him say in an irish accent to the Croatian lady &#34;Is the boss around?&#34; Thats unusual! Passing him on the way to the shop, I noticed them talking to a local inside the partially open rear door of the van, I think they used the term Cognac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130484.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I got back and Wendy said, she heard mullet man saying on the phone to a fellow traveller &#34;you better get up here now, there is a shed&#34; our suspicions were confirmed about this lot. About 20 minutes later another of the Irish envoy turned up, in a SUV. Now, remember none of these people speak Croatian. I heard them saying to each other that we spoke english and the language! We can order coffee, beer and juice and ask for the bill. But I have no idea how to say &#34;Do you have a shed we can store our dodgy alcohol in please?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130494.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we left them to it and returned to the shop to grab some stuff for lunch and headed off. We were headed towards Velika Kladuša on the back roads, which lead to some interesting views and sights. Arriving at the border crossing about an hour or so later. By the time we got to the crossing it was getting hot, we queued for about 30 minutes, left Croatia and tried to enter Bosnia and Herzegovina. To be told that the crossing did not have an insurance agent. This meant we would not be able to buy a green card, which meant we had to turn around and re-enter Croatia and head for the Bihać crossing near the Plitviča National Park. Luckily the border guard felt sorry for us and opened up the barrier so we could jump the queue. On the way back through, the Croatia guard recommended that we try to buy insurance at Slunj. We tried and failed there opting to just try at Bihać.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130496.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky at Bihać, the guard did not really care if we had insurance. Normally they hold a passport until you can demonstrate that you have insurance. They returned all our documents and trusted us to go to the offices a 200 meters on and get insurance. The agents building was dark and smelt really bad under the cigarette smoke, housing about 8 or 10 agents. Most of the offices had closed doors with people who did not really care for your presence. I approached a lady who looked at me with slight sympathy in one of the offices asking her for &#34;Osiguranje&#34;, insurance in Croat. She had no idea, knocking and asking on all the doors. Just as she was giving up she told me after a colleague suggested to knock on the last door. I was in luck. They agree to do it, but struggled to find the forms! 30 Euro for 17 days. Moments later I piped out in triumph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130595.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this we motored towards Bihać not quite sure were to go. We passed the town on the outskirts not really seeing any good parts, and found shortly afterwards a sign for &#34;Autokamp&#34;. We decided we wanted to rest and stopped, it was a camp almost empty in the grounds of an empty hotel, Hotel Ada. There was a Spanish van and a Dutch van on site when we arrived. Later two more arrived. The place was deserted. It was a nice campsite though, it had loads of well established trees which provided tons of shade, no need for the awning. We popped the tent up and explored the river bank for a place to swim in the Una. We were lucky the river was beautiful and nice and cool. We spent about an hour swimming before popping back for a shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night we opted for an early dinner at the next door restaurant. It was a fantasy land from a film, outside it had a spit roast lamb on the go. The main building was an old mill and the river weaved between it and pontoons that supported seating areas. In amongst the pontoons the river flowed clear enough to allow viewing the plants and fish, like being in an aquarium shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a kilogram of lamb with flat bread and salad for dinner, finished off with Baklava and several local beers. All in around 25 Euro and fantastic. We headed to bed after a brief chat with our neighbours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a great first day in Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8 - Bovec to Duga Resa</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/03/day-8-bovec-to-duga-resa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 13:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/08/03/day-8-bovec-to-duga-resa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided that today we needed to get cracking and head south. I would have loved to have stayed longer in Bovec, but the campsite was fully booked over the weekend, so we had to either find another site, or move on.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130475.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we spent sometime trying to work out where to head, without driving too far, whilst fitting in with our rough plan. We eventually decided to head for the wine road south-west of Zagreb in northern Croatia. This is a road that runs between Samobor and Jastrebarsko and is famed for its wine. We found the area and the road specifically, with no problems. The route was beautiful and the drive was ideal in the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if I have mentioned previously, but the Garmin Montana GPS is dead (my second one). It does not boot beyond the maps loading at start up, so we are navigating by one of the 1:200k maps we have. Not a problem. Luckily I love maps so have more than enough to compensate. Anyhow, we stopped to get our bearings for a minute, I killed the Landy while Wendy sorted herself out so I could have pee. Jumped back in and the engine did not turn over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I thought I had failed to activate the immobiliser correctly, so did it again. Same outcome. By the third time I could not hear the starter motor solenoid pull in. Ok, I would need a multimeter. Once I grabbed that, I popped off the fuse cover the starter relay was pulling in there was 12 volts on the contact to the solenoid. Which leaves a couple of items as likely causes. Either wiring or connection or starter motor. Engine was too hot and the afternoon was too hot to get close to check either. Not wanting to hang around and given that no one had passed us in 15 minutes, I decided to bump start the Landy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were facing up hill and against the bushes… Luckily I managed to do it in about 2 meters in reverse. We carried on along the route for a while. About 20 minutes on and Cassie needed to wee now, so I stopped nose up a bank. Flicked the ignition and the starter flicked over, good sign… Killed the engine and it restarted, excellent. I suspect connections. I had a similar issue with a connection which was installed by a previous garage removing the stock alarm system. Which I fixed. This had prevented the fuel cut out solenoid activating about 18 months ago. I suspect the same issue here I hope. I&#39;ll replace the crimp when we stop for a couple of days somewhere and I am bored. At the moment the problem has not reoccurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, by this stage we were looking for one of the recommended Vineyards in the Bradt guide, which also had rooms. We found it. But no one was to be found. We waited for a few minutes before deciding to find the second recommendation. This was about another 30 minutes on. We had a different outcome with this, we found signs to the place and followed them diligently up gravel tracks, but the place was nowhere to be seen. We re-read the guide description. We asked locals who pointed up in the right direction. We found a place but it appeared to be another vineyard, by this time we had done the gravel track three or four times. Wendy and Cassie went to investigate, they followed the loud music, I saw a person from outside, they knocked, entered and found no one. Returning minutes later like the place was empty but having a ghost rave. We gave up and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/p1130483.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well what do we do now? On the map a campsite was shown slightly south of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karlovac&#34;&gt;Karlovac&lt;/a&gt;. They make the famous beer &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karlovačko&#34;&gt;Karlovačko&lt;/a&gt;. We eventually found a cool campsite south of Karlovac in Duga Resa. They were busy, but had an excellent river to swim in and a reasonable restaurant, which suited us, given, we were by this time absolutely knackered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically we were surrounded by a very big group of Irish travellers headed for Bosnia, they had large caravans. Fairly modern. Towed by Transit vans. The group as a whole were making a lot of noise. The kids were climbing all over the bathrooms. We were worried we would be associated with them, so stayed well clear despite out close proximity. They looked dodgy, why would you travel in such a large group. I am guessing 30 in total?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost gone</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/26/almost-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 18:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/26/almost-gone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130726-190547.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well we are at this time just over 40 minutes late on our booked departure time, the board is saying we&#39;ll depart an hour and six minutes late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily apart from not having a place to stay yet when we get to France, we have nowhere important to be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seen a nicely refurbished Mercedes truck, which has been converted for overland travel, it is from Switerland. I remember seeing those things as a kid in the desert with water tanks on the back tackling dunes. Nice ride, wish I got a pic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair done</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 17:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130724-184907.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The landy is now back to normal the whole repair is done, seats are in soundproofing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have the fun of packing for the trip. Sorry I did not take a picture of the finished article! But the picture above shows the first of three seats fitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must dash need to iron my pants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upriser/Upstand in</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 16:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not quite as far as I would have liked today. Missed the nut and bolt store. They close at 1400 on a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to get the Upstand and floor fitted and the two central seat brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130720-173701.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow when my drill is charged again, I&#39;ll get ready for the last two seat brackets, when I get the bolts on Monday they&#39;ll be fitted. I should also be able to refit the sound proofing tomorrow, that is the rubber chequer plate stuff from write off road. As sold to the MOD. I had not finished fitting it due to this repair, needing to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am going for a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There Upstand Assembly</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0109.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much of an update tonight, with the ongoing repair apart from to show some pictures of the panel now it has been fully tweaked and drilled to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished of the drilling tonight and deburred everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final job for the night was to give another coat of etch primer and paint the seat brackets and new panels with stone chip paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are now drying, so tomorrow I&#39;ll start fitting it for real. The only thing I need to do is drill the seat brackets in location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful with a push, I should have it done tomorrow or Sunday at the latest. Not wishing to tempt fate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0111.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Upstand/Upriser Re-Assembly</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0091.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now at the stage of re-assembly. It has been a slow road even to strip the back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mid-crossmember is galvanised and from YRM metal solutions. One of the nice features of the new one, is that the top brackets are loose rather than welded on this makes it easier to get the cross member under the fuel pipes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have had with the crossmember is that the holes, for mounting to the chassis rails where about 3mm out across the vehicle. I am not entirely sure why, but I eventually managed to get the bolts in. I suspect it may have been partially due to the camber of the road. I&#39;ve used stainless bolts so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0095.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note on the cross member is that the cut out for the fuel hoses on my vehicle is in the wrong location. This probably varies from vehicle to vehicle. One was YRM could improve this is to have a wider cut out. I have added additional protection and will tywrap the hoses out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the crossmember was in it was time to start fitting the upstand/upriser. The new item is a different size to the old one. In a good way. The lips are about another 10mm deep. This means that around the top a certain amount of fitting is required, this is around the spars under the floor and the doubler between the separate sections of floor near the doors. I only cut out these areas, I like the idea of the extra depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new item seemed longer also, I did not have to cut it down. The reason is that the old panel was tapered making the top shorter than the bottom edge. I spaced it evenly each side and it seems ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0102.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fitting done, I have now dry fitted it, drilled the holes for the top rivets and will tomorrow drill the sides pieces and seat brackets. At the moment the rivets are all loose. I will strip it out and paint it once I have dry assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The floor is in with a couple of screws at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair continues</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130717-141934.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll need to forgive the posts at the moment, they are short and sweet. This is because I am under pressure and because I am feeling guilty about not posting, all I would like to on what has happened and what I want to happen. I am doing them on the run with the Wordpress app.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow an update on the floor repair of the landy. The second row floor is out. This was a bit of hassle as all the screws were seized. I have no power at the vehicle so a grinder was not an option. The up stand/ upriser is out and the mid cross member is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also cleaned up around the mid cross member mountings and put stone chip paint on it to give it some protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/img_0086.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand Corrosion Repair</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130715-194202.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promised to do some posts about our planned trip, which we are due to depart on in 11 days. As of now we have not even booked the channel tunnel crossing or got our international driving permits. We are cutting it fine this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo shows some horrible corrosion I needed to get fixed before we go. It is in the area of the second row seat brackets on the upstand. Fairly typical of what happens when you combine steel and aluminium. Electrolytic corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I am in the throws of stripping the floor and getting the panel out. The end caps were particularly hard due to a hidden solid rivet under the c post bracket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New panels are from YRM, I got the upstanding and end brackets from them. I also have a galvanised crossmember I am not sure if I will fit that yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to post more pictures as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130715-195412.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Warm Up and Last Minute Fuel Pump Change</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 08:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-30-may-2013-1644.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend we got lucky with the weather, mostly. We spent a couple of nights camping in Wales. On the way we decided we&amp;#039;d break the journey, by stopping the night at a pub that allows camping in their garden. So we stopped in Wiltshire at The Parish Lantern, highly recommended. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole journey avoided the motorways and took us through many little interesting towns and funny back roads, on the way back we managed to include a couple of green lanes near Salisbury and the Stone Henge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1518.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1536.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to departure, I thought I&amp;#039;d change the fuel filter, the Landy will get it&amp;#039;s service any day, but in the mean time I though that I&amp;#039;d do the filter because I felt it had been a bit sluggish when I had occasionally driven it over the winter. As you&amp;#039;d expect the filter was quick and easy to change. But.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems occurred during priming, I was not able to prime the filter with the lift pump handle. I though it may have been the position of the pump lever on the cam, flicking the engine over a few times did not improve that. I managed to get the engine started though after several attempts without the lift pump for assistance, then just to confirm my suspicion cracking the bleed screw on the filter housing did not give a stream of diesel. This in my eyes proved the lift pump was failed and that it was not pressurising the filter, etc. It was getting late on the night before we left at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I had a new genuine lift pump in my spares box complete with olives, nuts and gasket. I would have to make a decision. Live with it and fit a new one on return or fit the spare in the morning before we left. The problem is that I did not want to have a sluggish vehicle on a long journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the task seemed mostly simple I took the gamble to fit it in the morning. In the pouring rain. My only apprehension was that the bolts to the block interface plate could be seized. They were not, so after establishing that, I spent an hour and the problem was fixed. Pump on and decent pressure restored at the pump bleed screw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside of it all was that we got off earlier on our weekend trip and managed to have an early pint at the pub we stayed at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the annual trip approaching over the next couple of weeks, I have to get a service done on the Landy and fix the second row seat up riser corrosion which is a big job. For that I managed to get a galvanised mid cross member from YRM metal solutions together with the aluminium panels I need. I just hope I can get it all apart! I&amp;#039;ll keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>