<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Repair on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/repair/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Repair on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/tags/repair/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair done</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 17:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/24/upstand-repair-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130724-184907.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The landy is now back to normal the whole repair is done, seats are in soundproofing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we have the fun of packing for the trip. Sorry I did not take a picture of the finished article! But the picture above shows the first of three seats fitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must dash need to iron my pants.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upriser/Upstand in</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 16:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/20/upriserupstand-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not quite as far as I would have liked today. Missed the nut and bolt store. They close at 1400 on a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to get the Upstand and floor fitted and the two central seat brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130720-173701.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow when my drill is charged again, I&#39;ll get ready for the last two seat brackets, when I get the bolts on Monday they&#39;ll be fitted. I should also be able to refit the sound proofing tomorrow, that is the rubber chequer plate stuff from write off road. As sold to the MOD. I had not finished fitting it due to this repair, needing to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I am going for a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand Corrosion Repair</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/15/upstand-corrosion-repair/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130715-194202.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promised to do some posts about our planned trip, which we are due to depart on in 11 days. As of now we have not even booked the channel tunnel crossing or got our international driving permits. We are cutting it fine this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo shows some horrible corrosion I needed to get fixed before we go. It is in the area of the second row seat brackets on the upstand. Fairly typical of what happens when you combine steel and aluminium. Electrolytic corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I am in the throws of stripping the floor and getting the panel out. The end caps were particularly hard due to a hidden solid rivet under the c post bracket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New panels are from YRM, I got the upstanding and end brackets from them. I also have a galvanised crossmember I am not sure if I will fit that yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to post more pictures as I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://AfricanUhambo.github.io/assets/20130715-195412.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>