<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planning on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/planning/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planning on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirations for 2013&#39;s Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 19:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2013-1900.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as I mentioned earlier in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, we have been thinking about what we might do this summer. Actually we have been thinking since last summer. I guess we are probably not alone on this, we tend to think from trip to trip, from day to day, even during a trip. I guess most people who enjoy travelling have this problem. Is it wrong? I don&amp;#039;t want to wish my life away, but I love thinking about possibilities, getting the map out while drinking wine or beer in camp. Is that dreamin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us we have been to lots of places in Europe, we still have much of Northern Europe to go and places on our own door step such as Scotland and Ireland, but the weather makes life tricky in those places. We don&amp;#039;t want to be confined, confined to a hotel. We want the option to camp, we like camping. No we are not poor, we just like to get away from it. I camp in hotels all year for work, I really don&amp;#039;t like it. So I guess sooner or later we need to take the plunge and face the weather, before we loose the opportunity to see the places we take for granted on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we have been thinking about travel this August. Unfortunately during tourist season, we are bound to this because of school holidays, we tend to get away lightly due to the places we visit, not always. Our plans have been a little hampered this year, domestics are getting in the way! We had to have the kitchen done... I guess you are wondering what the hell I am on. Well it is all about economics. The kitchen cost a fortune (it is still not finished). This has hampered our trip money saving ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this has meant that, although we have &amp;#039;planned&amp;#039;, the plan is more of an &amp;#039;aspiration&amp;#039;. Let me explain. I guess what we are saying is that, we refuse to give up the opportunity of our annual trip. Regardless of how far we have saved, we&amp;#039;ll see how far we can go on what we&amp;#039;ve got! So if we don&amp;#039;t know what we will be able to do we should plan for what we&amp;#039;d like to do. So I guess you&amp;#039;d say plan for your aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that explained. We&amp;#039;d like this year to explore some more dirt roads in the Alps, there is a warren up there and plenty of places to wild camp without having to part with Euros. After that we&amp;#039;d also like to explore Kosovo, Albania and Macedonia. These are completely new to us and potentially very exciting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-may-2013-2022.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we get from the Alps to Albania and the surrounding areas, would either be by road or by sea. We used a ferry last year from Bari to Croatia which made life very easy, but expensive. The easiest ferry option for Albania is from Ancona to Durrës. This costs circa €400 but saves probably about three days in raw driving, that is really more because we stop and take a non direct route. The ferry crossing is around 20 hours. The saving is definitely not in fuel, even in a Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of getting to Albania from Ancona, is that we can use the days saved to spend more time exploring before heading back, it is probably about 1500 miles (2600 km) to Brighton from there. Which would be about 7 days driving, we&amp;#039;d need to allow about 10 so we could chill a bit. This would leave us about 2 weeks in the area we want to be. In reality I&amp;#039;d hope to be able to build some of the return days into the route to allow us to look at possibly Kosovo, Montenegro and Bosnia and Herzegovina a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks we&amp;#039;ll be looking at every country we aspire to visit this year and posting a bit about sites and areas that have caught our attention. This will hopefully culminate with a rough route plan. Hopefully we&amp;#039;ll be able to research some more Alps routes too. So stay tuned if you want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready for the Summer</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 17:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-26-may-2013-1303.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the weather getting better and a short camping trip planned for next weekend, we decided this weekend was probably the most sensible time to get the tent on the Landy and the awning set up, ready for opportunities to go camping and the summer trip. The other good thing given that this weekend is a bank holiday is that next weekend should be quieter! The roads and transport systems in the UK just can&amp;#039;t cope when we all decide to move in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a friend giving me a lift getting the roof tent on was a breeze. This year, I have made some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first. The tent is mounted about 6 or 8 inches further forward. This I am hoping will make the car feel a little more stable, while still allowing the rear door to open easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second tweak, was to fit some locating pegs to the back of the tent to remedy the problem I mentioned in this blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that caused the base to sag and create an uncomfortable step. I&amp;#039;ll write about that further &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/&#34;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually we also made a third tweak. That was to create some drain holes in the lower side of the tent cover. We noticed when we removed the tent last year that we had some water sitting in the bottom of the cover. These holes should allow moisture to be dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to another thing I should mention. We have been working on ideas for the summer, we intend this year to again go on a &amp;#039;Big&amp;#039; trip. Note that I say ideas and not planning or plans. Why? Well we are not sure if our aspirations will match our plans. We had to have some house work done this year that cost a small fortune. We&amp;#039;ll reveal more in the near future on the trip though. So stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit to the Map Shop - Stanfords</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 18:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/image.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves at a loose end this morning, the weather was iffy. So we took a pleasant ride into London for a wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are considering are plans for the summer so decided we&#39;d pop to the map shop in London. Those of you who don&#39;t know it. This is probably the best place to purchase maps and travel books in London. It has three floors of books and maps normally in the scale you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a Bradt Albania Guide, a 1:150k Kosovo map, 1:200k Albania map, 1:400 Bulgaria map and 1:500k Romania / Moldova map, the latter two are not ideal scales for what we need but they&#39;ll do. I&#39;ll probably get better scales if I can find them. Unfortunately I could not find a decent Macedonia map so had to resort to Amazon for that and a Kosovo and Macedonia guide book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance you should pop in, it is a pretty cool shop!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2012 - &#34;what to do?&#34;</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/summer-2012-what-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 20:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/summer-2012-what-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; This year, Wendy&amp;#039;s Biological Parents are flying over from Australia to join us for our Summer trip across Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have decided on 3 places that we will definitely stop at, Paris, Venice and Pisa. Keeping these in mind, we planned a rough route for this years trip.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-1-jul-2012-2055.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;437&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a route is all fine and well, but Carole and Daniel need transport. Do they hire or purchase?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we looked into hiring a car, we considered all types of cars. Essentially, as we wanted to go on a few off road routes, a 4x4 would be best suited. Hiring a car would cost anything upwards of £3k. The price got steeper because we were not simply going to Western Europe, we also wanted to go to Montenegro and Croatia, which is outside Europe. This increased the insurance price on the hire. The other insurance raising aspect was Carole &amp;amp; Daniel having an Australian drivers licence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would it not be better to purchase a car and sell it after the holiday? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could we insure a car for them if they bought one? So we started with insurance. We found only a handful of insurers would insure someone on a foreign licence, specifically an Australian licence. Direct Line, Norwich Union and a few short term insurance brokers were the only insurers that we found who would add a foreign licence onto a plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Now we know that it&amp;#039;s possible to insure them, we need to find a car!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were a little anxious as buying a car for someone else is a difficult task...what if something goes wrong with the car while we are away? And so we looked at everything from a Toyota Hilux to a Mitsubishi Pajero. The later being the car we finally decided upon and purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-7-jul-2012-1533.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Pajero&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not all plain sailing, we experienced some insurance issues. First Wendy&amp;#039;s no claims came into question, then terms and conitions were changed and foreign licences no longer covered. This ended up in us having to cancel 2 policies and take out short term insurance to cover us during the holiday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transport organised and so we moved onto the smaller items on the agenda. We will still be camping, and as we have many tents, Carole and Daniel will be using our &amp;#039;family&amp;#039; sized tent and have Cassie in with them. Dan and I will sleep in our 2 man tent. We will need camping mats, camp chairs and all the car requirements for driving in the European countries: triangle, high vis jackets, breatherliser, and fire extinguisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with organising equipment for people coming from another country, we identified some extra things that we require this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, we decided to purchase a roof tent. After much research by Dan, we settled on a tent from MyWay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-21-jul-2012-1525.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also purchased more boxes and a hi-lift jack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-7-jul-2012-2040.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;666&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-17-jul-2012-0751.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;666&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; All that&amp;#039;s left now is to count down till Carole and Daniel arrive and we can start our holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys Locked in - The Frostfire Mooncode 1555 Portable Key Storage</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/24/keys-locked-in-the-frostfire-mooncode-1555-portable-key-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 20:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/24/keys-locked-in-the-frostfire-mooncode-1555-portable-key-storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-20-may-2012-0855.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;285&#34; alt=&#34;Frostfire Mooncode 1555&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you have read about our trip last year, you will know that we locked the keys in the Landy in Croatia. We normally have at least a door key on us each, in order to try and prevent this situation. However it was quite late in the holiday and the inevitable happened. Both doors slam, I see the keys swinging in the ignition. I can also see Wendy&amp;#039;s bag on the passenger floor. Just to confirm, I ask where her keys are. My suspicion is confirmed!...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been saying every year we must do something about this. But what do you do? Leaving a key stashed is tricky and potentially easy to find, added to that most solutions are magnetic, which is useless on a landy. I wanted something of a more robust and secure nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While browsing the net I came across the Mooncode key safe, which is an oversized padlock shaped device with a combination code to open. The body has space sufficient to allow stashing of a key and bank card. The padlock mechanism would allow it to be locked to the landy. The device looked ideal. I ordered one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way I will say now, this will only be used while we are away. I have no intention of leaving it fitted or broadcasting where it is fitted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-24-may-2011-1227.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;256&#34; alt=&#34;Closed Mooncode Key Safe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On arrival I was keen to check out the new toy, first impression was that it is fairly robust and heavy device, the padlock clasp is covered in transparent rubber to help prevent it rattling, the rear of the body is covered in fairly heavy duty rubber foam, both of these also help protect car paint work. In my case it will help prevent the rattling in the eventual stowage location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to release the clasp of the padlock you have to know the code, this is a good feature. The release mechanism is internal to Moodcode&amp;#039;s body. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-24-may-2011-12271.jpg?w=441&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;441&#34; height=&#34;251&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that would be an improvement, is if the Moodcode was waterproof. The body will prevent splashes and light rain entering the chamber that contains the keys etc, by the shape of the closing edges, the inside and outside edges overlap but will not prevent water ingress. I did wonder if I could seal it with some stick rubber strip, I&amp;#039;ll have a play sometime on that one. Obviously for the use of overlanders and 4wd&amp;#039;s it would be much better If waterproof. If the manufacturers considered this they would also need to consider the code wheels and mechanism as I am sure this would not take long to suffer from dust ingress and seize up. I think to help it survive the latter it will have the code wheels taped up in situ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not decide where it will go yet. We&amp;#039;ll let you know how it survives the holiday this year. Have any of you got a decent solution to locking your keys in the car?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Books for Travel and Planning</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/17/useful-books-for-travel-and-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 16:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/17/useful-books-for-travel-and-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-15-apr-2012-2218.jpg?w=234&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;234&#34; height=&#34;308&#34; alt=&#34;Unesco World Heritage Sites&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Over the last few years we have read and used various travel related books. Some have been good, some have been great and some we just did not get on with. This may not mean they are bad, it is just that certain types of writing suits certain people better than others. A good example of this is in travel guides, we tend to prefer Bradt guides over Lonely planet. Most people swear by Lonely Planet guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of our most frequently used books is the UNESCO World Heritage site guide, it is a massive book with loads of superb pictures a page or two on each site, not all sites have a photo though, it would be nice if they all did and were at least a page in size, perhaps in the next release? At the beginning of the book are nice maps on several pages showing all the site locations and page numbers, these form a nice geographical index. In the back is a compressive index of each site together with a handy index by country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1060012.JPG&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; height=&#34;249&#34; alt=&#34;Look out for our book!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This is actually our second copy. We think we lost the first in a vineyard in Portugal somewhere, when we were exploring off road. In case you are in the area, I think this is where it was! Near the bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We find this book is excellent when we are musing over ideas with our Michelin 1:1,000,000 Europe map for instance. It allows you to get an idea of what is enroute. Just beware after a few beers plans can get somewhat over enthusiastic! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-22231.jpg?w=128&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;197&#34; alt=&#34;Europe on a shoestring&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having said we prefer Bradt guides, which was actually a fairly late discovery. We do have a fair few Lonely planet guides and one we keep referring to is Europe on a shoestring. It seems to make it into the car every year. At over five years old it is not only getting out of date but also somewhat dog eared. If  you want a handy general guide this is one to have, if you need more detail, grab a specific guide for the country or preferably the area you want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What this book does well is gives you ideas of itineraries, budgets and key things or places to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2229.jpg?w=207&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;207&#34; height=&#34;273&#34; alt=&#34;No doctor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;For medical questions and some things you would rather not waste the doctor&amp;#039;s time with, we have often referred to Where There Is No Doctor. Horribly detailed and super useful, this one lives in the Landy. It is not really a first aid book, more of a Haynes manual for you body. If you are squeamish at the best of times look away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was very luck to get a good tip for purchasing my copy of Tom Sheppard&amp;#039;s book the Vehicle Dependent Expedition Guide. When I was looking I was shocked at the prices. When you have read the book you will understand why they command such a price. The level of detail is astonishing and will leave any other book on the topic standing in its shadow. The tip I got was to phone the Royal Geographic Society to purchase a discounted copy from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2240.jpg?w=189&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;189&#34; height=&#34;258&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I am still reading Tom&amp;#039;s book to this day, it lives beside my bed. The reason is that it is a good reference and I don&amp;#039;t think a cover to cover type read. You need to take your time to absorb the topics in this book. The devil is most definitely in the detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This book will answer all the questions you have from logging your trip in detail, maintenance of your vehicle to the type of sleeping arrangement you want. If you can think of a vehicle related question, the answer is probably in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Definitely a good book to start reading and referring to during what ever you are planning for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2255.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;273&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since I purchased this book I have also read another of Tom&amp;#039;s books called Quiet for a Tuesday. This book you should buy even if you only plan to look at the photos! It is an account of Tom&amp;#039;s trip to Algeria, where he had all his maps confiscated by officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily thanks to his insanely methodical record keeping, Tom managed to navigate and enjoy his journey in the Algerian Sahara. Whilst avoiding the authorities!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;He finds out during his covert travels whilst trying to recover the maps with the help of contacts back home, that the Authorities most definitely do not want him to stay! So having acknowledged this will probably be his last trip in Algeria he makes the most of the journey. Which will probably end up in him being banned from Algeria, due to a misunderstanding, which is exactly what happened in Libya.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to know when Google Maps updates occur?</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/14/want-to-know-when-google-maps-updates-occur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 14:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/14/want-to-know-when-google-maps-updates-occur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doing my usual this morning browsing the threads on Horizons Unlimited, I spotted a thread that is about a new Google maps update notification service, which is something I have longed for, for a long time. This new service from Google will alter you when maps are updated in an area you choose. It is called &#34;Follow Your World&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20120414-150528.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; alt=&#34;20120414-150528.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a regular gmaps user you are likely to have spotted that there is still quite a bit that still needs to be &#34;done&#34;. Last year I noticed that Bosnia and Herzegovina was missing detail of the road routing for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://followyourworld.appspot.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HUBB thread can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/route-planning/google-earth-map-updates-notifier-63719&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>