<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planning on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/categories/planning/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planning on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/africanuhambo.github.io/categories/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albania Off Road Guide</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/17/albania-off-road-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/17/albania-off-road-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130717-140602.jpg&#34;&gt;
I have been in touch by chance via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/&#34;&gt;Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; with a chap called Matthew over the last few months. He is planning on travelling to Albania at a similar time to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway via Matthew I have found this book which I thought I would recommend, about routes in Albania.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I like the book is that it not only takes off road, but also cover sites to see on route. One nice feature of the book is that the Author attempts to give you an idea of difficulty and what vehicles the route was covered in.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition there is a decent section on cuisine and the differences between regions and a small section on language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bebaweb.cz/albania-offroad-guide.php&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It was about 19 euro delivered to the UK and took a couple of days to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the back of the book so you can see it and the isbn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130717-140758.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirations for 2013&#39;s Trip</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 19:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2013-1900.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as I mentioned earlier in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, we have been thinking about what we might do this summer. Actually we have been thinking since last summer. I guess we are probably not alone on this, we tend to think from trip to trip, from day to day, even during a trip. I guess most people who enjoy travelling have this problem. Is it wrong? I don&amp;#039;t want to wish my life away, but I love thinking about possibilities, getting the map out while drinking wine or beer in camp. Is that dreamin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us we have been to lots of places in Europe, we still have much of Northern Europe to go and places on our own door step such as Scotland and Ireland, but the weather makes life tricky in those places. We don&amp;#039;t want to be confined, confined to a hotel. We want the option to camp, we like camping. No we are not poor, we just like to get away from it. I camp in hotels all year for work, I really don&amp;#039;t like it. So I guess sooner or later we need to take the plunge and face the weather, before we loose the opportunity to see the places we take for granted on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we have been thinking about travel this August. Unfortunately during tourist season, we are bound to this because of school holidays, we tend to get away lightly due to the places we visit, not always. Our plans have been a little hampered this year, domestics are getting in the way! We had to have the kitchen done... I guess you are wondering what the hell I am on. Well it is all about economics. The kitchen cost a fortune (it is still not finished). This has hampered our trip money saving ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this has meant that, although we have &amp;#039;planned&amp;#039;, the plan is more of an &amp;#039;aspiration&amp;#039;. Let me explain. I guess what we are saying is that, we refuse to give up the opportunity of our annual trip. Regardless of how far we have saved, we&amp;#039;ll see how far we can go on what we&amp;#039;ve got! So if we don&amp;#039;t know what we will be able to do we should plan for what we&amp;#039;d like to do. So I guess you&amp;#039;d say plan for your aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that explained. We&amp;#039;d like this year to explore some more dirt roads in the Alps, there is a warren up there and plenty of places to wild camp without having to part with Euros. After that we&amp;#039;d also like to explore Kosovo, Albania and Macedonia. These are completely new to us and potentially very exciting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-may-2013-2022.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we get from the Alps to Albania and the surrounding areas, would either be by road or by sea. We used a ferry last year from Bari to Croatia which made life very easy, but expensive. The easiest ferry option for Albania is from Ancona to Durrës. This costs circa €400 but saves probably about three days in raw driving, that is really more because we stop and take a non direct route. The ferry crossing is around 20 hours. The saving is definitely not in fuel, even in a Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of getting to Albania from Ancona, is that we can use the days saved to spend more time exploring before heading back, it is probably about 1500 miles (2600 km) to Brighton from there. Which would be about 7 days driving, we&amp;#039;d need to allow about 10 so we could chill a bit. This would leave us about 2 weeks in the area we want to be. In reality I&amp;#039;d hope to be able to build some of the return days into the route to allow us to look at possibly Kosovo, Montenegro and Bosnia and Herzegovina a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks we&amp;#039;ll be looking at every country we aspire to visit this year and posting a bit about sites and areas that have caught our attention. This will hopefully culminate with a rough route plan. Hopefully we&amp;#039;ll be able to research some more Alps routes too. So stay tuned if you want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready for the Summer</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 17:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-26-may-2013-1303.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the weather getting better and a short camping trip planned for next weekend, we decided this weekend was probably the most sensible time to get the tent on the Landy and the awning set up, ready for opportunities to go camping and the summer trip. The other good thing given that this weekend is a bank holiday is that next weekend should be quieter! The roads and transport systems in the UK just can&amp;#039;t cope when we all decide to move in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a friend giving me a lift getting the roof tent on was a breeze. This year, I have made some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first. The tent is mounted about 6 or 8 inches further forward. This I am hoping will make the car feel a little more stable, while still allowing the rear door to open easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second tweak, was to fit some locating pegs to the back of the tent to remedy the problem I mentioned in this blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/09/04/myway-serengeti-1-6m-roof-tent-boab-roof-bars/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; that caused the base to sag and create an uncomfortable step. I&amp;#039;ll write about that further &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/27/myway-serengeti-modifications/&#34;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually we also made a third tweak. That was to create some drain holes in the lower side of the tent cover. We noticed when we removed the tent last year that we had some water sitting in the bottom of the cover. These holes should allow moisture to be dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This leads to another thing I should mention. We have been working on ideas for the summer, we intend this year to again go on a &amp;#039;Big&amp;#039; trip. Note that I say ideas and not planning or plans. Why? Well we are not sure if our aspirations will match our plans. We had to have some house work done this year that cost a small fortune. We&amp;#039;ll reveal more in the near future on the trip though. So stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 09:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastlane99.plus.com/&#34;&gt;Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just found this link via a reply to a &lt;a title=&#34;HUBB&#34; href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/europe/familly-friendly-4x4-tours-alps-70380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post on Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;. If your looking at exploring the tracks of the Alps. There some nice pictures on here from the early 2000&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit to the Map Shop - Stanfords</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 18:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/27/a-visit-to-the-map-shop-stanfords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/image.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves at a loose end this morning, the weather was iffy. So we took a pleasant ride into London for a wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are considering are plans for the summer so decided we&#39;d pop to the map shop in London. Those of you who don&#39;t know it. This is probably the best place to purchase maps and travel books in London. It has three floors of books and maps normally in the scale you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a Bradt Albania Guide, a 1:150k Kosovo map, 1:200k Albania map, 1:400 Bulgaria map and 1:500k Romania / Moldova map, the latter two are not ideal scales for what we need but they&#39;ll do. I&#39;ll probably get better scales if I can find them. Unfortunately I could not find a decent Macedonia map so had to resort to Amazon for that and a Kosovo and Macedonia guide book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance you should pop in, it is a pretty cool shop!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful maps for exploring the Maritime Alps</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2013/04/19/useful-maps-for-exploring-the-maritime-alps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; If your planning on exploring the tracks around the Maritime Alps on the French / Italian border, you&amp;#039;ll need a few maps of the area. The best single retailer for maps in the UK is Stanford maps in London. They have three floors of travel books and maps. This is where I got our maps months prior to departing. Of course you can try online also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#039;t have to buy the maps before you leave, they are sold locally in France. You will need something with some detail though, equivalent to the UK Ordnance Survey (OS) map, which is 1:25k or 1:50k depending on the series you go for. In France the equivalent is the Institut Geographique National (IGN) they do a 1:25k map series which covers the whole of France. Where ever you go in France you can normally by IGN maps of the local area. So you could buy on arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the IGN maps, we also used the Italian equivalent as we found the IGN maps loose detail on shortly after the border. These maps are Istituto Geografico Centrale (IGC). At Stanfords they had these in 1:50k. They have a slightly vintage feel in the style of printing, but they are very clear. Interestingly they also show prohibited routes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I should also mention is that Garmin maps have a lot of the tracks we used, well certainly in the European City Navigator 2012. Not all though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1320.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Here are some pictures of the maps we used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 8 Alpi Marittime E Liguri (ISBN 9788896455081)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGC 1 Valli Di Susi Chisone E Germanasca (ISBN 9788896455012)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3841 OT Vallée De La Roya, Vallée Des Merveilles, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 3282113841030)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IGN 3741 ET Vallées De La Bévéra Et Des Paillons, Parc National Du Mercantour (ISBN 9782758524083)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-1319.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-2129.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And in case you are interested the back of the first one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-23-sep-2012-13191.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2012 - &#34;what to do?&#34;</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/08/summer-2012-what-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 20:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/07/08/summer-2012-what-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; This year, Wendy&amp;#039;s Biological Parents are flying over from Australia to join us for our Summer trip across Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have decided on 3 places that we will definitely stop at, Paris, Venice and Pisa. Keeping these in mind, we planned a rough route for this years trip.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-1-jul-2012-2055.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;437&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a route is all fine and well, but Carole and Daniel need transport. Do they hire or purchase?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we looked into hiring a car, we considered all types of cars. Essentially, as we wanted to go on a few off road routes, a 4x4 would be best suited. Hiring a car would cost anything upwards of £3k. The price got steeper because we were not simply going to Western Europe, we also wanted to go to Montenegro and Croatia, which is outside Europe. This increased the insurance price on the hire. The other insurance raising aspect was Carole &amp;amp; Daniel having an Australian drivers licence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would it not be better to purchase a car and sell it after the holiday? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could we insure a car for them if they bought one? So we started with insurance. We found only a handful of insurers would insure someone on a foreign licence, specifically an Australian licence. Direct Line, Norwich Union and a few short term insurance brokers were the only insurers that we found who would add a foreign licence onto a plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Now we know that it&amp;#039;s possible to insure them, we need to find a car!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were a little anxious as buying a car for someone else is a difficult task...what if something goes wrong with the car while we are away? And so we looked at everything from a Toyota Hilux to a Mitsubishi Pajero. The later being the car we finally decided upon and purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-jul-2012-1533.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Pajero&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not all plain sailing, we experienced some insurance issues. First Wendy&amp;#039;s no claims came into question, then terms and conitions were changed and foreign licences no longer covered. This ended up in us having to cancel 2 policies and take out short term insurance to cover us during the holiday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transport organised and so we moved onto the smaller items on the agenda. We will still be camping, and as we have many tents, Carole and Daniel will be using our &amp;#039;family&amp;#039; sized tent and have Cassie in with them. Dan and I will sleep in our 2 man tent. We will need camping mats, camp chairs and all the car requirements for driving in the European countries: triangle, high vis jackets, breatherliser, and fire extinguisher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with organising equipment for people coming from another country, we identified some extra things that we require this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off, we decided to purchase a roof tent. After much research by Dan, we settled on a tent from MyWay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-21-jul-2012-1525.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also purchased more boxes and a hi-lift jack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-7-jul-2012-2040.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;666&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-17-jul-2012-0751.jpg?w=500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;666&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; All that&amp;#039;s left now is to count down till Carole and Daniel arrive and we can start our holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Books for Travel and Planning</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/17/useful-books-for-travel-and-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 16:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/17/useful-books-for-travel-and-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-15-apr-2012-2218.jpg?w=234&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;234&#34; height=&#34;308&#34; alt=&#34;Unesco World Heritage Sites&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Over the last few years we have read and used various travel related books. Some have been good, some have been great and some we just did not get on with. This may not mean they are bad, it is just that certain types of writing suits certain people better than others. A good example of this is in travel guides, we tend to prefer Bradt guides over Lonely planet. Most people swear by Lonely Planet guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;One of our most frequently used books is the UNESCO World Heritage site guide, it is a massive book with loads of superb pictures a page or two on each site, not all sites have a photo though, it would be nice if they all did and were at least a page in size, perhaps in the next release? At the beginning of the book are nice maps on several pages showing all the site locations and page numbers, these form a nice geographical index. In the back is a compressive index of each site together with a handy index by country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/P1060012.JPG&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; height=&#34;249&#34; alt=&#34;Look out for our book!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This is actually our second copy. We think we lost the first in a vineyard in Portugal somewhere, when we were exploring off road. In case you are in the area, I think this is where it was! Near the bench.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We find this book is excellent when we are musing over ideas with our Michelin 1:1,000,000 Europe map for instance. It allows you to get an idea of what is enroute. Just beware after a few beers plans can get somewhat over enthusiastic! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-22231.jpg?w=128&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;197&#34; alt=&#34;Europe on a shoestring&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Having said we prefer Bradt guides, which was actually a fairly late discovery. We do have a fair few Lonely planet guides and one we keep referring to is Europe on a shoestring. It seems to make it into the car every year. At over five years old it is not only getting out of date but also somewhat dog eared. If  you want a handy general guide this is one to have, if you need more detail, grab a specific guide for the country or preferably the area you want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;What this book does well is gives you ideas of itineraries, budgets and key things or places to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2229.jpg?w=207&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;207&#34; height=&#34;273&#34; alt=&#34;No doctor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;For medical questions and some things you would rather not waste the doctor&amp;#039;s time with, we have often referred to Where There Is No Doctor. Horribly detailed and super useful, this one lives in the Landy. It is not really a first aid book, more of a Haynes manual for you body. If you are squeamish at the best of times look away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I was very luck to get a good tip for purchasing my copy of Tom Sheppard&amp;#039;s book the Vehicle Dependent Expedition Guide. When I was looking I was shocked at the prices. When you have read the book you will understand why they command such a price. The level of detail is astonishing and will leave any other book on the topic standing in its shadow. The tip I got was to phone the Royal Geographic Society to purchase a discounted copy from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2240.jpg?w=189&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;189&#34; height=&#34;258&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I am still reading Tom&amp;#039;s book to this day, it lives beside my bed. The reason is that it is a good reference and I don&amp;#039;t think a cover to cover type read. You need to take your time to absorb the topics in this book. The devil is most definitely in the detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This book will answer all the questions you have from logging your trip in detail, maintenance of your vehicle to the type of sleeping arrangement you want. If you can think of a vehicle related question, the answer is probably in here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Definitely a good book to start reading and referring to during what ever you are planning for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-16-apr-2012-2255.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;210&#34; height=&#34;273&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Since I purchased this book I have also read another of Tom&amp;#039;s books called Quiet for a Tuesday. This book you should buy even if you only plan to look at the photos! It is an account of Tom&amp;#039;s trip to Algeria, where he had all his maps confiscated by officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Luckily thanks to his insanely methodical record keeping, Tom managed to navigate and enjoy his journey in the Algerian Sahara. Whilst avoiding the authorities!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;sites-canvas-main&#34; style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;He finds out during his covert travels whilst trying to recover the maps with the help of contacts back home, that the Authorities most definitely do not want him to stay! So having acknowledged this will probably be his last trip in Algeria he makes the most of the journey. Which will probably end up in him being banned from Algeria, due to a misunderstanding, which is exactly what happened in Libya.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to know when Google Maps updates occur?</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/14/want-to-know-when-google-maps-updates-occur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 14:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/14/want-to-know-when-google-maps-updates-occur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doing my usual this morning browsing the threads on Horizons Unlimited, I spotted a thread that is about a new Google maps update notification service, which is something I have longed for, for a long time. This new service from Google will alter you when maps are updated in an area you choose. It is called &#34;Follow Your World&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20120414-150528.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; alt=&#34;20120414-150528.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a regular gmaps user you are likely to have spotted that there is still quite a bit that still needs to be &#34;done&#34;. Last year I noticed that Bosnia and Herzegovina was missing detail of the road routing for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://followyourworld.appspot.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The HUBB thread can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/route-planning/google-earth-map-updates-notifier-63719&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big One - Plan A in 2007, which was the original plan!</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/19/the-big-one-plan-a-in-2007-which-was-the-original-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 20:17:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/03/19/the-big-one-plan-a-in-2007-which-was-the-original-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;Oh how plans change!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;Our original plan to go on a long overland trip, started all the way back in 2007, our plan at the time was to sell the flat and do the trip. Back then we had planned on doing the classic Eastern route of Africa. Had we done the trip we would have been back by now and probably settled back into working life. But life has ways of changing plans that we cannot really explain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;Below is a an extract from the web page we wrote back then, that outlines what our plan was. This is only really for historical purposes and provides an insight to our thoughts at the time. Please forgive us if the style or layout of writing is poor. We have removed the graphics also.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;-———————&lt;/span&gt;———————————————————————&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;On the way to Cape Town these are the countries we plan to cross:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;Obviously our route is flexible and plans might, or should I say, they probably will, change depending on situations and advice as we travel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;UK - &lt;/span&gt;Here we plan to stop off at family to say our goodbyes, etc. Firstly at Wendy&amp;#039;s parents in &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Upper Heyford, Oxfordshire&lt;/span&gt;. Secondly onto Dan&amp;#039;s Mother&amp;#039;s in &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Pentre, Wales&lt;/span&gt;. Catching a ferry across to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Jersey, Channel Islands&lt;/span&gt; to see Dan&amp;#039;s Grandmother.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;FRANCE - &lt;/span&gt;Here we plan to stop in &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Saint Jean D&amp;#039;Aulps&lt;/span&gt; to visit Dan&amp;#039;s sister Anna.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt; ITALY - &lt;/span&gt;Here we plan to stop at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Lake Como&lt;/span&gt; (not sure the weather will be nice for lake side exploring and watersports at this time of the year though). &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Lake Garda, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Pisa and f&lt;/span&gt;inally &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Ancona&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt; for our ferry crossing to Greece.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;GREECE - We arrive at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Igoumenitsa&lt;/span&gt; on the ferry and from here we will go to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Ionnina&lt;/span&gt; to see the Zagoria Villages, Papingo rock pools etc. Then onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Meteora&lt;/span&gt; to see the rock monastaries. We then move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Mount Olympus&lt;/span&gt; to contemplate climbing it or just relaxing at a nearby camp. From Mount Olympus we move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Thessaloniki&lt;/span&gt; for more sites such as Vergina and Pella. From Thessaloniki we go to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Chalkidiki - Kalamitsi&lt;/span&gt; for a few days relaxing on greek beaches. After a few days on the beach it will be time to move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Kavala&lt;/span&gt; for more beach and sun. Hopefully relaxed from the travel done so far and raring to move on we will go into the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Dadia Forest Reserve&lt;/span&gt; for some local wildlife and birdlife spotting. From there we will go onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Soufli&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt; to see the silk museum and cross into Turkey.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;TURKEY - &lt;/span&gt;We will enter Turkey via &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Ipsala&lt;/span&gt; and go straight onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Istanbul&lt;/span&gt;. Here we will visit the many souqs etc. From Istanbul we will go to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Canakkale&lt;/span&gt; to see Troy and the Gallipoli battle heads. Our next stop is &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Selcuk&lt;/span&gt; for the Ephesus and Hierapolis Ruins. Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Fethiye&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Oludeniz&lt;/span&gt; for more beach bumming and watersports for Dan. A visit to the butterfly valley at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Faralaya&lt;/span&gt;. A look at the &amp;#039;sleeping man&amp;#039; mountain and monument tombs at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Kas&lt;/span&gt;. We will then visit the famous beach ree house camp at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Mount Olympos&lt;/span&gt;, maybe climb it? Moving onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Antalya&lt;/span&gt; to see the Laleici quarter with spectacular views of the Bey Mountains. Also to see Antalya&amp;#039;s many tombs and monuments. From Antalya to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Goreme&lt;/span&gt; to see the famous &amp;#039;fairy towers&amp;#039; and rock churches. Also for a wonder in the underground city. We plan to visit the Black Sea stoping along the way at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Amasya&lt;/span&gt;. A town in a ravine bisected by a river and has beautiful architecture and rock hewn tombs.A stop at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Giresun&lt;/span&gt;, a place well known for its cherries, hazelnuts and fine cuisine. Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Kahta&lt;/span&gt; to see the fallen heads of Nemrutdagi. We cross the border at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Akcakale&lt;/span&gt; into Syria.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;SYRIA - &lt;/span&gt;First stop in Syria is &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Aleppo&lt;/span&gt; for more souqs, ruins, food and a visit to Apamea, the sandstone city and mosaic museum. After Aleppo we head towards &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Hama&lt;/span&gt;. Hear we shall see the majestic water wheels groaning their sad song thorugh the town. &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Homs&lt;/span&gt; is our next stop. This will be a base to go and visit Crac des Chevaliers, the magical castle. It&amp;#039;s onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Palmyra&lt;/span&gt; next to visit some more clasiscal ruins. From Palmyra we travel to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Damascus&lt;/span&gt;. That biblical town to see the old city and it&amp;#039;s souqs, carpet shops and coffee shops. All the time trying to avoid the lure of the barterers. Maybe visit a hammam and see a few mosques. We cross the border into Jordan at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Nasib&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;JORDAN&lt;/span&gt; - Straight onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Amman&lt;/span&gt; for day trips to Pella, Bethany Beyond Jordan and many more biblical sights. After Amman we head for &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Wadi Mujib Nature Reserve&lt;/span&gt;. Here we can experence extreme nature with gorge rock slides/canyons and a good float in the Dead Sea. It&amp;#039;s onto the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Dana Nature Reserve&lt;/span&gt; after Wadi Mujib. Here again we can experience local wildlife and birdlife. A little relax. From there we head for &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Madi Musa&lt;/span&gt; to see the breathtaking site of Petra, the red rock monuments. Madi Musa to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Wadi Rum&lt;/span&gt; for more breathtaking desert sceneray and first experience of desert driving etc. At &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Aqaba&lt;/span&gt; we will catch a ferry to Egypt. The only crossing into Egypt from Jordan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;EGYPT - &lt;/span&gt;Egypt&amp;#039;s first stop will be &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Dahab&lt;/span&gt;. Here we will have a well earned rest and beach &amp;#039;holiday&amp;#039;. We will hopefully take in some snorkelling and watersports (for Dan of course). A trip to the well known Ras Mohammed National Park for their reefs and marine life. Dahab onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;St Katherine&amp;#039;s Monestary.&lt;/span&gt; Maybe a climb of Mt Sinai? Then it&amp;#039;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Wadi Feiran&lt;/span&gt; to see the biblical and historical point at which Moses struck the rock to create water for his poeple. A visit to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Hammam Fara&amp;#039;un&lt;/span&gt; to sip into their hot springs and visit their beaches. Then it&amp;#039;s time to do a bit of ship spotting in &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Suez.&lt;/span&gt; Suez to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Alexandria&lt;/span&gt;. Here we can see the Roman Museum and the Roman Amphitheatre. A taste of Egyptian cities before heading off to Cairo. In &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Cairo&lt;/span&gt; we will do stocking up and visit the pyramids, Giza, take a felucca ride. Do neccessary paperwork suh as visas etc. Take Cassie to Cairo Zoo and Al-Azhar Park. We will hopefully be able to go out along to the famous &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Siwa Oasis&lt;/span&gt;, temperature permitting. For a bit of desert driving and bush camping. From here we will head back to the Nile stopping at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Bahariyya Oasis&lt;/span&gt;. See a few more ruins, temples and tombs. A bit more desert driving and bush camping. We hit th Nile again and the town of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Minya&lt;/span&gt;. A quick stop before carrying on down the Nile. Minya to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Luxor &lt;/span&gt;and expecting our first convoy. In Luxor we will see the temples, Valley of the Kings and so forth. We will then head off to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Aswan&lt;/span&gt; in another convoy to relax a little before the hard going in Sudan. Do some shopping and see a few more sights. Here we will catch the ferry to Sudan.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;SUDAN - Arriving in &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Wadi Halfa&lt;/span&gt; we may need to wait for the car to pull into port. This may mean a nights stop or more depending on the relaxed scheduling we may find here. We will continue to travel down along the Nile to reach Khartoum. This will mean a few bush camps and perhaps a stop at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Dongola&lt;/span&gt; as it has been praised as a friendly and relaxed stopover. &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Khartoum&lt;/span&gt;. Here we will hopefully see some whirling dervishes. See the point where the two Niles meet, go to some more souqs and experience the great Sudanese hospitality. From here we will head towards the border crossing at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Gallabat&lt;/span&gt; for Ethiopia. Stopping along the way at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Wad Medani&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Gedaref&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;ETHIOPIA - From entering the border at Metema, we will travel onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Gonder.&lt;/span&gt;It will then be gonder to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Lalibela&lt;/span&gt; where we will see the rock hewn churches and the Simien Mountains. A turn back in the direction we came from and head off to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Bahar Dar&lt;/span&gt; to see Lake Tana and the Blue Nile Falls. From here we will travel down to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Addis Ababa&lt;/span&gt; to sample its many charms and catch up on some shopping and car maintenance. It&amp;#039;s Addis to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Awasa&lt;/span&gt; through the Rift Valley. Stopping to see the magnificent Rift Valley Lakes. Then its down to the border crossing at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Moyale&lt;/span&gt; to enter Kenya.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt; KENYA - &lt;/span&gt;As we enter Kenya we will head for &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Marsabit&lt;/span&gt; and Marsabit National Park.Then we will head off in the complete wrong direction and go to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Loyangalani&lt;/span&gt;, a small village on Lake Turkana. Just to see the &amp;#039;Jade Sea&amp;#039;. From here we will head down down the Rift Valley to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Maralal&lt;/span&gt;.From Maralal to the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Samburu National Park&lt;/span&gt;. A good spot of viewing will hopefully be put in.We will then travel a little further down to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Mount Kenya National Park&lt;/span&gt;.It&amp;#039;s off to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Nairobi&lt;/span&gt; and to find the famous Jungle Junction for a quick rest and meet up with other overlanders. Now it&amp;#039;s time for the big game viewing as we head off towards the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Masai Mara Nature Reserve. &lt;/span&gt;It&amp;#039;s then over to cross the border into Tanzania at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Sirare.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;TANZANIA - &lt;/span&gt;Our first stop in Tanzania is &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Musoma&lt;/span&gt; on Lake Victoria.We move onto the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Serengeti National Park&lt;/span&gt; for a few days game viewing. It&amp;#039;s onto another park at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Ngorongoro Conservation Area&lt;/span&gt;. Here we&amp;#039;ll see the impressive Ngorongor Crater and it&amp;#039;s own eco system and wildlife.We leave the animals behind for now and move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Dodoma&lt;/span&gt;. This will be a stop over for onward travel. &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Dar Es Salaam&lt;/span&gt;, the next stop on our itinerary. A chance for stocking up, checking the car and getting visas etc. We&amp;#039;ll avoid the city centre and stay at Dar&amp;#039;s fantastic beaches. Onto the beaches! It&amp;#039;s off to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Zanzibar &lt;/span&gt;for some beach combing and relaxation.Back to the mainland and onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Iringa. &lt;/span&gt;Another stop over for onward travel. It&amp;#039;s then &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Mbeya&lt;/span&gt;, our last stop before heading over the border ar &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Kiyela&lt;/span&gt; into Malawi.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;MALAWI - &lt;/span&gt;Here we plan to follow Lake Malawi to the border crossing into Zambia. First stop is &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Karonga&lt;/span&gt;. Onto the clear waters and amazing beaches of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Chitimba&lt;/span&gt;. Possible a swim, but making sure we are aware of the risks of bilhazhia in the lake.We move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Chintheche&lt;/span&gt; for more peace and quite along the lake shores. From tranquility we move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Senga Bay&lt;/span&gt;. A hotspot for lake side water activities. A good chance for Dan to brush off the dusty windsurfing skills. It&amp;#039;s across to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Cape Maclear and Lake Malawi National Park&lt;/span&gt;. More beaches and swimming. Over to the capital &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Lilongwe&lt;/span&gt; for markets, shopping and stocking up. Onto the border crossing at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Mchinji&lt;/span&gt; for Zambia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;ZAMBIA - &lt;/span&gt;Straight into &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;South Luangwa National Park&lt;/span&gt;. A recommended park for excellent game viewing. A drive down some unpredictable roads to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Petauke&lt;/span&gt;. A stop over for onward travel. Time to hit the city &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Lusake&lt;/span&gt; for more markets. Then down to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Choma&lt;/span&gt;. A good place to stop over on the way to Livingstone and the great Vistoria Falls. It&amp;#039;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Livingstone&lt;/span&gt; now and a chance to see the great Victoria Falls. A chance for Dan to perhaps take the white river rafting challenge? Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Katima Mlilo&lt;/span&gt; for the ferry across to Namibia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;NAMIBIA - &lt;/span&gt;We start out at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Divundu&lt;/span&gt; to see Popa Falls and Mahango Game reserve.Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Tsumeb&lt;/span&gt; to see their renowned arts and crafts and go to their craft market. We move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Otjiwarongo&lt;/span&gt;. Here they lay claim to dinasour footprints and magical mountains. It&amp;#039;s the capital next, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Windhoek&lt;/span&gt;. Catch up on laundrey and all things mundane. Moving onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Buitepos&lt;/span&gt; for our border crossing into Botswana.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;BOTSWANA&lt;/span&gt; - We cross the border and head for &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Ghanzi.&lt;/span&gt; It&amp;#039;s in the middle of the Kalahari and is a Bushman town. Next we head towards Maun. Here we will take a trip to the Okovango Delta. Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Gweta&lt;/span&gt; and a visit to Ntewtwe Pan, a salt pan. From here we will travel to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Francistown&lt;/span&gt;. A stopover for stocking up before we head off into Zim ands it&amp;#039;s empty shops and fuel tanks. Its across the border into Zimbabwe at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Ramokgwebana&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;ZIMBABWE&lt;/span&gt; - First stop is &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Bulawayo&lt;/span&gt;. Many of Wendy&amp;#039;s family used to live here and were farmers here, so will be a chance for her to see where they used to live. Next it&amp;#039;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Gweru&lt;/span&gt;. A visit to the Antelope Park where they have an extensive Lion breeding programme. We head onto Lake Chivero, Harares main water source and a man made lake. A chill here and some more watersports opportunities for Dan. We have decided to miss Harare and move onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Mutoko&lt;/span&gt;. Just a stopver before crossing the border at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Nyamapanda&lt;/span&gt; into Mozambique.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;MOZAMBIQUE&lt;/span&gt; - From the Zimbabwian border we&amp;#039;ll head for &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Chimoio&lt;/span&gt;. Here there is fantastic country side and mountains. We travel onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Vilanculos&lt;/span&gt; on the coast for the start of our beach bumming. Here we will experience tropical beaches and excellent swimming and surfing for Dan. Who knows, Wendy might give it a try...Onto the famous beach bumming beaches of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Tofo&lt;/span&gt;. Excellent surfing. More sun, sea and sand. The flavour of our journey down Mozambique. It&amp;#039;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Xai Xai&lt;/span&gt; now. A town situated on the Limpopo River, wher it meets the sea. More beautiful beaches. What a hard life. The capital is our next stop, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Maputo&lt;/span&gt;. Here we can catch up on laundrey see the beautiful acacia lined street and colonial houses. Do some more shopping etc. A short stay as we cross the border next at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Kosi Bay&lt;/span&gt; into South Africa. Wendy heads home.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;SOUTH AFRICA - &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;We shall head for the &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;St Lucia Wetlands&lt;/span&gt; and see the mangroves, reefs, swamps and sand forests. It&amp;#039;s along the coast to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Durban&lt;/span&gt;. Wendy&amp;#039;s birth place. Perhaps a stop to visit Wendy&amp;#039;s Dad&amp;#039;s Brother and the rest of the family. It&amp;#039;s been many years since the last visit. Not to mention a visit to the flea market and beaches. Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Waterfall&lt;/span&gt;, where Wendy lived before they moved to England. I want to show Cassie and Dan where I grew up. From here we will travel to the majestical &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Drakensberg&lt;/span&gt;. The scenic mountaon range and it&amp;#039;s fantastic hikes. A few days here to unwind from all the beach combing. We will start in the north and come down to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Sani Pass.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;LESOTHO - &lt;/span&gt;We plan to spend a night at the top of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Sani Pass&lt;/span&gt;. Just for the views into Lesotho and South Africa. It&amp;#039;s also a hard days drive through the pass. Here we will go to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Upper Rafolatsane&lt;/span&gt;. The first town from the bottom of Sani Pass.Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Sehonghong&lt;/span&gt;. We are not doing the tourist trail and are just coming into Lesotho for a feel of it. Then its &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Tsoelike&lt;/span&gt;. Another small village and stop over point. Then out of Lesotho back into South Africa at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Qacha&amp;#039;s Nek&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;SOUTH AFRICA Part 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;margin:0 0 20px;padding:0;&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size:large;&#34;&gt;Back into South Africa and straight onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Kokstad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;Wendy had family that used to own a farm in this region. From Kokstad onto the coast again and &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Port Shepstone&lt;/span&gt; and surrounding towns of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Margate, Shelly Beach&lt;/span&gt; etc. The Wild Coast as it&amp;#039;s called. It&amp;#039;s a choice of where to stay in these coastal towns. The holiday spot of Wendy&amp;#039;s childhood. Onto &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Port St Johns&lt;/span&gt;. The hippie town of the war times. Where poeple moved to avoid being drafted. Apparently not much has changed. Next stop is the highly recommended &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Cintsa&lt;/span&gt;. Apparently S.A&amp;#039;s best beach spot. Time to head away from the beaches and towards a town called &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Hogsback&lt;/span&gt;. This is where J R Tolken apparently got his inspiration to write Lord of the Rings. Back towards the coast again but first stoping at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Grahamstown&lt;/span&gt;. A historical town. Back on the coast at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Jeffreys Bay&lt;/span&gt;. South Africa&amp;#039;s best surfing beach. A chance for more surfing and beach bumming. We start the famous &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Cape Garden Route&lt;/span&gt; now wih our first stop at &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Storms River&lt;/span&gt;. It&amp;#039;s the adventure sports capital with blackwater tubing and bunjee jumping. Watch this space.... Next it&amp;#039;s &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Knysna&lt;/span&gt; and it&amp;#039;s beautiful scenery. Off to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Outshoorn&lt;/span&gt; and it&amp;#039;s famous ostrich farms. Everything here is ostrich from the food to the sports. Maybe one of us will dare to ride one. Down to &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Swellendam&lt;/span&gt;, South Africa&amp;#039;s 3rd oldest inhabited city. The start of the wine tasting. Whale watching in &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Hermanus&lt;/span&gt; and a visit to seal island. We will then base ourselves in the town of &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Stellenbosch&lt;/span&gt;. The centre of the wine country in the Cape. Hopefully family and friends will meet us here for Christmas and the chance to explore the Cape. Below are the places we will explore from our base in Stellenbosch: &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Cape Town&lt;/span&gt; itself - a trip up Table Mountain, the famous V&amp;amp;A Waterfront, Clifton Beach and Kirstenbosch Botanical Gardens, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Cape Point&lt;/span&gt; - The southern tip of Africa, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Franshoek&lt;/span&gt; - A beautiful wine town, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Paarl&lt;/span&gt; - Another wine town set in a valley, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Saldanha Bay&lt;/span&gt; - Wonderful natural harbour and the heart of ghouno shipping, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Citrusdal&lt;/span&gt; - Beautiful orange groves, hot mineral springs with healing powers (apparently) and the Cederberg Mountains, Hout Bay - for the breath taking Chapmans Peak drive, &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:normal;&#34;&gt;Constantia&lt;/span&gt; - More wonderful wines. It&amp;#039;s then the decision of wether we drive up the West Coast home...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning the Summer 2011 Trip</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2011/07/26/planning-the-summer-2011-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 16:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2011/07/26/planning-the-summer-2011-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;This Summer Dan has managed to wangle 4 weeks off work. To add to that, Wendy has changed jobs and now has the school holidays off, so she has 6 weeks holiday over the Summer! This has allowed us to open up our plans, expand our horizons and we have this year decided to travel down to the Serbia, Montenegro and the Bosnia area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As usual we consulted our UNESCO World Heritage book for ideas of places to stop in the countries we would like to be visiting this year. We also bought Bradt travel guides for the same countries and started our “plan”, we only do this to amuse Wendy, Dan would rather just book the ferries point the Landy in the right direction and be done with it. Luckily the plans are never stuck too, not even the ferry bookings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We have a Michelin Europe Map (705), which is on a really large scale (1:3 000 000), which is great for planning our trips. It gets more and more tatty each year, not to mention colourful. So, we sat down with our trusty old Europe map and plotted places we found in book, on-line and in the guides. With help from a few glasses of Vino, this is what we came up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF8029.JPG&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Once we had this plotted, we decided to draw up a Google map. Unfortunately Google won’t route you through Bosnia, so we have had to route around Bosnia to create our map. Pity really. We have shared this Google map with family so that they know the rough route we plan on travelling. We should really just say we are heading to Devon for a month, any mention of going further a field tends to instil panic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/summer-2011-overview-map.jpg?w=640&#34; width=&#34;515&#34; height=&#34;371&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Between the plan’s inception and leaving there were a few things to sort out. When you leave the EU you need an international driving permit (IDP), we got this at a local post office in WHSmiths, what a bad experience! The cue was massive and the staff a bit unfamiliar. Next time I think we will use the AA postal service. Apart from the IDP, insurance is an issue. The EU 3rd party cover will not be valid in some countries out side Europe, like Serbia. We managed to confirm that a green card would be available on the border. Prices vary wildly thou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Over and above paper work, maps needed sorting, both paper 1:200 000 and GPS. The car needed a service and a couple of niggles sorting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Only 4 days to go and the car needs to be packed up by Thursday as Dan has a meeting Friday. The flat once again looks like a camping store with piles here and boxes there… Clothes are being washed ready to get packed up. Pity the English weather isn’t being helpful in the way of supplying sunshine. But it looks like all is going ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning the Summer Trip</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2010/07/29/planning-the-summer-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 15:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2010/07/29/planning-the-summer-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We sat down one Sunday afternoon in July 2010 with just 4 weeks to go and a rough idea of where we wanted to go. Wendy had done some basic research on the internet about the different countries we had decided to visit and the suggested highlights to see. Dan had plotted these on a map for us to see where they lay and which ones would be possible and which would not. What we had decided was that we were doing Eastern Europe this year for a change.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan dragged out an old Europe map we had from back in 2007 (a little out of date, but useful for planning purposes). We decided to plot our route on this. Thankfully, Cassie had had a friend over to play with and that gave us the opportunity to spend the day plotting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-19-jul-2010-2215.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=374&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;337&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We then added the destinations to good old Google maps to find out distances between stops and travel time. From last years travel we decided to aim for 300 miles a day travelling. Going across Czech, Slovakia and Hungary, we guessed that 300 miles would not be possible due to no major roads. We decided to make up the needed distance back up through Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;The initial plan&#34; alt=&#34;2010 Overview&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/2010-overview.jpg?w=1280&amp;amp;h=420&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;209&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Dan contacted Pete, his friend we visited in Spain back in 2008, to show him our planned route. We had hoped to meet up with Pete again last year, but he was unable to get time off work to meet us. Pete informed Dan that it was a great route, but would we like to flip it, change one destination to Bovec, Slovenia and then he would be able to join us for some of the journey. Dan created a new map, emailed Wendy with the question and she decided that it would be no difference going one way as to the other. Wendy brought up the issue of our 2nd wedding anniversary and that if we flipped the route, we would be spending it in Stuttgart, not somewhere she wanted to spend our anniversary. After some investigation from Wendy she decided to change Stuttgart to Tübingen, a town on the banks of the river Necka. It is also close to Naturpark Schönbuch. Pete was happy with this and so we are going to meet a good old friend again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2010 Overview Plan B&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/2010-overview-plan-b.jpg?w=1280&amp;amp;h=440&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;220&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-19-jul-2010-22151.jpg?w=500&amp;amp;h=374&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;374&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-18-apr-2012-2145.jpg?w=150&amp;amp;h=200&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So this year we have made some more purchases. We have bought another box (as seen above) for food storage. We have bought a laundry bag, the clothes got a little bit out of hand last year being stuffed into nooks and crannies till they were washed. We have also bought a new braai…the amazing Boab braai. It’s very impressive. Unfortunately the English weather has not allowed us to test it at home before we set off on our journey. Dan has fitted a working light to Tusky as well as done some maintenance bits to the car which you can read about on the pages about Tusky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Because we are travelling to Eastern Europe we have also had to have vaccinations. Originally it started out as 6 vaccinations for Dan and Wendy and 2 for Cassie. We ended up just having 3 for Dan and Wendy and 1 for Cassie. Dan and Wendy had Typhoid, Diphtheria and Hepatitis A. It was suggested that we go to a travel clinic to get a vaccination for Tick Encephalitis but we did not have enough time left and you require 4 weeks and a minimum of 2 doses. Instead we have had to stock up on Deet insect repellent and some tick removing tweezers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Continuing on the health, we have also purchased a Life Systems first aid kit this year and stocked it with a few extra items. We decided on the mountaineer first aid kit because of the items it has. We have then added Imodium, burn patches, anti histamine cream, blister stick and blister plasters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>