<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Defender on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/defender/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Defender on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/tags/defender/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost There Upstand Assembly</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/19/almost-there-upstand-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0109.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much of an update tonight, with the ongoing repair apart from to show some pictures of the panel now it has been fully tweaked and drilled to fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished of the drilling tonight and deburred everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final job for the night was to give another coat of etch primer and paint the seat brackets and new panels with stone chip paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are now drying, so tomorrow I&#39;ll start fitting it for real. The only thing I need to do is drill the seat brackets in location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful with a push, I should have it done tomorrow or Sunday at the latest. Not wishing to tempt fate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0111.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the Upstand/Upriser Re-Assembly</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/18/starting-the-upstandupriser-re-assembly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0091.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now at the stage of re-assembly. It has been a slow road even to strip the back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mid-crossmember is galvanised and from YRM metal solutions. One of the nice features of the new one, is that the top brackets are loose rather than welded on this makes it easier to get the cross member under the fuel pipes etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0098.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I have had with the crossmember is that the holes, for mounting to the chassis rails where about 3mm out across the vehicle. I am not entirely sure why, but I eventually managed to get the bolts in. I suspect it may have been partially due to the camber of the road. I&#39;ve used stainless bolts so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0095.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing to note on the cross member is that the cut out for the fuel hoses on my vehicle is in the wrong location. This probably varies from vehicle to vehicle. One was YRM could improve this is to have a wider cut out. I have added additional protection and will tywrap the hoses out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the crossmember was in it was time to start fitting the upstand/upriser. The new item is a different size to the old one. In a good way. The lips are about another 10mm deep. This means that around the top a certain amount of fitting is required, this is around the spars under the floor and the doubler between the separate sections of floor near the doors. I only cut out these areas, I like the idea of the extra depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new item seemed longer also, I did not have to cut it down. The reason is that the old panel was tapered making the top shorter than the bottom edge. I spaced it evenly each side and it seems ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0102.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fitting done, I have now dry fitted it, drilled the holes for the top rivets and will tomorrow drill the sides pieces and seat brackets. At the moment the rivets are all loose. I will strip it out and paint it once I have dry assembled it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The floor is in with a couple of screws at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upstand repair continues</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/17/upstand-repair-continues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/20130717-141934.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You&#39;ll need to forgive the posts at the moment, they are short and sweet. This is because I am under pressure and because I am feeling guilty about not posting, all I would like to on what has happened and what I want to happen. I am doing them on the run with the Wordpress app.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyhow an update on the floor repair of the landy. The second row floor is out. This was a bit of hassle as all the screws were seized. I have no power at the vehicle so a grinder was not an option. The up stand/ upriser is out and the mid cross member is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also cleaned up around the mid cross member mountings and put stone chip paint on it to give it some protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0086.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Warm Up and Last Minute Fuel Pump Change</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 08:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/06/08/quick-warm-up-and-last-minute-fuel-pump-change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-30-may-2013-1644.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend we got lucky with the weather, mostly. We spent a couple of nights camping in Wales. On the way we decided we&amp;#039;d break the journey, by stopping the night at a pub that allows camping in their garden. So we stopped in Wiltshire at The Parish Lantern, highly recommended. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole journey avoided the motorways and took us through many little interesting towns and funny back roads, on the way back we managed to include a couple of green lanes near Salisbury and the Stone Henge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1518.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-2-jun-2013-1536.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to departure, I thought I&amp;#039;d change the fuel filter, the Landy will get it&amp;#039;s service any day, but in the mean time I though that I&amp;#039;d do the filter because I felt it had been a bit sluggish when I had occasionally driven it over the winter. As you&amp;#039;d expect the filter was quick and easy to change. But.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Problems occurred during priming, I was not able to prime the filter with the lift pump handle. I though it may have been the position of the pump lever on the cam, flicking the engine over a few times did not improve that. I managed to get the engine started though after several attempts without the lift pump for assistance, then just to confirm my suspicion cracking the bleed screw on the filter housing did not give a stream of diesel. This in my eyes proved the lift pump was failed and that it was not pressurising the filter, etc. It was getting late on the night before we left at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I had a new genuine lift pump in my spares box complete with olives, nuts and gasket. I would have to make a decision. Live with it and fit a new one on return or fit the spare in the morning before we left. The problem is that I did not want to have a sluggish vehicle on a long journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the task seemed mostly simple I took the gamble to fit it in the morning. In the pouring rain. My only apprehension was that the bolts to the block interface plate could be seized. They were not, so after establishing that, I spent an hour and the problem was fixed. Pump on and decent pressure restored at the pump bleed screw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside of it all was that we got off earlier on our weekend trip and managed to have an early pint at the pub we stayed at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the annual trip approaching over the next couple of weeks, I have to get a service done on the Landy and fix the second row seat up riser corrosion which is a big job. For that I managed to get a galvanised mid cross member from YRM metal solutions together with the aluminium panels I need. I just hope I can get it all apart! I&amp;#039;ll keep you posted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Minutes jobs are never 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/19/5-minutes-jobs-are-never-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 20:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/19/5-minutes-jobs-are-never-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it every job on my Landy that should be five minutes, takes hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changed the front mud flaps on the Land Rover yesterday... and today. Passenger side easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drivers side was a different story. One of the bolts was heavily corroded into the rivnut. This meant that the rivnut spun... Only choice was to rip the rivnut out and replace it. Luckily I managed to fit a new one of the same size. All without the proper tool to clamp it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice trick with a bolt, washer and nut. Let me know if you can&#39;t figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway another five minute job done in 2 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Stats - Summer 2012 Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 20:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/04/16/some-stats-summer-2012-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In starting to consider this years plan, i thought i would post some recorded figures from last summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stats from our last trip from 27th July to the 26th August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We covered 3663.1 miles, about 5900 km.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used 606.42 litres of diesel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Averaged 27 miles per gallon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filled up 15 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paid 26 tolls totalling 287.8 Euro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most expensive where for the Tunnel de Mont Blanc at 38.9 and tunnel de Frejus at 39.8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used the channel tunnel for crossing the channel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We used a over night ferry from Bari to Dubrovnik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 night in a hotel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 attempted nights at a hotel night resulting in six police officers attending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 nights free camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 none catastrophic car part failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which do you want to know more about!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antignano, Livorno - Italy</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/06/antignano-livorno-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 19:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/08/06/antignano-livorno-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9256.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-818 alignleft&#34; alt=&#34;Poor Tusky&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Carole and Daniel have decided that they would like to look for a small camping fridge. We looked for a Decathlon and used the GPS find our way. It was along the way and we were heading towards Bari now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We found a Decathlon, but were not in luck, they did not stock any fridges what-so-ever! As we were near the shops, we decided to stop off and get our food shopping done for the next few days. As we were packing the cars and fridge with our food shop, Dan and Daniel noticed an oil leak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;It turns out that the vacuum pump is seriously leaking. We need to get to a garage and get the right part to fix this situation. Dan used the GPS to locate the nearest Land Rover garage, and off we set on a search for this garage and a way to get the part we would require.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The first garage we find is no longer open to business. This is a set back that we did not expect or want. The day is wearing on and time is ticking. We managed to locate another Land Rover garage, and so the search continues. This time we are in luck! The garage is still in business, but we have now hit Siesta time and so we have to wait for 14.00hrs till we can find out if they have a part or can order one for us. We decide to go to a truck café we saw just down the road to have a snack and drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;When we get back to the garage, the guy is extremely helpful. He says that he can order the part, but it may take as long as 48hrs to be delivered. Give him an hour or so and he will see what he can do for us. It turns out that he is able to get the part delivered for the next day, we just have to collect it after 14.00hrs. We thank him profusely and set off to find a campsite that isn&amp;#039;t too far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The campsite we found was just up the road. It had a swimming pool, points for Cassie, and it had bungalows, points for Carole. Carole and Daniel rented a bungalow and we took a pitch. We decided to stay for 2 nights so that Dan had time to fit the pump and not worry. As we pulled up to our pitch, Dan got worried about being able to work on the Landy. It wasn&amp;#039;t a secluded spot. We went and had a look at a pitch that we would be able to &amp;#039;upgrade&amp;#039; to if we wanted. It was more expensive and came with it&amp;#039;s own sea view terrace. Dan was happier with the privacy this pitch provided, and so we moved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9240.jpg?w=225&#34; class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-817&#34; alt=&#34;The terrace adjoined to our pitch&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The time at he campsite was spent relaxing. The next day Wendy and Cassie spent the day at the pool whilst Dan worked on the Landy and Carole and Daniel did things they wanted to catch up on. It was a nice lazy stop despite the reason for stopping. We explored the beach, went for a swim in the sea and had a lovely braai on the terrace on the last evening. Ready to leave in the morning and do one mammoth drive. We were going to try and cover the whole distance to Bari tomorrow, making up for lost time.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1110456.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-820&#34; alt=&#34;Cassie &amp;amp; Wendy enjoying the sun &amp;amp; pool&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safari Snorkel Fitted</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/21/safari-snorkel-fitted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 18:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/21/safari-snorkel-fitted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-10431.jpg?w=180&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;239&#34; alt=&#34;Safari Snorkel&#34; /&gt;Thanks to being the lucky recipient of a Safari Snorkel for my Birthday and many Christmases to come, I managed to get a Safari Snorkel fitted to the Landy last week.
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;It was all fairly straight forward and I forgot to take many photos.&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most intimidating bit for me was drilling the holes in the body work, making sure I had the template spot on etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-10-jul-2012-0538.jpg?w=201&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; alt=&#34;Mounting holes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the existing induction pipe work, I sealed up the drain valve in the tee piece, for this I used Sika flex to seal the flap shut, then completely filled in the drain appeture with more of the stuff. I tested this when I finished by blocking the top of the Snorkel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the holes were drilled, I fitted the neoprene gasket for the Snorkel to the body of the Snorkel using some Sika flex sealant, I also did the same with the windscreen mount gasket. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-1044.jpg?w=195&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;195&#34; height=&#34;260&#34; alt=&#34;Water drain&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once these were dry, I test fitted the lot with plain nuts rather than nylocs, so that I could find the location to drill the windscreen frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lick of paint on the holes and then some more sealant around all the holes will keep the water out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The windscreen mount is secured with self tappers, five in total. I left the bolts for the snorkel body on the windscreen mount loose, until I tightened up the wing securing bolts using nylocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wing gasket had copious amounts of sealant around it, this is not really to keep water out of the snorkel though, more just to keep the holes sealed. The design of the Safari Snorkel is such that it does not depend on the wing seal. The whole upright section is continuos unit until the hose fits to it for the induction system, meaning that there are fewer potential failure failure points, that other designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-1043.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; alt=&#34;Windscreen bracket&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-10441.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; alt=&#34;Back of the wing panel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-12-jul-2012-13441.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Job Done&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defender Split Charge - Version 2</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/defender-split-charge-version-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2012 19:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/08/defender-split-charge-version-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; During the trip last year into the Balkan states, we had a slight issue that the split charge contactor started failing to close. At first this was intermittent, then it became permanent in the heat. I was sometimes able to get it to close by tapping the contactor with a fair force. Eventually that did not even work. This of course was a serious issue for keeping our drinks cold!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img-20120413-00172.jpg?w=351&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; alt=&#34;Albright Contactor&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got back to the UK, the fault disappeared completely. It appeared to be a heat related fault. Probably the coil or a mechanical failure. While we were on the road we tried to get a new contactor, but failed. There were plenty of relays around at about 30 amps, but I needed a 100 amp contactor. A 30 amp relay would have been fried in no time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that I would seek a decent quality replacement in the UK. I actually already knew that I would replace it with a sealed Albright contactor when we were back. This provided the ideal opportunity to refine the whole split charge, being one not to miss out on an opportunity. I did some other work also. The Albright is a sealed unit which means that if it should get wet in the battery box it is not an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This other work was really because. Having been installed for three years the deep cycle battery I had was starting to show symptoms of loosing capacity, which I suspected was caused by the low output of the 65 amp alternator being at around 13 volts. To rectify this, I decided to install a 100 amp alternator, to give me extra head room and also charge the batteries quicker. At a later stage I will need to improve the alternator output cable to something slightly thicker, at the moment it is the standard 16 mm cable. I will probably stick in some 25 mm cable. This runs from the alternator to the starter motor. You may ask yourself why I changed the alternator rather than overhaul it, which would have been far cheaper. The reason was purely because I needed the extra capacity in the 100 amp unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the alternator improvement and my output now at 14.4 volts again, I also fitted some decent Odessey deep cycle batteries. I did not want to fit decent batteries with a crap alternator, this would have just shortened their life. In the end I went for PC1500&amp;#039;s with the side terminals. These batteries are sealed units so they do not give off gas or fluid if they get hot. This has the benefit that my now clean battery box should stay corrosion free. Typically batteries gas, on a defender it means that you get that horrible white powder in the box and also excessive corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20119.jpg?w=302&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;302&#34; height=&#34;226&#34; alt=&#34;Jump cable socket&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the batteries I wanted to use the side terminals of the start battery for an Anderson connector. Connected via 35 mm cable. This would provide a convenient way to jump start people or for me to be jump started. I had some 4 meter jump leads made for the purpose. Access to the batteries is otherwise a real pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-24-may-2011-1234.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;247&#34; alt=&#34;4 meter jump leads&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the battery box itself, I re-treated the box with Hammerite to protect against corrosion, then mounted a Devon 4x4 twin battery tray. This was actually the second battery tray. I first tried to order a Flatdog tray, but that did not fit my Odessey batteries height wise. The reason was because the threaded bars were too short. I sold that one. Luckily the Devon 4x4 version was included in the battery package I wanted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08277.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original fuse panel I had fitted was also at capacity, I needed a bigger one. I decided to fit a 12 way fuse box with a positive and negative power bus. This makes connecting new loads really easy. While I was at the rewiring, I also connected the stereo to the Auxilary battery, the CB also and put a new power socket in the lockable cubby box. This would be for charging the laptop and iPad on the go. Whilst I was in there I moved the stereo USB connector into the cubby box. This mean the iPod or USB stick will be safe under lock and key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20113.jpg?w=390&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;390&#34; height=&#34;292&#34; alt=&#34;Odyssey Batteries &#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was in the under seat box, I also decided to remove the old immobiliser enclosure in the battery compartment. I stowed the wiring for now thou. I&amp;#039;ll deal with that later, but am fairly confident I could just cut the wiring!... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The immobiliser housing took up a fair amount of space, which I felt I would at some stage need. Why you ask? I have a plan / idea that I would like to fit an 80 or 100 watt solar panel to the roof somehow. This would more than cover the fridge running in the day. If I do this I will probably use a CTEK DC-DC charger (DS250s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20116.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;399&#34; alt=&#34;Fuse panel 12-way&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08274.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;12-way fuse panel in place&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally the Albright contactor was mounted such that it was tucked into the corner out the way. I had planned to connect the contactor in such a way that it would be powered when the charge indicator extinguished. I also wanted a way for the contactor to be forced to close before the charge indicator extinguished, this would allow for easy self jump starting, if necessary. In order to facilitate this I have a switch on the dash with an LED indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-9-jun-2012-20115.jpg?w=317&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;317&#34; height=&#34;423&#34; alt=&#34;Albright mounted&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-15-apr-2012-21101.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Split charge control switch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serbia, Unexpected off road</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/01/serbia-unexpected-off-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 09:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/07/01/serbia-unexpected-off-road/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just been playing with the iPad iMovie app. Last year when we were in Serbia, we were following the GPS to go from the Studenica monastery to Durmitor and ended up going along a grade gravel road. This as it turned out, was the foundation for a section of soon to be E-760, we think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;We ended up turning back after giving the workers a few laughs. We had fun, they got a laugh everyone&amp;#039;s a winner. After turning back we ended up following another proper farm track which turned out to be good fun. We got a little lost and came across a farmer who looked bemused!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we popped out the other side a little muddy and happy with the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first video shows were the GPS thought we were. The second shows the farm track that we eventually used.
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HWU9MqfHTYU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JB1uuHmhOEg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defender Door Hinge Modification</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/06/10/defender-door-hinge-modification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 08:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/06/10/defender-door-hinge-modification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;After 14 years, my doors had started to droop! It is widely known that Defender hinges wear, they wear at the interface between the pin and the body which is fixed to the door. Mine had so much play my door leaked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;In addition to the wear they also start to corrode from the same place and cause bleeding paint effects. Not Pretty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I did order some more hinges, but they were worse. So I sent them back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Eventually I stumbled across this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orrp.com/smf/index.php?topic=50676.0&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;, which gave me the idea I would do the same. I got hold of some hinges from a mate at work, knocked the pins out and drilled them for a M8 stainless steel bolt. I have not fitted a grease nipple yet, i&amp;#039;ll do this when I do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;So far I have done the drivers door, and it looks supper. I sprayed the hinges with etch primer and black Hammerite smooth. I then shoved them in the oven for a few hours to dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1080170.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;266&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img01395-20100727-2052.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-543&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Modified Hinge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The hinge is fitted to the car with stainless steel screws, to reduce the effects of corrosion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The result is that if I now check for play the whole vehicle moves. The plan is to try these for the summer and do the whole car in the winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;There is some additional info &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eastcoastrover.com/Hinges.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and if you are feeling rich you can buy some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.croytec.co.uk/products/DoorHinges.htm&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, which have had the work done!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrument Binnacle (Cowl) - Raptor Engineering</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/05/30/instrument-binnacle-cowl-raptor-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 05:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/05/30/instrument-binnacle-cowl-raptor-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-0913.jpg?w=420&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;473&#34; alt=&#34;Dash Explosion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The binnacle on the Defender is the part that surrounds the instruments in front of the driver, it secures to the underside of the dashboard top surface. The binnacle is also known as the instrument cowl. Item 1 In the picture on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binnacle provides a frame to mount the instrument panel and heater controls onto. On older Defenders and I expect Series vehicles also, it is common to find them cracked and falling apart, this leads to the surrounding components being loose and fee to move. In my case leading to an annoying medley of squeaks and rattles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a simple job, apart from a couple of ackward screws, to replace the binnacle, a standard plastic replacement is available from various part suppliers at about £50. I believe the part number is MTC2808. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The problem with replacing like for like is that eventually the replacement will end up in the same state as the original, I suspect the combined effects of heat, vibration and UV on the exposed sections probably cause the failure. That together with heavy hands. I suppose you would hope that modern replacements are of a better specified plastic and more hardy. Not knowing for sure I wanted an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-0934.jpg?w=343&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;343&#34; height=&#34;343&#34; alt=&#34;Raptor Binnacle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily a powder coated steel equivalent is available from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raptor-engineering.co.uk/defender-s111-binnacle-mount&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; title=&#34;Raptor Engineering Binnacle&#34;&gt;Raptor Engineering&lt;/a&gt;, at around the same price as the plastic replacement. I decided I would go for this when I replaced the binnacle on our Defender. I did not fancy doing the job again in the future. Picture on the right shows what it looks like. I forgot to take a before picture, so have pinched the one from Raptor&amp;#039;s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the good things about the Raptor replacement is that there are less of the fiddly screws to put back, once they are out. Also the lugs at the top of the mount, were the top of the instrument panel secures to are adjustable, allowing an element of fine tuning the final position of the instrument panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On thing that would have been nice as an option on purchase, would have been a kit of u-nuts and original spec screws. I found that I had various bits missing, probably lost with bits of dash before my time. I think I would have purchase the extras at the time if I had the option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-08284.jpg?w=351&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;351&#34; height=&#34;262&#34; alt=&#34;Broken Defender Binnacle Instrument Cowl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually managed to get the old binnacle out and it was only then that I realised how bad it was. There were pieces from both sides and the back missing, there were also various cracks which prevented the captive nut things securing properly, which are supposed to hold the side panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have my suspicions that the rear section in the picture on the left was broken when the immobiliser was fitted for my insurance. I found the missing bit deep in the dash below the hazard relay etc. the other side of the binnacle looks similar to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:right;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-082710.jpg&#34; class=&#34;alignright&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the old one is out the Raptor replacement dropped straight in. I loosely fitted it to start with to allow me to make sure everything lined up correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once happy, I secured the main fixings and then the heater controls to the binnacle. As I had screws and u-nuts missing, I decided to replace all of the side self tapping screws with round head hex M5 screws and nuts, that are black anodised. This matches the adjustable tab screws provided by Raptor and looks smart, it also gave me the spares to secure the front properly. The only self tappers are the four that secure the main instrument panel to the binnacle. Picture below if you are interested. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2012-0827.jpg?w=358&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;358&#34; height=&#34;268&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;Overall, I am pleased with the Raptor product, it makes a very sturdy replacement, fits well and gives the dash a fresher look. I would highly recommend using this as a standard replacement.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter cooler Leak Testing - FTP8030 300TDI</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/04/inter-cooler-leak-testing-ftp8030-300tdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 19:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/04/04/inter-cooler-leak-testing-ftp8030-300tdi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Defender has had what I think is a typical inter cooler leak for quite some time, which leads to some power loss often notable on hills. I attempted to sort it out last summer prior to our departure for our summer trip. I purchased a second hand item and found that it was also leaking. Luckily I tested it before I fitted it to the vehicle. I ended up leaving the original in place and living with the loss of power for the trip and manage to get my money back. The seller was very apologetic!
&lt;div&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img-20120404-00134.jpg&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-285&#34; width=&#34;512&#34; height=&#34;384&#34; alt=&#34;300 TDI Intercooler Leak - Back&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture above is typical of the leaks I have seen on these items. If you look on ebay a lot of the second hand inter coolers have the oil stain you see above, in the lower corner of the inter cooler, some have other oil stains which may be a sign of a leak, so please buy with care. This tel-tale sign of oil is what prompted me to test the leaking one I had last summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fairly easy to set up a fairly crude off vehicle test. I used an old inner tube, which was cut so the valve was in the middle of a length of inner tube long enough to fit between the two hose connections on the inter cooler, the inner tube was secured with some jubilee clips. I then pumped up the inner tube to about 20 psi and stuck the whole lot in a tub of water. What I found was a constant stream of bubbles from the corner of the inter cooler, indicating a leak. Below you can see my inter cooler test equipment. Impressed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img-20120404-00148.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-289&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; alt=&#34;Intercooler Test Equipment - Bike Inner Tube&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I managed to purchase a new replacement inter cooler from Motor &amp;amp; Diesel Engineering Ltd, they supply the LGV 2.8 Diesel engine over here which is a development of the 300TDI engine. The item they sent looked to me to be a re-core, but it had comforting stickers on it which suggest it was tested. The price was also very reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fairly easy to change the inter cooler, so I will not get into the detail, you can see that below. I think with my faffing around it took me two leisurely hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/300tdi-intercooler-change-lr.jpg&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-283&#34; width=&#34;516&#34; height=&#34;554&#34; alt=&#34;Defender 300TDI Intercooler Change&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this is of use to someone, has anyone else had the experience, I had with purchasing a bad second hand item?
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Charge Auxiliary Battery Installation - Version 1</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/03/17/split-charge-auxiliary-battery-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 19:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2012/03/17/split-charge-auxiliary-battery-installation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The battery in a Defender is under the passenger seat. It is a large compartment which you can actually fit two batteries in. This is perfect if you want to use there vehicle for winching, camping or over landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/IMG00119.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; alt=&#34;You should see a picture of the Defender battery compartment&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The main driver for fitting a second battery in our vehicle was to run the fridge. We have a Weaco CF-18 cool box style fridge this is an excellent fridge, which is sufficent for us on holidays camping, it has an 18 litre capacity. If we where going on longer trips I think I would push to get a large capacity fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;I wanted to keep the control and wiring simple when I installed the second battery. In order to do this I decided against control electronics, there are loads on the market made by people such as National Luna. I decided to use the method shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The two batteries are simply linked by a contactor with a large rating. I chose a 120 Amp contactor in the end. The control of the contactor is by the charge indicator in the dash. I picked this up of the back of the alternator wiring to save me running wires upto the dash board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/1Qev0Mv3TaSUzn93-ekcuK3e04M5rZserP4Yo33wpwb0.png&amp;amp;w=499&amp;amp;h=335&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;499&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; alt=&#34;You should see the circuit diagram of the split charge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Attached to the auxilary battery is a small six way fuse panel this allows me to fuse any additional items I attach to the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/IMG00116.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;320&#34; alt=&#34;You should see a picture of the Auxiliary Fuse Panel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Here are a few pics of the layout, before additional connections where made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/IMG00118.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of Contactor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/IMG00117.jpg&#34; class=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;160&#34; alt=&#34;The contactor&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Around the vehicle I fitted surface mounted 12 volt sockets, such as below the second row seats and above the rear light cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img00124.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-563&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img00126.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-564&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img00127.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-565&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/P1080802.JPG&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;The fridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;There is some more info in these threads. &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.landrovernet.com/showthread.php/161991-Split-charge-Alternator-size&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.landrovernet.com/showthread.php?t=151988&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Sorry about the crappy pictures I took them on my blackberry...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>