<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bosnia And Herzegovina on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/bosnia-and-herzegovina/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bosnia And Herzegovina on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Code released under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.co.uk/categories/bosnia-and-herzegovina/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 13 - Jablaničko Jezero to Kostanjica</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/08/day-13-jablanicko-jezero-to-kostanjica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 20:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/08/day-13-jablanicko-jezero-to-kostanjica/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9981.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we headed for Montenegro, our cunning plan was to head out on the main roads so we could get there in good time to relax. That is where we went wrong!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We headed out from Konjic diligently following the signs to Nevesinje. Within a few miles the signs became vague and then non-existent. We were planning to get most of the way through Montenegro in order to get in to Albania asap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Round about when we got to Glavatičevo some 20 km after we started we took the first wrong turning. We passed a town name which we found on the map, Ladanica. This had a nice looking Cafe Restaurant so we stopped to have a coffee and get our bearings, apparently we should have gone right at the bridge. Which was a dirt track indicating a place we could not find on the map. Sceptical I asked someone passing, they confirmed we should have gone up there via, some other towns… Not shown on the map. This was not the main road we had hoped to be on. Still doubtful we tracked back to some shops up the road and asked some ladies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9987.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ladies eventually concluded we should follow them, it would be easier. These ladies drove an Audi with a German plate. They took us up the dirt track, after about 2 km, they pulled into a drive. We concluded this was there place. Handed us a hand drawn map, and said just keep going, don&#39;t turn left. The map showed two town names and a turning. They told us it was 10 km to Nevesinje. We soon realised that they would be able to go no further.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9989.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The track continued to degrade, but remained ever present. We gradually climbed a fairly big mountain side. Emerging in some farm land, by this time we had passed about 10 turnings left. I was starting to loose faith. However eventually we came across a farm, with a driery looking guy sitting out side, he confirmed we were headed in the right direction. About 40 minutes later we came across another person, at a small house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enquired with the person about out destination, he suggested I need to keep going. As I walked off I became alarmed, by his gestures which he repeated when I looked at him questioningly. He was indicating or seemed to be suggesting it was a long way to Nevesinje. He did this by drawing his hand down from his chin as if twisting a beard. I think he was saying you&#39;ll have a beard by the time you get there. I laughed worried and told Wendy who looked slightly alarmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 30 minutes later we arrived on tarmac at a junction. I now concluded that the guy previously had a sense of humour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We opted to turn right. Headed for Luka. Within 1 km we were on gravel again precisely what we did not expect. We continued at speed but tentatively on the track for about 20 minutes before an old soviet truck approached us thundering. We asked if Nevesinje was the way we were going he indicated we had to turn around. We managed to do this some 500 meters later. We passed the truck again and he moved over to let us pass. We beeped in thanks and joy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this we seemed to be on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some two hours later we arrived at the wrong border crossing to Montenegro having been redirected once or twice. We had hoped to cross at Bileća, but had missed the turning ending up crossing in reverse where we entered Bosnia and Herzegovina two years ago at Dolovi. With this we took the easy option headed for the beach in an area we know to chill for two nights.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf0018.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Kostanjica and just relaxed. Phew. What a great but unexpected day. Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12- Sarajevo to Jablaničko Jezero via Lukomir</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/07/day-12-sarajevo-to-jablanicko-jezero-via-lukomir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 06:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/07/day-12-sarajevo-to-jablanicko-jezero-via-lukomir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So having spent the night in a hotel, which is fairly civilised for us, we got cracking early after a light breakfast. The plan for today was to find our way out of Sarajevo and head for the village of Lukomir. After which we would find some camping etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting out of Sarajevo was easier said than done. The city has a one way system, we wanted to head out of the city to the southwest. For a start vaguely towards the airport and then end up on road 18. We only need to get out a few kilometers, to find the turn off to the roads in the mountains. But there was a surprising lack of signs indicating places and exits out of Sarajevo. You would expect for instance to see the airport sign posted or the next largest city. But there was nothing. Well nothing we could see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the city driving is fairly easy, there was a big circular oneway system around the centre, it takes about 10 minutes to go around. The previous day we did it several times, so by now we were experts. Once we got to the western end of the system we headed south over one of the bridges and eventually with a few missed turnings found our way out, with some amusement.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130773.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We needed a few supplies before we headed up to Lukomir, I was anticipating wild camping up on the mountains somewhere, as without decent scale maps or a working GPS I was a little vague on how exactly to get there or what to expect. The best map we had was a 1:200 Bosnia and Herzegovina map, which turned out to be totally inaccurate for the dirt roads. Anyway, conveniently there was a fuel station at the hotel and also conveniently at the turning off the main road was a tiny shop. Which meant we were now ready for anything ... sort of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we headed up off the main road towards Bjelašnica which is the local Ski resort, we climbed at first what seemed a fairly none descript dusty road past a load of industrial cement works (I think), beyond these as we continued up toward Bjelašnica, the road continued to become smaller and with occasionally broken tarmac. By comparison, with French and Swiss Ski resorts, Bjelašnica is tiny.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130801.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to follow the signs to the most easily accessible village of Umoljani. This is reasonably well sign posted and only involves a short section of dirt track to get to the village from Bjelašnica. What we found out was that if you approach from the other side, via Ozimine, is that you can do the whole route by tarmac, on very minor roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9916.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to get to Umoljani then try and find Lukomir. Which we thought would be a simple affair as the map shows a track to Lukomir and we also saw the occasional sign. But we where wrong, these just lead to Umoljani. After about 40 minutes or so, we decided to just follow a track we came across in the opposite direction to which we had been indicated. I think we had given up on the idea of Lukomir and just fancied doing a bit of exploring, I could see a zig-zag track going up what I think was Vlahinja, which looked like it could also turn out to be a good stop.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130814.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after about 15 minutes we spotted a small sign indicating Lukomir so obediently turned as indicated by the sign. The track seemed to go on forever. But eventually after passing a few shepards and their flocks we could see houses in the distance. Just outside the village is a tourist sign, which tells the &#34;Story&#34; of the village, we parked there and went for a wander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/dscf9923.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that hits you is the smell of sheep manure, there were huge piles of it, setting the odour of the area, it was not unpleasant, just strong. As we passed the first houses on the track through the village, the old ladies of the houses shouted for us to buy some of there products, which they had hanging on the fence. The seemed to mainly be slippers made of wool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We continued to wander along the track and we got to the water spring in the centre of the village, which in the heat, offered an opportunity to cool off. Here we saw there was a small wood sign indicating food, which lead us to a few tables outside a house. We sat down and tentatively asked for drink. Cassie had juice, I cheekily asked if they had beer ... I was in luck. The guy running the place stopped to have a drink too, he had been cutting wood. He was spending the summer up in the village with his mother, at his grandfather&#39;s house. He used to be a tram driver in Sarajevo, but having spent a year training he had been waiting for two years to get a new contract. This was an opportunity for him to earn some cash for the winter, in Sarajevo. He explained that not many people spend the winter on the mountains anymore, most opt to return to Sarajevo or lower towns for the cold months. We also learnt some of the villagers stories and how sometimes too many tourists can appear. Which seemed a shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later we purchased some slippers and grabbed some stuff out the car, so we could go for a short walk and have a picnic lunch. We found an excellent spot on a peak over looking the canyon beyond the village. During lunch we talked about what to do next, I had asked if we could camp nearby and the guy who gave us drinks said we could camp where we parked. Wendy was not comfortable with that, feeling like we were intruding. So we drove down from the mountain tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first we headed out the way we came, but spotted a sign to Vrdolje and opted to follow that a different was down. This would we hope lead us to a main road on which lies Konjic, which we thought would have camping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tracks require a certain amount of faith. You&#39;ll pass loads of branches, and with no signs, we always opted to take what we fought was the continuation of the main route. Always what plays in you mind is mines, which are normally indicated and should not be a problem in the area we were in but, it just sits there. We were lucky we passed a man and he confirmed we were headed in the right direction and that we should just continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About an hour or so later we popped out on the main road, and looked for camping on Konjic. Which was fairly well sign posted. We had to pay a small 5 KM toll to take the road into the campsite, which considering it was 50m beyond the toll man was steep. We did not mind though. The campsite was basic, which we like, outdoor shower, lake to swim and a horrible toilet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We parked, grabbed a beer from the fridge and went to cool down in the lake. Later we popped into the restaurant in the site and had Ćevapi for dinner with several beers. All of these places have restaurants and being so cheap, we have been using them rather than cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11 - Jajce to Sarajevo</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 19:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/06/day-11-jajce-to-sarajevo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130707.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We packed up fairly sharpish this morning the plan was to have coffee and breakfast in Jajce, then explore. We got in to town easily from the campsite and managed to find parking. Dan accidentally purchased a day of parking for 5 KM (about 2.5 euro). Jajce is a candidate for a Unesco site, so we expect to find something fairly special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked into what we thought was the Old Town, the traffic was immense. The heat was already building and we decided to stop and have a coffee and breakfast before we headed out to explore. This being easier said than done. All the cafés were a little strange, so we opted for the most full…going with the thought process that if it&#39;s full, it must be ok. We decided to order a cappuccino instead of a coffee…we will not do this again. We promptly drank up and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130714.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wondering around and down a slippery, pebble polished set of stairs (from all the wear), we had no idea where we were going. We couldn&#39;t find the Old Town or the waterfalls mentioned to fall from Jajce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we still had not eaten, our stomachs won and we headed for the Pekara (bakery) we had seen on our way in to get some breakfast, or now, brunch. Cassie asked if we could go to the underground church she had seen a sign for, so we headed for that. Low and Behold! We were in the the Old Town. We should have simply headed that way to begin with. We paid 6KM for all of us to go down into the catacombs. They weren&#39;t extensive, but still a lot cooler than outside as the heat was blaring and interesting. A shame that on many of the alls there was engraved graffiti as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p11307261.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130727.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we wondered up to the top of the Old Town walls, we had a look around and decided to start our journey to Sarajevo. The drive was a hot one. As we entered the city, we found it hard to navigate with our large scale map and a guide book city centre map. We eventually managed to get onto a road that was shown on the map in our Bradt guide book. From here we were able to navigate ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130747.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parking … Oh parking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was none!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We navigated the one way system roughly 4 times before we decided to head on out of the city and find a hotel on the outskirts, with parking, and catch a taxi into the centre. Just on the fringe of the one way system there was a petrol station and a tiny hotel next door. It had parking! Dan pulled in and went to ask if they had a room for the night and the cost. BINGO! We were in. We decided to have a shower, a beer and then go out and explore Sarajevo and find some dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we wondered in, Dan had seen an Apple store at the Sarajevo School of Arts, so we decided to head there and see if they had some noise cancelling headphones for Dan and Cassie to use. Cassie wanted to cross the bridge on the entrance to the centre as it was &#34;curly&#34;. We then decided to get a city map so we could find the Turkish quarter (Baščaršija) where the guide book said it was the best place to get a feel for Sarajevo. After wondering a bit and finding the quarter, we explored the stalls and did some souvinir shopping. Cassie and I bought some clothing from a shop that sold only hand made Bosnian clothes. Cassie got a shawl/poncho and Wendy got a lovely top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130751.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went in search of a place that sold ćevapi, as we had seen everyone sitting outside on the street restaurants eating ćevapi. Ćevapi is a meat sausage made from lamb or beef, or a mix, in a pita type bread served with sour cream/yoghurt and onions. It was lovely! The restaurants were full and after wondering around a bit we found one where the waiter put us on a table with another lady. She happened to be a student from Holland doing her Thesis in Bosnia on Genoside and Reconciliation. She was very good company and a lovely dinner partner to chat to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130767.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we looked for a place to have a beer, but being in the muslim part of the town, beer was a tad hard to find being served. We decided to just head back to the hotel and have a beer there. An opportunity to update this blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130750.jpg&#34;&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10 - Bihac to Jajce</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/05/day-10-bihac-to-jajce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 16:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/05/day-10-bihac-to-jajce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130633.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a short day today, we left the campsite at a leisurely pace and drove around 150km to Jajce. It looked to be a fairly simple drive following the road numbered 5 for Sarajevo. Jajce was before Sarajevo but signs did not appear until about 70km from Bihac.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130623.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this thing about having to have my headlights on in the summer, I know it is the law in a lot of countries. But I just don&#39;t like it. I would understand in the winter, but in the summer it does nothing but waste fuel! Anyhow this again got me pulled over by the Police (it also happened in Serbia twice and once in Montenegro), I did not see them in time to put the lights on, a grumpy cop pulled me over in a Serbian part of the country as we passed through. I apologised pretending to be forgetful, he asked me to get out and demanded documents, we had everything so he did not seem too fussed. He asked where we were going, I pointed at Jajce on the map. He sent us on the way. We joked that had it not been in the Serbian part the cops would not have cared. We did pass lots of Police prior to the incident and got away with it. Oh well. It was fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway we got to Jajce in time for lunch by the lake, followed by a swim and a beer in the local lake side restaurant, Cassie spent time looking at the fish and getting Damsel flies to land on her hand. The lake was nice and had interesting mills, but was not the most pleasant place to swim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later we went looking for the &#34;Autocamp&#34; we had passed, it was simple, not next to the lake and once we were in, fairly pleasant. We spent the afternoon catching up on stuff. Reading on the grass and checking maps etc. I also checked out routes to Lukomir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, Jajce is a candidate for a UNESCO site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We finished the evening by having dinner and several locals beers. We also booked into a Sarajevo Hotel online to allow us to explore tomorrow. Tomorrow we planned to have a look around Jajce and head for Sarajevo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9 - Duga Resa to Bihać</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/04/day-9-duga-resa-to-bihac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 19:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/08/04/day-9-duga-resa-to-bihac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well we had a surprisingly quiet night. We thought we would be woken up, having seen and heard the action at the bar, but managed to sleep through. We packed up promptly and made for a café in Duga Resa. The plan was to have some coffee and find something for breakfast. Duga Resa is a tiny place. At this stage I should point out that we still had not found a local cash machine and all I had was Euros. Which is fine for bigger places, but the lady in the café, did not accept them. By the time I remembered it was obviously too late and I had already ordered the coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the lady had a plan, there was a tiny tiny shop around the corner run by two ladies, who were obviously used to all the tourists from the campsite popping in for bits and bobs. I asked if they would mind changing some Euros for me, they agreed, but had to have a discussion about changing as much as 50 Euro, of course it was by this time too late for me to say &#34;How about 30, then?&#34; which fell on deaf ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now back at the café, I sat down for Wendy to tell me what she heard. I should mention that a fat man with a very bad blonde mullet with an irish accent, driving a slovenian plated white van, left the campsite at the same time as us and followed us in to the café. Anyhow, on entering the café I offered for him to go before us in the café while we procrastinated, he declined. After placing our order we heard him say in an irish accent to the Croatian lady &#34;Is the boss around?&#34; Thats unusual! Passing him on the way to the shop, I noticed them talking to a local inside the partially open rear door of the van, I think they used the term Cognac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130484.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I got back and Wendy said, she heard mullet man saying on the phone to a fellow traveller &#34;you better get up here now, there is a shed&#34; our suspicions were confirmed about this lot. About 20 minutes later another of the Irish envoy turned up, in a SUV. Now, remember none of these people speak Croatian. I heard them saying to each other that we spoke english and the language! We can order coffee, beer and juice and ask for the bill. But I have no idea how to say &#34;Do you have a shed we can store our dodgy alcohol in please?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130494.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we left them to it and returned to the shop to grab some stuff for lunch and headed off. We were headed towards Velika Kladuša on the back roads, which lead to some interesting views and sights. Arriving at the border crossing about an hour or so later. By the time we got to the crossing it was getting hot, we queued for about 30 minutes, left Croatia and tried to enter Bosnia and Herzegovina. To be told that the crossing did not have an insurance agent. This meant we would not be able to buy a green card, which meant we had to turn around and re-enter Croatia and head for the Bihać crossing near the Plitviča National Park. Luckily the border guard felt sorry for us and opened up the barrier so we could jump the queue. On the way back through, the Croatia guard recommended that we try to buy insurance at Slunj. We tried and failed there opting to just try at Bihać.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130496.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were lucky at Bihać, the guard did not really care if we had insurance. Normally they hold a passport until you can demonstrate that you have insurance. They returned all our documents and trusted us to go to the offices a 200 meters on and get insurance. The agents building was dark and smelt really bad under the cigarette smoke, housing about 8 or 10 agents. Most of the offices had closed doors with people who did not really care for your presence. I approached a lady who looked at me with slight sympathy in one of the offices asking her for &#34;Osiguranje&#34;, insurance in Croat. She had no idea, knocking and asking on all the doors. Just as she was giving up she told me after a colleague suggested to knock on the last door. I was in luck. They agree to do it, but struggled to find the forms! 30 Euro for 17 days. Moments later I piped out in triumph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/p1130595.jpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this we motored towards Bihać not quite sure were to go. We passed the town on the outskirts not really seeing any good parts, and found shortly afterwards a sign for &#34;Autokamp&#34;. We decided we wanted to rest and stopped, it was a camp almost empty in the grounds of an empty hotel, Hotel Ada. There was a Spanish van and a Dutch van on site when we arrived. Later two more arrived. The place was deserted. It was a nice campsite though, it had loads of well established trees which provided tons of shade, no need for the awning. We popped the tent up and explored the river bank for a place to swim in the Una. We were lucky the river was beautiful and nice and cool. We spent about an hour swimming before popping back for a shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night we opted for an early dinner at the next door restaurant. It was a fantasy land from a film, outside it had a spit roast lamb on the go. The main building was an old mill and the river weaved between it and pontoons that supported seating areas. In amongst the pontoons the river flowed clear enough to allow viewing the plants and fish, like being in an aquarium shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a kilogram of lamb with flat bread and salad for dinner, finished off with Baklava and several local beers. All in around 25 Euro and fantastic. We headed to bed after a brief chat with our neighbours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a great first day in Bosnia and Herzegovina.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready, but where are we going? Can you help?</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 20:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/07/25/almost-ready-but-where-are-we-going-can-you-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/img_0156.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tomorrow we depart for our next trip. Yet again I am nervous, this time we are once again unaccompanied, and heading to new territory. Why do people keep asking if we will be safe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have spent the last two evenings getting stuff together, packing the boxes and making sure we are organised. What have we forgotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would say we have about two thirds of the kit in the Land Rover, so that after work tomorrow we can chuck in the last few items and hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we get off the Chunnel (Channel Tunnel) in Calais, we&#39;ll be heading in the general direction of Reims, before we bear slightly further towards east to head down through Germany, Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is at this point we are even more vague about what we are planning. Do we head down the coast to Albania, through Croatia / Montenegro. Then on the way back go through central Montenegro and Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina? Or do we do it the other way, Bosnia &amp;amp; Herzegovina, central Montenegro to Albania?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to help direct us! Perhaps another route is better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aspirations for 2013&#39;s Trip</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 19:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/28/aspirations-for-2013s-trip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-27-may-2013-1900.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well as I mentioned earlier in &lt;a href=&#34;http://africanuhambo.co.uk/2013/05/26/getting-ready-for-the-summer/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post, we have been thinking about what we might do this summer. Actually we have been thinking since last summer. I guess we are probably not alone on this, we tend to think from trip to trip, from day to day, even during a trip. I guess most people who enjoy travelling have this problem. Is it wrong? I don&amp;#039;t want to wish my life away, but I love thinking about possibilities, getting the map out while drinking wine or beer in camp. Is that dreamin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us we have been to lots of places in Europe, we still have much of Northern Europe to go and places on our own door step such as Scotland and Ireland, but the weather makes life tricky in those places. We don&amp;#039;t want to be confined, confined to a hotel. We want the option to camp, we like camping. No we are not poor, we just like to get away from it. I camp in hotels all year for work, I really don&amp;#039;t like it. So I guess sooner or later we need to take the plunge and face the weather, before we loose the opportunity to see the places we take for granted on our door step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we have been thinking about travel this August. Unfortunately during tourist season, we are bound to this because of school holidays, we tend to get away lightly due to the places we visit, not always. Our plans have been a little hampered this year, domestics are getting in the way! We had to have the kitchen done... I guess you are wondering what the hell I am on. Well it is all about economics. The kitchen cost a fortune (it is still not finished). This has hampered our trip money saving ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately this has meant that, although we have &amp;#039;planned&amp;#039;, the plan is more of an &amp;#039;aspiration&amp;#039;. Let me explain. I guess what we are saying is that, we refuse to give up the opportunity of our annual trip. Regardless of how far we have saved, we&amp;#039;ll see how far we can go on what we&amp;#039;ve got! So if we don&amp;#039;t know what we will be able to do we should plan for what we&amp;#039;d like to do. So I guess you&amp;#039;d say plan for your aspirations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that explained. We&amp;#039;d like this year to explore some more dirt roads in the Alps, there is a warren up there and plenty of places to wild camp without having to part with Euros. After that we&amp;#039;d also like to explore Kosovo, Albania and Macedonia. These are completely new to us and potentially very exciting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/wpid-photo-28-may-2013-2022.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How we get from the Alps to Albania and the surrounding areas, would either be by road or by sea. We used a ferry last year from Bari to Croatia which made life very easy, but expensive. The easiest ferry option for Albania is from Ancona to Durrës. This costs circa €400 but saves probably about three days in raw driving, that is really more because we stop and take a non direct route. The ferry crossing is around 20 hours. The saving is definitely not in fuel, even in a Land Rover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of getting to Albania from Ancona, is that we can use the days saved to spend more time exploring before heading back, it is probably about 1500 miles (2600 km) to Brighton from there. Which would be about 7 days driving, we&amp;#039;d need to allow about 10 so we could chill a bit. This would leave us about 2 weeks in the area we want to be. In reality I&amp;#039;d hope to be able to build some of the return days into the route to allow us to look at possibly Kosovo, Montenegro and Bosnia and Herzegovina a little more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks we&amp;#039;ll be looking at every country we aspire to visit this year and posting a bit about sites and areas that have caught our attention. This will hopefully culminate with a rough route plan. Hopefully we&amp;#039;ll be able to research some more Alps routes too. So stay tuned if you want to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 15: SATURDAY 13 AUGUST 2011 Donji Morinj (Montenegro) – Mostar (Bosnia)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/14/day-15-saturday-13-august-2011-donji-morinj-montenegro-mostar-bosnia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 17:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.co.uk/2011/08/14/day-15-saturday-13-august-2011-donji-morinj-montenegro-mostar-bosnia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Sobe (A dodgy private room) €25 – 1 night&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A fairly early start for us, with not far to travel either. The border crossing was uneventful, even for a Saturday. We managed to make it to Mostar by 14.30hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;FOOTNOTE: The Garmin screen has given up the ghost. Unable to use it to navigate, we are now subject to map (i.e Wendy) navigation. She seems to get a little better each year though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;No camps in Mostar, so we decided to enquire about room prices. The first one quoted €40 for a night, Dan said it was a nice place but a little to steep. Not by UK standards thou. We parked up in secure, paid parking and went on the quest for a room. After enquiring and being lead to the back of beyond, we got a fair enough price on a room for the night – €25. We accepted and then went to get a pivo + sok. We found a lovely bar overlooking the river and under the famous old bridge. Cassie managed to brave up and wonder down to the river to put her feet in. We watched a few teenagers dive into the river from a platform on the opposite side of the river. After our pivo, we went exploring. We wondered along the souvenir alley, here we got our obligatory fridge magnet, a plate for the wall, Cassie got a wooden box and Wendy got some harem trousers. After that we had another pivo. It was extremely hot. Not that it is an excuse! Then we went to find a recommended restorant in the Bosnia guide book. We ordered a mixed grill for 2 people – honestly this could have fed 4 people! We thought we’d hunt out a place called ABC, a sweet shop, said by the guide book, to be the best in Bosnia. We managed to find it and had a dessert. Dan had a cake, Wendy and Cassie had some ice cream. We then wondered back to Tusky to get our bits and bobs and back to our room. A good nights sleep for a change. Woke up fairly early and were showered and out by 8.00hrs…a record!! Off to Blagaj and the Dervish house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9093.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9118.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9124.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9199.JPG&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;100&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9130.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9151.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9156.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9165.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9174.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9208.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.co.uk/assets/DSCF9213.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>