<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipad on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/tags/ipad/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ipad on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/africanuhambo.github.io/tags/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bloggin on the Road, Cheapo iPad Camera Connection Kit</title>
      <link>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/28/bloggin-on-the-road-cheapo-ipad-camera-connection-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 12:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/africanuhambo.github.io/2012/04/28/bloggin-on-the-road-cheapo-ipad-camera-connection-kit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1423.jpg?w=280&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;280&#34; height=&#34;285&#34; alt=&#34;Cheap iPad camera connection kit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So having found Blogsy which is the app that we would like to use, to write our travel blog posts on the road, we realised that we would still need to be able to get images from our camera onto the iPad.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard iPad camera connection kit costs about £25 and is fairly expensive for what it does. Looking around on EBay and Amazon, it is obvious there are a fair few copies around. At about a tenth of the cost delivered. I decided I would take the risk, I purchased one on Amazon. Within a couple of days the connection kit fell through the letter box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impression was that it was well packaged and reasonably well built for something so cheap. It also accepts several different memory cards or a straight camera connection via USB. To change modes there is a switch on the side that allows the user to toggle between with USB or memory card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1312.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;224&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing I did after freeing the device from the packaging was stick a memory card in and test it. On connection to the iPad, the photo app loads to a screen that allows the selection of what is imported or deleted from the card. When a selection is imported the user has a choice of keeping or removing imports from the card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once imported the pictures are placed in a folder in the photo app, called last imported. From there you can do as you wish. Older imports are then placed into a dated folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did notice is that on occasion if the reader is left with an empty card slot, but connected to the iPad, a message would show that said device not supported. But I just clicked ok and all was fine. I am not sure if this is normal behaviour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:left;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1313.jpg?w=300&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;168&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not sure how this device will cope on a long term test, but it seems ok and I have no reason to doubt it will survive a decent trip. Time will tell, I&amp;#039;ll report back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1425.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;275&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-14231.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;193&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear:both;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;africanuhambo.github.io/assets/wpid-photo-28-apr-2012-1422.jpg&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>