<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>France on African Uhambo</title>
    <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/categories/france/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in France on African Uhambo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://africanuhambo.github.io/categories/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost gone</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/26/almost-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 18:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/07/26/almost-gone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/20130726-190547.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well we are at this time just over 40 minutes late on our booked departure time, the board is saying we&#39;ll depart an hour and six minutes late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily apart from not having a place to stay yet when we get to France, we have nowhere important to be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seen a nicely refurbished Mercedes truck, which has been converted for overland travel, it is from Switerland. I remember seeing those things as a kid in the desert with water tanks on the back tackling dunes. Nice ride, wish I got a pic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 09:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2013/05/18/stella-alpina-motociclistica-internazionale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastlane99.plus.com/&#34;&gt;Stella Alpina Motociclistica Internazionale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just found this link via a reply to a &lt;a title=&#34;HUBB&#34; href=&#34;http://www.horizonsunlimited.com/hubb/europe/familly-friendly-4x4-tours-alps-70380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post on Horizons Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;. If your looking at exploring the tracks of the Alps. There some nice pictures on here from the early 2000&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 27: THURSDAY 25 AUGUST 2011 Villey le Sec (France) – Hove (England)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/27/day-27-thursday-25-august-2011-villey-le-sec-france-hove-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 17:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/27/day-27-thursday-25-august-2011-villey-le-sec-france-hove-england/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We woke up in the pouring rain! We decided to pack up and see how the weather goes as we drive. Needless to say, that it did not clear up rain, rain, rain. We stopped just outside reims to get some food from the supermarket. We made the decision that as we were only 200km (give or take), so we decided to just carry on all the way to Calais.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;We arrived at 15.45hrs and were told we could board at 17.45hrs. We had 2 hours to kill. We wondered around the port for a bit, then got a coffee from the vending machine. Above the vending machine was a sign for a restaurant on the 2nd floor of the port building. We decided to go and find it. We wondered across but failed to gain access as we needed our ticket and passports. Dan decided to go and fetch them whilst Cassie and I waited. When we found the restaurant, we had some explosively expensive drinks and sat and whiled away time. We got to the car to load onto the ferry. Once on the ferry, we had a small snack to keep us going. Finally back in the UK…back to grey, cloudy, dreary UK. We made it home at 20.30hrs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;The end to the 2011 Summer Adventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAY 25/26: 23/24 AUGUST 2011  Altkirch (France) – Villey le Sec (France)</title>
      <link>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/25/day-2526-2324-august-2011-altkirch-france-villey-le-sec-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 17:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://africanuhambo.github.io/2011/08/25/day-2526-2324-august-2011-altkirch-france-villey-le-sec-france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Camping Costs: Camping de Villey le Sec €44.60 + electricity – 2 nights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;A little late rising, but not an issue as we had packed things up the night before. In the morning, tents packed up and off we went back to the supermarket to get a map so we could navigate back to Calais. Map bought, and off we went, in the right direction. We drove to Nancy and decided that we’d pull over and look for a supermarket for food and then a campsite. After our supermarket trip, we saw signs to a campsite and so we decided to follow them. The campsite was ok, so we decided to stay for 2 nights. We put up the tents, awning and had lunch. Dinner that night was simple, sausages, rolls, gherkins and mustard. As we cleaned up after dinner and put Cas to bed, we heard thunder rolling in, luckily Cas was asleep. The heavens opened up and it absolutely bucketed down! As the night wore on, the thunder got worse and such Cassie woke up. She ended up in our tent again for the night. To say that we got no sleep would be an understatement. The storm did not relent, it just got worse. The rain got heavier, and as we were camped between a river and a lake, we thought that with both rising we might actually wash away. At one point, the thunder was so loud, it scared the living daylights out of us. From the outside, the tent must have jumped off the ground with our fright! The tent held up despite the immense amount and heaviness of the rain, it did not leak once! Morning arrived and Cassie happened to be the only one out of us 3 that had managed to actually get a good nights sleep! The day seemed cloudy, but dry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9648.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;DAY 26: WEDNESDAY 24 AUGUST 2011&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;Tired and worn from the previous nights storm and restless sleep, we got up and had breakfast followed by 2 coffees! We simply lazed around. Cassie took some bread from todays baguette and went to feed the ducks. Cassie and Dan then played Mario Bros. on her Nintendo DS… Dan got carried away and had to get to the point where you could actually save your game. After a stroll around the camp, Cassie started chatting to 2 English girls and so Dan and I got chatting to their parents. We shared holiday routes and jourmney lengths etc. They were travelling in a bongo and so Dan had a look out of interest for Carole and Daniel (Wendy’s Biological Parents who would be visiting us next Summer). The family were leaving that afternoon, and after a nice long chat we decided to let them pack up whilst we went back to the tent for lunch. The sky looked ominous, so we decided to string our tarp up over the tents. We then decided to take Cassie’s tent down, put her in our tent again, so that if it did rain again we’d only have 1 tent to take down in the rain. As we moved the tent under the tarp and got it semi to our desired set up, the heavens opened. We were thankful we’d put the tarp up and ate our lunch under the awning and tarp in dryness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;As quickly as the heavens had opened, they cleared up and the sun showed it’s face again. We all moved our chairs out into the sunshine and sat reading and playing games. We idled the day away, playing with Cas in the park, playing music, Dan taught Cassie knots and before we knew it, dinner time was upon us. A simple dinner of steak and salad which Dan made whilst Cassie and Wendy played in the park. Dinner over and dishes washed, Cassie showered, it was bedtime. Now the skies were clear and blue, Murphy’s law, take precaustions and what you plan for never happens. Better to be prepared though. Time to move on again tomorrow, heading for Reims. We will try to get 200km covered so we are near enough to calais for the ferry and last stop. The eeking out of the last days of holiday. Lets hope they stay sunny!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:justify;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9655.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9656.JPG&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://africanuhambo.github.io/assets/DSCF9676.JPG&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>